<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Confidence on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/confidence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Confidence on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 08:35:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/confidence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Yourself on Fire</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 08:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I use the term &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;set yourself on fire&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; frequently. To me, it means a sink-or-swim moment: &lt;strong&gt;you&amp;rsquo;ll either find a way to put this fire out, or you&amp;rsquo;re toast.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It removes the option to fail just a little bit. You now either make this work, or you go down hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, and for most people I know, this is both horribly frightening and incredibly motivating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-drawing-garfield-to-marketing-a-band:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;From Drawing Garfield to Marketing a Band&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/minusmythoughts.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;MinusMyThoughts&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tysonvick.com&#34;&gt;Tyson Vick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a musician&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, we had no income. On tour, we were lucky to get paid $100 for a show, and sometimes we could pull together $50 in sales from the merch table. It barely covered gas to get to the next city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no budget whatsoever, so things like &amp;ldquo;marketing budgets&amp;rdquo; were never even discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was a need for marketing: tour posters, merchandise, album art, web banners, MySpace customizations, a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no one to do the work. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to hire help, and none of us knew anything about that stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured, &amp;ldquo;I drew pictures of Garfield and the Ninja Turtles when I was a kid; I can figure out a tour poster.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no experience, and no idea what I was doing. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any reason that I would fail. So &lt;strong&gt;I set myself on fire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The posters weren&amp;rsquo;t great. But they also weren&amp;rsquo;t terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MySpace page went through several iterations, all of which were — let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, here — pretty MySpacey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first website I built &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20040718012243/http://minusmythoughts.com/&#34;&gt;was horrible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It was a table-based layout with no CSS, and it used iframes for content. But goddammit, if you clicked our &amp;ldquo;shows&amp;rdquo; link, you saw a list of shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it sucked. But it worked. &lt;strong&gt;And I fucking &lt;em&gt;built&lt;/em&gt; that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-a-dude-in-a-band-to-a-web-designer:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;From a Dude in a Band to a Web Designer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the few years that my band was touring, I rebuilt that website over a dozen times. At first because I could see the horrible mistakes I was making, but then it just became a fun thing for me to do in the downtime between soundcheck and going onstage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the band broke up, my friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;Nate Green&lt;/a&gt; asked me if I&amp;rsquo;d help him build a website for his new personal brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how to build a website someone else could manage, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any reason that I would fail. &lt;strong&gt;I set myself on fire again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate&amp;rsquo;s website &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20070910075625/http://www.thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t ground-breaking&lt;/a&gt;, but it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate&amp;rsquo;s business grew, and I was suddenly a web designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-life-slightly-singed:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;My Life, Slightly Singed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenges over the years have changed, but I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to keep my response consistent: I can handle that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I look at a challenge and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t put anyone in danger — I&amp;rsquo;m not going to volunteer to build a rocket or perform open-heart surgery, here — I&amp;rsquo;ll take it on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can back that trailer into the boat slip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can cook a turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each of these scenarios (all of which are real moments in my life), I had never done the thing I had just told someone I was able to do. But I trusted myself to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I set myself on fire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every case, I figured it out. I moved slowly, I did a &lt;em&gt;shitload&lt;/em&gt; of Googling, and in the end I delivered a result that was good enough to make everyone involved happy. And with practice, I&amp;rsquo;ll get to the point that it&amp;rsquo;s just a thing I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-yourself-on-fire:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;Set Yourself on Fire&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you trying to learn right now? Have you been putting it off? How can you remove your safety net so you &lt;em&gt;have to learn it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you set yourself on fire in the past? Or been set on fire by someone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit the discussion link and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;I use the term &amp;ldquo;musician&amp;rdquo; loosely, here.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t actually the &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; first site. The Wayback Machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a copy of it, unfortunately.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away Its Power</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/name-your-fear</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 10:58:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/name-your-fear</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At a sleepover in second grade, my friends put on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0094761/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Blob&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — a horror film about space jelly that kills anyone it touches. I was so scared I started crying and my mom had to pick me up to take me home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another night I snuck out of my bedroom while my parents watched TV, and I saw the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OPdDdC4go6c&#34;&gt;sewer scene from &lt;em&gt;It&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. My dad had to remove everything that even &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt; resembled a clown from the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-wasn-t-scared-of-the-story:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;I Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Scared of the Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both cases, I actually barely saw any of the movie that frightened me. I saw that the movie was a scary movie, I knew that scary movies terrified me, and I knew that watching a scary movie would scare me too badly to be able to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize, however, was my fear of horror films — and the fear I felt when I imagined what terrors those films might contain — was all it took to ruin my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was scared of the movies themselves.&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of the movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was so bad that I only had to see the cover of &lt;em&gt;Child&amp;rsquo;s Play&lt;/em&gt; in a video store to end up petrified and sleepless for a few nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-out-how-it-ends:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Find Out How It Ends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an adult, I still don&amp;rsquo;t care for horror films. But if I start watching one, I now force myself to finish the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I see a scene from a horror film — just like I did when I was a kid — I build a vague, terrifying beast out of my fear of the movie, and this unknowable shape is more monstrous than anything I&amp;rsquo;ll see in a movie. I don&amp;rsquo;t care how good the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer-generated_imagery&#34;&gt;CGI&lt;/a&gt; is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to see the end. I need to know what happens. What &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; goes on in this movie?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no way the actual outcome will be scarier than what I can dream up in my ignorance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By seeing the full movie, I learn the reality of the story, and that takes away the paralyzing power of my ignorance and fear.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-away-its-power:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Take Away Its Power&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our fears are imaginary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t know what comes next, so we make projections about the future. And in our imaginations, the potential for catastrophe is alarmingly high.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;rsquo;re not actually scared of the experience. We&amp;rsquo;re scared of the unknown: the vague, monster-shaped outline in our imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By facing that fear, we replace the monster with a memory. And even if the memory is uncomfortable or humiliating, it&amp;rsquo;s very unlikely that it will be as horrifying as the make-believe nightmare scenario we dreamed up before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shining-a-light-into-monster-shaped-shadows:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Shining a Light into Monster-Shaped Shadows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To take power away from your fear, give it a name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an effort to limit the number of monsters occupying my headspace, I try to push my fears into reality and name them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I feeling anxious about a client who seems unhappy with my work? Call them and clear the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there an unresolved tension between me and a family member? Let&amp;rsquo;s sit down and get to the bottom of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is my laundry room haunted? Let&amp;rsquo;s go stand in there and find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I notice a situation that scares me, I try to jump in earlier rather than later, because the end result is always the same: I face the fear and realize the difference between what I &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; was wrong, and what was &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; wrong is staggering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I thought may have been a relationship-ending issue with the client turned out to be a few small adjustments and ten minutes of screensharing to show them how to use a tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a beer with the family member, we realized we were both working toward the same goal even though our methods were clashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My laundry room is creepy as shit. But it&amp;rsquo;s not haunted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a fear is dragged into reality and exposed to a little daylight, the giant monster-shaped shadow in my imagination shrivels to a small, silly bit of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;name-your-fears:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Name Your Fears&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What monsters are lurking in your imagination right now? How many of them can you drag into reality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/uaeincredible/217849066/&#34;&gt;Capture Queen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;Sure, &lt;em&gt;The Ring&lt;/em&gt; still scared the shit out of me, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t lose any sleep afterward. I can guarantee the things my brain will dream up out of a storyline involving a dead girl who haunts your TV are &lt;em&gt;far worse&lt;/em&gt; than what happens in the movie.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;For an easy example, imagine asking someone out on a date that you think is &amp;ldquo;out of your league.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I get anxious imagining it: I see her across the room, obviously more successful, socially adept, and better-looking than me. She&amp;rsquo;s smiling, sharply dressed, surrounded by people who are laughing at the devilishly clever observation she just made about current events of which I&amp;rsquo;m appallingly ignorant.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And here I come — trying to look confident but probably smiling like a crazy person, food caught in my beard, smudges on my glasses — to interrupt her conversation. I tell a joke that doesn&amp;rsquo;t land, laugh loudly at my own joke out of discomfort, turn tomato-red in self-conscious embarrassment, and stammer my way through awkward compliments that are just making her more uncomfortable.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I never even get to the part about asking her out.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;She laughs in my face. The people around her laugh in my face. Everyone in the room perks up, and she grabs the microphone from the party&amp;rsquo;s emcee.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ladies and gentlemen, a special announcement: Jason Lengstorf is a useless idiot who lacks the charm of a papercut and smells like he&amp;rsquo;s been eating nothing but cheese for the last eight weeks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The story makes the news later that night, and I&amp;rsquo;m forced to flee the country in shame. I live out the rest of my days in Bulgaria harvesting sugar beets in exile.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The reality, however, is that — while &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d probably still blow it&lt;/a&gt; — the actual situation would be far less ridiculous. I&amp;rsquo;d say hello, she&amp;rsquo;d say hello, I&amp;rsquo;d try to make conversation, and when we didn&amp;rsquo;t hit it off I&amp;rsquo;d make an exit. This isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a storybook ending, but it&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near the worst-case scenario my imagination cooks up.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Montana</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 17:46:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Years back, before I moved to Portland, I used to haunt a bar called Al&amp;rsquo;s and Vic&amp;rsquo;s in Missoula, Montana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of those dives where it was too loud to hear yourself think and the floor was &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; sticky, but they sold a bucket of PBR for four dollars, and a Montana Happy Meal&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a night where I&amp;rsquo;d been called in as wingman for Scott, we met with his date and — for the span of a beer — I did my best not to make him sound like a degenerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His date, whose name I don&amp;rsquo;t remember but whose face looked like a Bernadette, told us her friends were arriving and would we mind standing at the bar with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette introduced us to her friends, Mandy and Kate. Mandy, it turns out, was a friend of Scott&amp;rsquo;s, and the two of them pulled Bernadette into conversation, leaving Kate and I to fend for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate was beautiful. Like, &lt;em&gt;holy shit&lt;/em&gt; good-looking — the kind of attractive that usually requires about a grand&amp;rsquo;s worth of Photoshop cleanup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, on the other hand, was wearing a cowboy shirt with pearl snaps, sporting an extra twenty pounds or so, and unshaven in the not-sexy way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, despite my homeless desperado ensemble, we hit it off immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was funny, sharp-witted. I was scrambling to keep up, but she was laughing. The hoarse mating calls of a hundred college kids were muffled under the sound of her voice, like bourbon over fine-grit sandpaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The faces around us blurred and faded; it was just me and Kate and my beer and her whisky diet and this moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain was leaking that special cocktail of chemicals that only happens the first time you make a connection with someone. In that moment I understood how people can meet and fall in love and end up making long-term promises to each other in front of an Elvis impersonator — all in the span of one intense night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spark between us had magnetized the air; my heart was trying to pull out of my chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette reappeared over Kate&amp;rsquo;s shoulder, and the room snapped back into focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandy was with her, and Scott returned a moment later with a fresh bucket of beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott gave me a &lt;em&gt;how&amp;rsquo;d it go for you&lt;/em&gt; look. I tried not to look upset about the interruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls did their secret eye contact telepathy thing, and Bernadette started preparing her exit. Mandy and Kate took her cue and started gathering their purses and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate caught my eye as she swung her coat around her shoulders, and my heart went all squishy and weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I formed the words in my brain — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number&lt;/em&gt; — opened my mouth to speak — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number, you idiot!&lt;/em&gt; — and I said, &amp;ldquo;It was really nice meeting you. Have a great night.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She might have hesitated. I was too disgusted with myself to notice. The next thing I knew I was watching her hair bounce in the red bar-glow as she walked away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of running after her, telling her I couldn&amp;rsquo;t let her get away without knowing I could see her again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s romantic? Probably creepy. Better not.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of asking Scott for Bernadette&amp;rsquo;s number so I could call her and ask for Kate&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s even worse. Stop it. All of your ideas are bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did nothing. I watched the door close behind her. My mouth was probably hanging open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Scotty — never one to pass up a kidney punch — said, &amp;ldquo;Blew that one, huh?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the beer he offered and did a poor job of acting nonchalant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You know who she is, right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shook my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a special kind of schadenfreude that only men experience. It occurs when we watch a friend — hitting it off with a woman who is clearly out of his league — suddenly and spectacularly self-destruct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a teeball benchwarmer. Kate was one good season away from the big show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scotty was so darkly gleeful he should have been stroking a Persian cat as he said, &amp;ldquo;She was Miss Montana last year.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goddammit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot with Miss Montana, and I let her walk out of the bar. After fifteen minutes of great conversation and good chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replayed the moments before she left in my head. I met her eyes. &lt;em&gt;She was waiting for you to ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot. I did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-wasted-second-chance:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;The (Wasted) Second Chance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks later, I was out with Scotty again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was late, and we had slunk into the bar everyone despised. The sign on the door said &amp;ldquo;Bodega&amp;rdquo;, but it may has well have been called You&amp;rsquo;re Hammered Again &amp;amp; None of the Girls Will Talk to You, Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out front, I bummed a cigarette off a stranger and wobbled gently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jason?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wheeled and found myself facing Kate. I immediately stamped out my cigarette. I could feel the air starting to magnetize again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate smiled. And then she hugged me. Her hair smelled like vanilla-scented heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smelled like an ashtray full of whiskey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So how are you?&amp;rdquo; I managed to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Great! Oh, by the way, these are my brothers, Jeff and Mark,&amp;rdquo; she said, motioning to the two frighteningly large men who flanked her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded. They nodded back, then pretended not to pay attention while this drunken asshole in front of The Saddest Bar in Missoula tried to flirt with their sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow we just fell back into it. She teased me about my smoking, I poked fun at the shoes she was carrying, and we both laughed. My heart did the squishy-weird thing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it was time to make the move. Her brothers weren&amp;rsquo;t going to stand there all night, and I needed to head back inside before Scott ordered me any more drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried scraping every last bit of courage off the walls of my rib cage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just ask. Ask for her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to think of a line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a line, dickhead: &amp;ldquo;Can I get your number and call you sometime?&amp;rdquo; Just. Ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I caught eyes with the larger of her two brothers. And then I wondered if I&amp;rsquo;d misread the whole situation and she was just being nice to me. And then I froze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, hey, it was great seeing you again. I should probably get back inside.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idiot. Idiot. Idiot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flushed. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even make eye contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As suddenly as she&amp;rsquo;d appeared, Kate — Miss Montana — the gorgeous, funny girl I love-at-first-sighted (twice) was gone into the night. For good this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lost-in-the-woulds:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;Lost in the Woulds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would have been a great couple. She would have had a secret family recipe for waffles and a mean Scrabble game. Maybe her disturbingly attractive genes would compensate for my hairiness and we&amp;rsquo;d make the world&amp;rsquo;s hottest babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She would have shot me down. We&amp;rsquo;d have only had another thirty seconds of good conversation left in us. She would have had a boyfriend. I would have hated her guts after two weeks of hanging out. Or, more likely, she&amp;rsquo;d have hated mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand wonderful memories, starting with the one where I asked if I could call and she said yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand mistakes and alienated myself from the Montana Beautiful Women&amp;rsquo;s Club&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any of those outcomes would have been fine. Even bad experiences are still &lt;em&gt;experiences&lt;/em&gt;, you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;em&gt;wondering!&lt;/em&gt; The wondering is murder. There&amp;rsquo;s no lesson to learn in &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s just the nagging of an unanswered question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, I&amp;rsquo;m not the guy who took a long shot with a beauty queen and succeeded against the odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also not the guy who took a shot and missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just a guy who had a shot and stood there looking foolish while the clock ran out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;A shot of Jameson with a PBR back.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;Totally a thing.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fear</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/fear</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 15:17:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/fear</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to back down from a challenge, or to hedge our bets to leave ourselves an out. Sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s wise. Most times we&amp;rsquo;re just scared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a terrifying thing, The Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear tells us that our ideas are too risky, or uninteresting, or just plain &lt;em&gt;bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear tells us we&amp;rsquo;ll be rejected if we try to say hello. That we&amp;rsquo;ll be ridiculed and laughed at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we stand on the starting line of a new adventure — moving to a new city, leaving an unfulfilling job — The Fear tells us we&amp;rsquo;ll never make it; could never make it; should just give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying is scary. Trying is difficult. Most of all, trying makes us vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;schrödinger-s-kiss:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738&#34;&gt;Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s Kiss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was twelve, my parents used to play cards with Cindy&amp;rsquo;s parents. She was the first girl I&amp;rsquo;d spent time alone with, and I was &lt;em&gt;in love&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I wanted to do was kiss Cindy. And I was pretty sure Cindy wanted to kiss me, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But The Fear was certain a kiss spelled disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;ll say no. She&amp;rsquo;ll tell her parents. She&amp;rsquo;ll be so disgusted she&amp;rsquo;ll throw up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I didn&amp;rsquo;t try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wondering was torture. Would she kiss me? What would kissing be like? Did she like me, or did she &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; like me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visualized every step of the kiss: Cindy and I would be playing &lt;em&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/em&gt;, and she&amp;rsquo;d be on a roll&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;d watch intently as she squared off with Dr. Robotnik.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the split second after defeating the boss, while her heart was soaring with the joy of having saved the world from the clutches of evil, I&amp;rsquo;d wrap my arms around her and we&amp;rsquo;d kiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;d be surprised, and thrilled, and we&amp;rsquo;d kiss like on those soap operas my mom watched where our heads rotate side to side for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could almost feel our lips touching, I wanted it so bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But still The Fear said it would never work, and that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t even bother trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me weeks to defeat The Fear. During a game of Truth or Dare, I finally worked up the courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I dare you to kiss me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heart was in my throat. I was tensed up, ready to sprint for the door if she said no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But she didn&amp;rsquo;t say no.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Cindy led me downstairs, where we snuck past our dads out into the garage and sat on the bumper of her mom&amp;rsquo;s minivan.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Even as she held my hand, I heard The Fear telling me it was all about to go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it didn&amp;rsquo;t go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy leaned in, and I had my very first kiss: a tight-lipped peck followed by a panicked sprint back up to her room before our parents could notice we&amp;rsquo;d left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been kissed. I was a man now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fear-as-a-friend:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738&#34;&gt;The Fear as a Friend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I overcame The Fear and got my first kiss, I had an advantage: I knew The Fear could be beaten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear told me I&amp;rsquo;d blow it on my first oral presentation in junior high. I pushed through and got a B+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear was certain I&amp;rsquo;d never win in the student elections, but I ran anyways. I was elected Junior Class Vice President.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear screamed that my band would make me the butt of a lot of jokes. But I got on stage, and discovered my first real passion in music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It never went away, The Fear, but every time I push past it, it gets a little easier the next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started to look forward to The Fear now; when it rears its head, I know I&amp;rsquo;m pushing myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m doing something that scares me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m growing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still don&amp;rsquo;t like The Fear. It makes me feel awful, paralyzed, a little nauseous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every new adventure, I&amp;rsquo;ll be that twelve-year-old boy: terrified, and desperately trying to scrape together enough courage to go in for my first kiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I welcome it now. The Fear is the starting line of a new challenge. A sign that I&amp;rsquo;m becoming more than I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth-or-dare:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738&#34;&gt;Truth or Dare?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s play a game of Truth or Dare.&lt;/strong&gt; Think of something you&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to try, but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now tell the truth: &lt;strong&gt;is there anything &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; stopping you?&lt;/strong&gt; Or is it just The Fear making excuses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, of course, the dare: I dare you — I &lt;em&gt;double dare&lt;/em&gt; you — to &lt;strong&gt;do that thing you&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do *today&lt;/strong&gt;*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s too big to do in a day, then take one step toward that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; to move past The Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it can be shared publicly, post your thing on the discussion for this post, and tell me what the one step you&amp;rsquo;re taking today will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Push through The Fear. The kiss is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brennaphotos/3499551628/&#34;&gt;Brenna Lyn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;Get it? Because&amp;hellip; because it&amp;rsquo;s Sonic. And he rolls. &lt;em&gt;Amirite?&lt;/em&gt; Ah, never mind.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;Because — of course — sneaking clumsily through the house was &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; less conspicuous than staying in her room like we always did.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;I was impeached about a month later. Long story. Ask me over drinks.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Not a Phony</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/not-a-phony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 15:24:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/not-a-phony/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Confidence is kind of a dirty word these days. Talking about our strengths and abilities makes us feel like impostors. We&amp;rsquo;re all insecure, and &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sick of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I read an old post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/ImAPhonyAreYou.aspx&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; about feeling like a phony. It reminded me of another post by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scrawnytobrawny.com/my-success-is-a-lie&#34;&gt;Nate Green&lt;/a&gt; on the same subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sentiment behind both of these articles is summed up pretty well in this quote from Nate (for context, he&amp;rsquo;s talking about how he got &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1m1oy3S&#34;&gt;a book deal&lt;/a&gt; at 23 with no formal education):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who the hell did I think I was?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only a matter of time, I thought. Only a matter of time before everyone realizes I have no business doing any of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any moment, I would be exposed as a fraud. On a large scale. And it scared the shit out of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-get-trained-to-feel-like-phonies:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;We Get Trained to Feel Like Phonies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty widespread sentiment among the people I know who are successful. Far too many things are working against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the slow build, which pretty much guarantees that you never really notice your success.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Lots of things have improved for me since I was a broke freelancer working 16-hour days in an apartment that I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure had black mold — but I don&amp;rsquo;t really &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; different than that younger, less experienced version of myself.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the realization that knowing almost everything about Thing A only leads to the further realization that — in order to &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; understand the &amp;ldquo;big picture&amp;rdquo; — a complete knowledge of Things B, C, and D is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, most importantly, we get told that feeling competent and self-assured is socially unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;apologize-for-your-progress:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;Apologize for Your Progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the lines, it became unacceptable to feel proud of our success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying out loud that you&amp;rsquo;re skilled is met with derision. &amp;ldquo;You sound arrogant.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re acting like you&amp;rsquo;re better than everyone else.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s be clear: I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about &lt;em&gt;bragging&lt;/em&gt;, here. There&amp;rsquo;s a world of difference between, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m making a lot of progress at work right now; all that hard work is finally paying off,&amp;rdquo; and, &amp;ldquo;I am &lt;em&gt;killing it&lt;/em&gt; right now — who wants to touch me?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels, though, that the pursuit of political correctness has made it a &lt;em&gt;faux pas&lt;/em&gt; to talk about what you&amp;rsquo;re capable of in most situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I find myself actively try to steer conversations away from what I&amp;rsquo;m doing because I&amp;rsquo;m worried that I&amp;rsquo;ll come off like an asshole if I talk about the things I&amp;rsquo;m working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-am-not-a-phony:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;I Am NOT a Phony&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not the smartest guy in the world. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the most things about anything. There are much smarter people, much more experienced people, much better-looking people, much funnier people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet I still represent myself as an expert on certain topics, and I still think I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just because someone else is better doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m not good.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, on top of that, I have a very unique blend of strengths that make me extremely valuable in certain situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people ask for my services, I don&amp;rsquo;t look around like &lt;em&gt;who, me?&lt;/em&gt; — I take the compliment and get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-okay-to-be-confident:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Okay to Be Confident&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate that when I compliment someone, the expected response is, &amp;ldquo;Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m not any good. I just got lucky.&amp;rdquo; Or, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by a great team.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We deflect the praise because it just feels too &lt;em&gt;icky&lt;/em&gt; to admit we&amp;rsquo;re good at things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear myself say shit like this all the time. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be branded a cocky prick, so I give all the credit to other people, or hide behind some self-deprecating wisecrack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of this is humility, which is a good thing. But it&amp;rsquo;s been taken to the extreme where accepting &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; praise is somehow uncouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: I have been fortunate, and I do have an incredible team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;but I&amp;rsquo;m also really fucking good at what I do.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve put in tens of thousands of hours learning this craft, and every year I put in thousands more continuing my education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a phony. I belong here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-guy-s-a-dick:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;This Guy&amp;rsquo;s a Dick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post sounds like bragging. Like I&amp;rsquo;m trying to tell everyone how great I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say here is that &lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s okay to be proud of your accomplishments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re being honest with yourself, talking about your accomplishments is perfectly acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;m not advocating constant self-adulation. It requires a little tact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-own-your-success-without-being-a-dick:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;How to Own Your Success Without Being a Dick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know my friends, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I still struggle with &amp;ldquo;the line&amp;rdquo; sometimes. But I&amp;rsquo;m working on a system of rules to keep myself from being a dick in conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never bring up your own success.&lt;/strong&gt; You can&amp;rsquo;t avoid sounding self-serving if you insert praise for yourself into a conversation; let someone else ask first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t exaggerate.&lt;/strong&gt; Hyperbole is great for a cute anecdote, but if it turns out you&amp;rsquo;re telling a success story that&amp;rsquo;s been embellished, you&amp;rsquo;ll look like a liar. If anything, play &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt; the details a bit.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop at one.&lt;/strong&gt; If you end up telling a success story, don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself get sucked into telling another one. This is hard, because once you start talking about yourself it&amp;rsquo;s hard to stop. But, seriously. Stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spend more time asking questions and listening than talking.&lt;/strong&gt; This is huge. Unless you&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to speak, spend more time seeing what you can learn from everyone else at the table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a complete list, but it (usually) keeps me from coming off like a douchebag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-not-a-phony-either:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re Not a Phony, Either&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we make a deal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, let&amp;rsquo;s try to own our successes. We&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s recognize that we&amp;rsquo;re not the best or the smartest, but we&amp;rsquo;re pretty damn good, and we&amp;rsquo;re pretty damn smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are NOT impostors. We are NOT frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are fucking awesome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;This is called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normalcy&#34;&gt;creeping normalcy&lt;/a&gt;, which is the idea that we don&amp;rsquo;t notice changes if they happen in small increments over a long period of time. Usually this is used to describe negative changes, but the same effects seem to be present with the positive as well.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;Except for the whole &amp;ldquo;not dying of black mold-related illness&amp;rdquo; thing.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;I am. I&amp;rsquo;m awesome.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;For example, if you launched a successful company, don&amp;rsquo;t talk about the press or awards you&amp;rsquo;re getting. Instead, talk about what you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt;, and let someone else talk about how much everyone else likes you.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>