<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 11:40:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Speechless: Key Phrases to Learn in a Foreign Language</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/foreign-language-phrases</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 11:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/foreign-language-phrases</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I started out feeling pretty cocky. I usually do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I speak a little Spanish. How hard could Italian really be?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The airport was easy; everyone spoke English. The train, too. Our taxi driver didn&amp;rsquo;t speak much English, but all he really needed was an address, anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was promising: three interactions with Italians and no issues!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cab driver dropped us at Ripa&amp;rsquo;s Cafe, where our Airbnb host, Francesco, had left the keys to his apartment. I felt bulletproof as I wheeled my carry-on into the bar and approached the counter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prego?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; The man behind the counter was in a hurry, and folks from the neighborhood were queueing up behind me for lottery tickets and cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opened my mouth, froze, and slowly closed it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fuck. I don&amp;rsquo;t speak Italian. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to say &amp;ldquo;keys&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was tongue-tied. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know how to tell this poor guy I didn&amp;rsquo;t speak Italian. My cocksure attitude toward the language barrier withered, and I knew I was defeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so — my cheeks burning bright red in embarrassment — I waved the white flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;English?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shook his head and walked away. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if he was coming back. Were we supposed to wait?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt the people behind me staring daggers into the back of my head. My body was tying itself in knots. I was shrinking in shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can help, please?&amp;rdquo; A girl had appeared behind the counter, looking at Marisa and I with pity. She barely spoke any English, but with a lot of miming and hand gestures we were able to get the keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we finally found the apartment, I felt sick and helpless as I collapsed on the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; over my head,&lt;/em&gt; I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/Mime.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;mime&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  For how communicationally challenged I felt, I may as well have been wearing face paint.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://mime.com.ua/&#34;&gt;Никита Капранов&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I came to grips with the fact I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to learn Italian by magic and/or wishing &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hard, I did two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duolingo.com/&#34;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; and started the Spanish course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I made a list of phrases that I knew I would use multiple times each day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had to figure out how to get by without speaking the language.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a way to acknowledge people when spoken to. I was going to need to ask for things like food and coffee. I knew people would help me, and I needed to know how thank them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My emergency phrase list was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no avoiding it, really; I&amp;rsquo;m a terrible mime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;know-enough-to-get-by:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Know Enough to Get By&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a short trip — for instance, five days in Milan — there&amp;rsquo;s very little chance I&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; learn the language. So instead, I choose to &lt;strong&gt;focus on the words and phrases that meet the minimum requirements for functioning in that country.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, these are the phrases I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten the most mileage out of. You won&amp;rsquo;t impress the locals with your conversational skills. You&amp;rsquo;ll still be lost in most conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But knowing these few key phrases will at least give you tools to feel a little less helpless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-learn-how-to-apologize:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Step 1: Learn How to Apologize&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/im-sorry.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;I&amp;#39;m sorry&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might not get much done, but if you learn &lt;em&gt;nothing else&lt;/em&gt; of a foreign language, at least &lt;strong&gt;learn how to apologize for showing up in someone else&amp;rsquo;s country and not speaking their language.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s usually just two phrases: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;excuse me&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-m-sorry-i-don-t-speak-your-language:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Sorry, I Don&amp;rsquo;t Speak Your Language&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the debacle in Milan, this is the first phrase I will learn in every language. I&amp;rsquo;ll know it before I enter the country, and I&amp;rsquo;ll have practiced it under my breath repeatedly as I deplane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not particularly useful in the practical sense. It won&amp;rsquo;t help anyone understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say. In fact, after I&amp;rsquo;ve said it, I&amp;rsquo;ll be exactly where I was before I said it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With one key difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; key difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve let the person I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to know that — if nothing else — &lt;strong&gt;I cared enough to learn how to let them know I&amp;rsquo;m a dumbshit tourist who can&amp;rsquo;t speak their language.&lt;/strong&gt; I put in a tiny bit of effort to show respect, even if it won&amp;rsquo;t help us communicate any better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, after trying this in both Italy and Spain so far, is that it totally transforms my interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I said nothing and gaped helplessly at the waitress, the situation was a stand-off: an exasperated waitress stares into my wide, uncomprehending eyes with a look of annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By making the effort and letting her know I don&amp;rsquo;t understand her, it becomes a relatively painless situation: she smiles and says something I don&amp;rsquo;t understand,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:waitress&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:waitress&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; then calls to the back for the dishwasher, who speaks English, and we&amp;rsquo;re able to place our order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my goal is to learn how to order in the local language as quickly as possible to avoid the need for a translator altogether. In the time before I learn how, this is the best solution I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s why I think this is so effective: &lt;strong&gt;by making an effort to learn a bit of the local language, I&amp;rsquo;m helping avoid the perception that I&amp;rsquo;m an asshole tourist who sees the people in the country I&amp;rsquo;m visiting as less important than I am.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead, I&amp;rsquo;m a newcomer who&amp;rsquo;s trying to learn, but hasn&amp;rsquo;t gotten it all figured out yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People like to help each other when it feels like teamwork, or when they see someone struggling to figure something out. A few of the people we&amp;rsquo;ve interacted with have actually taken extra time to help us translate menus, and it felt like they were genuinely pleased to have helped us learn something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/tourists.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;tourists&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Dad Spanish: &#34;I WOULD LIKE EL STEAK-O!&#34;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if I sit down and immediately start ordering in Dad Spanish, I&amp;rsquo;ve just shown that I&amp;rsquo;m willing to make zero effort, but I expect a big effort and a lot of help from the person I&amp;rsquo;m talking to. This is disrespectful, and it puts me at odds with the person I&amp;rsquo;m dealing with — hardly a productive way to handle a situation where I need help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an enormous benefit for very little effort. For example, in Spanish, all you have to say is, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lo siento, no hablo español.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; (I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, I don&amp;rsquo;t speak Spanish.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;excuse-me:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Excuse Me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m walking down the street — especially in more heavily touristed areas — I&amp;rsquo;m inevitably going to bump into people.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:pedestrians&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:pedestrians&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Rather than staring at them wide-eyed or saying something they won&amp;rsquo;t understand, I &lt;strong&gt;learn how to say a polite &amp;ldquo;excuse me&amp;rdquo; in their language,&lt;/strong&gt; which shows respect — I&amp;rsquo;m speaking their language — and avoids misunderstanding — they may not get my meaning when I say, &amp;ldquo;Sorry &amp;lsquo;bout that, pal!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Romance languages, these are often pretty similar to the English words you already know. For example, in Italian you would say, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Scuzi!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; In Spanish, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perdón!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; French: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Excusez-moi.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also helps politely get someone&amp;rsquo;s attention, making it doubly useful to learn right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-mind-your-manners:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Step 2: Mind Your Manners&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;rsquo;m going to be an idiot, I&amp;rsquo;m at least going to be a polite idiot. &lt;strong&gt;Figuring out the basics of being polite makes every interaction more friendly.&lt;/strong&gt; This, I hope, slightly eases the imminent pain&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:pain&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:pain&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and frustration I&amp;rsquo;m about to cause the person I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;please-thank-you:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Please &amp;amp; Thank You&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all you need. Learn them, and use them often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re American and headed to a Spanish-speaking country, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance you&amp;rsquo;ve heard these before: &lt;em&gt;por favor&lt;/em&gt; (please) and &lt;em&gt;gracias&lt;/em&gt; (thank you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-learn-how-to-feed-yourself:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Step 3: Learn How to Feed Yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also need food. Y&amp;rsquo;know, to stay alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, my ability to locate good food makes the difference between having a good time and being utterly miserable, so &lt;strong&gt;I place a high priority on learning my way around local menus.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/sea-urchin.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;sea urchin at Ñino Viejo in Barcelona, Spain&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Sea urchin. It&#39;s delicious, but you&#39;ll want to know you ordered it before it arrives.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ham-and-cheese:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Ham and Cheese&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Europeans love ham and cheese. It&amp;rsquo;s on nearly every menu I&amp;rsquo;ve seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all very good news to me; I love both ham &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; cheese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I &lt;em&gt;haven&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; seen consistently on menus is much of anything else. Turkey, beef, or chicken are available &lt;em&gt;sometimes,&lt;/em&gt; but not with anywhere near the ubiquity of good ol&amp;rsquo; ham and cheese.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:vegetarians&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:vegetarians&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My strategy to ensure I&amp;rsquo;ll always be able to find something to eat is to figure out how to translate &amp;ldquo;ham and cheese&amp;rdquo; and then pick items off the menu that feature those words.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I can&amp;rsquo;t understand any of the language on a menu, this is my food security blanket: by ordering ham and cheese, there&amp;rsquo;s a better-than-50% chance I&amp;rsquo;ve just ordered either a sandwich or an omelet, and both are fine by me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do my best to figure out more as quickly as possible so I can sample the variety of foods each city has to offer, but by starting out with ham and cheese I can at least be sure I don&amp;rsquo;t accidentally order an artichoke and tripe soup for breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;coffee:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Coffee&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/cortado-cometa.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;cafe cortado at Cometa in Barcelona, Spain&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  A *cortado* at Cometa in Barcelona, Spain.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ordering coffee is easy in almost any language — if you see an espresso machine and say &amp;ldquo;cafe&amp;rdquo; you&amp;rsquo;ll probably get the point across effectively. The trick, though, is to &lt;strong&gt;learn the way to order coffee in each language so it comes the way you prefer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like my coffee with a little milk, which means I need to figure out what it&amp;rsquo;s called locally. In Italy, this is easy (assuming any amount of time spent in or near an American coffee shop): &lt;em&gt;cappuccino.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:cappuccino&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:cappuccino&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spanish, it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as easy — the terminology isn&amp;rsquo;t used in American cafes. &lt;em&gt;Café con leche&lt;/em&gt; (coffee with milk) is a rough equivalent to the Italian cappuccino, and the &lt;em&gt;café cortado&lt;/em&gt; is a rough equivalent of the &lt;em&gt;macchiato&lt;/em&gt; (a shot of espresso with just a dollop of steamed milk and foam).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To some this may not seem like a big deal; to me, this is a non-negotiable entry in my emergency phrasebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;things-i-don-t-like:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Things I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;m not a picky eater, it&amp;rsquo;s far easier for me to &lt;strong&gt;figure out which food items I&amp;rsquo;d like to avoid&lt;/strong&gt; than to learn all the things I might enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My list of dislikes is very short: I don&amp;rsquo;t want to order fish unless I&amp;rsquo;m in a restaurant that specializes in fish, and if I&amp;rsquo;m given a choice I&amp;rsquo;ll take the option without spinach or kale.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:spinach&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:spinach&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I learn those words and pick around them on a menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By knowing what I want to avoid, it&amp;rsquo;s far less frightening to pick something I&amp;rsquo;ve never tried off the menu. This allows me to be more adventurous in my food choices without running the risk of ordering something I know &lt;em&gt;for sure&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d rather not eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ask-for-the-bill:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;Ask for the Bill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed in restaurants is that no one will bring you the bill until you ask for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/la-cuenta.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;the bill at a restaurant&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Paying for things is harder than you might think.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s out of politeness or something else, but after the waiter clears our plates and confirms that we don&amp;rsquo;t want anything else — if we forget to ask for the bill — we&amp;rsquo;ll spend the next fifteen minutes trying to catch his eye again so we can pay and leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This proved extremely frustrating when I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to ask for it. After I got sick of waving my credit card at people, I figured I should add this to my must-learn phrases in every language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spain, when the waiter comes to clear our plates and asks if we want anything else, I decline politely and ask, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;¿La cuenta, por favor?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; (The check, please?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-your-must-learn-phrases:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f&#34;&gt;What Are Your Must-Learn Phrases?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the phrases you rely on most when you travel? Have you run into frustration with communicating while abroad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through to the discussion and share your story!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:waitress&#34;&gt;I assume she says something like, &amp;ldquo;Okay, wait just a minute,&amp;rdquo; but she could also say, &amp;ldquo;I hate you, you idiot tourist; let me go get someone who can stomach your abhorrent mother tongue.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:waitress&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:pedestrians&#34;&gt;This is actually a huge pet peeve of mine. I mean, I know that there&amp;rsquo;s no need to hurry when you&amp;rsquo;re on vacation, but there are also some basic courtesy guidelines; are you planning to stand still, looking straight up, with your mouth hanging open and your fourteen suitcases in tow? Cool. Do your thing. But please move off to the side instead of standing &lt;em&gt;right in the fucking middle&lt;/em&gt; so no one can get around you.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:pedestrians&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:pain&#34;&gt;The pain of listening to me butcher their native language. I&amp;rsquo;m not, like, giving people noogies here.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:pain&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:vegetarians&#34;&gt;Vegetarians, I feel for you; you&amp;rsquo;ll be eating a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of croissants.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:vegetarians&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:cappuccino&#34;&gt;I also learned — too late, unfortunately — that it&amp;rsquo;s culturally frowned upon to order a cappuccino after the morning. Because it&amp;rsquo;s hard on digestion, I&amp;rsquo;ve been told.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:cappuccino&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:spinach&#34;&gt;Look, I eat spinach. But it leaves a weird texture on my teeth that I&amp;rsquo;m not crazy about. And kale just tastes like dry paper. Bring on the arugula and spring mix.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ac39e985d127e502f9040ce466dd019f:spinach&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Yourself on Fire</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 08:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I use the term &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;set yourself on fire&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; frequently. To me, it means a sink-or-swim moment: &lt;strong&gt;you&amp;rsquo;ll either find a way to put this fire out, or you&amp;rsquo;re toast.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It removes the option to fail just a little bit. You now either make this work, or you go down hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, and for most people I know, this is both horribly frightening and incredibly motivating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-drawing-garfield-to-marketing-a-band:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;From Drawing Garfield to Marketing a Band&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/minusmythoughts.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;MinusMyThoughts&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tysonvick.com&#34;&gt;Tyson Vick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a musician&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, we had no income. On tour, we were lucky to get paid $100 for a show, and sometimes we could pull together $50 in sales from the merch table. It barely covered gas to get to the next city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no budget whatsoever, so things like &amp;ldquo;marketing budgets&amp;rdquo; were never even discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was a need for marketing: tour posters, merchandise, album art, web banners, MySpace customizations, a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no one to do the work. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to hire help, and none of us knew anything about that stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured, &amp;ldquo;I drew pictures of Garfield and the Ninja Turtles when I was a kid; I can figure out a tour poster.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no experience, and no idea what I was doing. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any reason that I would fail. So &lt;strong&gt;I set myself on fire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The posters weren&amp;rsquo;t great. But they also weren&amp;rsquo;t terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MySpace page went through several iterations, all of which were — let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, here — pretty MySpacey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first website I built &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20040718012243/http://minusmythoughts.com/&#34;&gt;was horrible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It was a table-based layout with no CSS, and it used iframes for content. But goddammit, if you clicked our &amp;ldquo;shows&amp;rdquo; link, you saw a list of shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it sucked. But it worked. &lt;strong&gt;And I fucking &lt;em&gt;built&lt;/em&gt; that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-a-dude-in-a-band-to-a-web-designer:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;From a Dude in a Band to a Web Designer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the few years that my band was touring, I rebuilt that website over a dozen times. At first because I could see the horrible mistakes I was making, but then it just became a fun thing for me to do in the downtime between soundcheck and going onstage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the band broke up, my friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;Nate Green&lt;/a&gt; asked me if I&amp;rsquo;d help him build a website for his new personal brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how to build a website someone else could manage, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any reason that I would fail. &lt;strong&gt;I set myself on fire again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate&amp;rsquo;s website &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20070910075625/http://www.thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t ground-breaking&lt;/a&gt;, but it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate&amp;rsquo;s business grew, and I was suddenly a web designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-life-slightly-singed:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;My Life, Slightly Singed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenges over the years have changed, but I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to keep my response consistent: I can handle that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I look at a challenge and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t put anyone in danger — I&amp;rsquo;m not going to volunteer to build a rocket or perform open-heart surgery, here — I&amp;rsquo;ll take it on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can back that trailer into the boat slip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can cook a turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each of these scenarios (all of which are real moments in my life), I had never done the thing I had just told someone I was able to do. But I trusted myself to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I set myself on fire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every case, I figured it out. I moved slowly, I did a &lt;em&gt;shitload&lt;/em&gt; of Googling, and in the end I delivered a result that was good enough to make everyone involved happy. And with practice, I&amp;rsquo;ll get to the point that it&amp;rsquo;s just a thing I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-yourself-on-fire:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;Set Yourself on Fire&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you trying to learn right now? Have you been putting it off? How can you remove your safety net so you &lt;em&gt;have to learn it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you set yourself on fire in the past? Or been set on fire by someone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit the discussion link and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;I use the term &amp;ldquo;musician&amp;rdquo; loosely, here.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t actually the &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; first site. The Wayback Machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a copy of it, unfortunately.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Drinking for Adults</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-drink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 12:31:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-drink/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In my younger days, I had mixed feelings about going out for drinks. Lately, though, I love bellying up to the bar. Just not the way &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-hit-the-bars:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s hit the bars.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My younger, single self did bars differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start at the trendy bar: watching hot girls in too-short dresses; Jameson and PBR to build the courage to approach.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:rejection&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:rejection&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, the hope of a sexy jacuzzi party fades. We move to the &amp;ldquo;cool bar&amp;rdquo; and start buying each other shots nobody wants. The smoke is thick. We choose songs on the jukebox ironically; Lionel Richie asks the room if he&amp;rsquo;s the one we&amp;rsquo;re looking for. He&amp;rsquo;s not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At closing time, we&amp;rsquo;re at a bar we swore we&amp;rsquo;d never drink in again. Hammered sorority girls wobble like baby gazelle in their six-inch heels. The guys all circle around like hyenas, ready to pick off the ones who get separated from the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we come to surrounded by fast food wrappers, nursing seventh-level hangovers, promising ourselves we&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; do this again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-not-drinking-alone:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Not Drinking Alone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, I love drinking. But I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call what I do &lt;em&gt;drinking&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to meet friends at bars and have a couple drinks. I do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; like &amp;ldquo;going drinking&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is a running joke between my friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:similar&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:similar&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and his girlfriend Chelle after he once argued, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Look, I&amp;rsquo;m not drinking alone — &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m having a cocktail by myself!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while I may be heading to a bar with the intention of having a cocktail, I&amp;rsquo;m never going with the sole purpose of getting drunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important we establish this early on, or I&amp;rsquo;ll sound like an alcoholic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-not-drinking-it-s-research:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Not Drinking, It&amp;rsquo;s Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not drinking alone; I&amp;rsquo;m having a cocktail by myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate Green&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like learning about the things I&amp;rsquo;m into. &lt;em&gt;Experiences mean more when we fully grasp the complexity of what&amp;rsquo;s happening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cocktails caught my attention because they&amp;rsquo;re a lost art&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:art&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:art&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s been rediscovered in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half the fun for me is learning how the Old Fashioned morphed over time to include club soda and muddled fruit&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:prohibition&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:prohibition&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or that the daiquiri wasn&amp;rsquo;t always a fruity Spring Break booze smoothie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could certainly learn most of this by doing online research, but half the fun in cocktails is learning about them from smart people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-drink:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;How to Drink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I go to a bar, I sit &lt;em&gt;at the bar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to see the drinks being made, and ask questions. I want to get the bartender talking so I can hear about the history of the cocktail I&amp;rsquo;m about to drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I drink now, I go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clydecommon.com/&#34;&gt;Clyde Common&lt;/a&gt; at 5pm on a Monday and ask Junior endless questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t go during happy hour or on Friday night when the bar is packed and the bartenders too busy to talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best experience at a bar was in &lt;a href=&#34;http://rumclubpdx.com/&#34;&gt;Rum Club&lt;/a&gt; after I was stood up for a 5:30 meeting. Bartenders from &lt;a href=&#34;http://expatriatepdx.com/&#34;&gt;Expatriate&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.broderpdx.com/&#34;&gt;Broder Nord&lt;/a&gt; were there; otherwise, the bar was nearly empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat with a few of Portland&amp;rsquo;s biggest cocktail nerds for an hour, learned about Aquavit and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angostura_bitters&#34;&gt;Angostura bitters&lt;/a&gt;, and even did a shotski&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:shotski&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:shotski&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/shotski.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;The Shotski&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Shotski.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://hillarymaybery.com/2010-09-kelly-creighton-wedding/&#34;&gt;Hillary Maybery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t just have a great cocktail or two; I had an awesome time learning something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-all-have-a-drink:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s All Have a Drink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part about learning all this is testing my knowledge by trying to make drinks at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I really learned (from Daniel at &lt;a href=&#34;http://teardroplounge.com/&#34;&gt;Teardrop&lt;/a&gt;) was the proper way to make an Old Fashioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Old Fashioned is a simple drink that dates back to before Prohibition. It follows a simple formula: spirit, sugar, water, and bitters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should find a great bartender near you and learn about this drink. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have access to a great bartender, here&amp;rsquo;s a video of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jeffreymorgenthaler.com/&#34;&gt;Jeffrey Morgenthaler&lt;/a&gt; showing you how it&amp;rsquo;s done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LufrnOktZiA?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a variation I&amp;rsquo;ve been making at home recently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.beamglobal.com/brands/old-overholt&#34;&gt;Old Overholt Rye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; oz honey simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 dashes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feebrothers.com/products/bitters/black_walnut_bitters.php&#34;&gt;Fee Brothers black walnut bitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orange twist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is basically an Old Fashioned, but each varied ingredient makes the drink just a little different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make it with rum instead of whisky. Maple syrup instead of honey simple. Orange bitters instead of walnut bitters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these are all variations on just one style of cocktail. The depth of information here is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-need-a-drink:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;I Need a Drink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinking is something I regularly look forward to now. Just not the way I did when I was a teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone are the days of pounding Irish whiskey and ogling cute college girls. I&amp;rsquo;m too old now, anyways; it&amp;rsquo;d be creepy&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:creepier&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:creepier&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking at cocktails the same way I look at code, business, art, and philosophy: it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating world to study, with a rich history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s delicious. Also, making a good cocktail makes me feel like Don Draper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight, I&amp;rsquo;ll be making a drink. But remember: I&amp;rsquo;m not drinking alone; I&amp;rsquo;m having a cocktail by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:rejection&#34;&gt;We never actually approach. Rejection wasn&amp;rsquo;t something our whisky-fueled egos could actually bear.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:rejection&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:similar&#34;&gt;Nate recently wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thenategreenexperience.com/the-best-time-to-go-to-a-bar/&#34;&gt;a post similar to this one&lt;/a&gt;. We had the idea over drinks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://expatriatepdx.com/&#34;&gt;Expatriate&lt;/a&gt;, and apparently he&amp;rsquo;s more motivated.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:similar&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:art&#34;&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that long ago that bartenders enjoyed a similar level of respect as doctors and lawyers. Like any trade, a bartender who takes it seriously is on the level of an artist or chef.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:art&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:prohibition&#34;&gt;During the Prohibition they were introduced to cover the flavor of low-quality alcohol.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:prohibition&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:shotski&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Didn&amp;rsquo;t you just spend 200 words talking about how drinking for the sake of drinking is bad?&amp;rdquo; Hey. Shut up. We were bonding.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:shotski&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:creepier&#34;&gt;What I should &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; say here is, &amp;ldquo;Even creepier than it used to be.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:creepier&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All Jazz</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/jazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:37:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/jazz/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have a mantra. It&amp;rsquo;s the metronome that keeps me from going into a tailspin when things go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s my reminder to keep perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all jazz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s simple. Almost silly. And it probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense unless you&amp;rsquo;re me.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-wait-jazz:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;So, Wait. Jazz?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you listen to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jazz_improvisation&#34;&gt;jazz improv&lt;/a&gt;, the musicians are all working within the general framework of the song, but they each take turns making shit up as they play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good jazz musician will play something he&amp;rsquo;s never played before — &lt;em&gt;something he&amp;rsquo;s literally making up on as he goes&lt;/em&gt; — with the kind of skill and ease that makes everyone watching feel as though it&amp;rsquo;s a standard that&amp;rsquo;s been thoroughly rehearsed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ta_UByyi4Z0?rel=0&amp;start=179&amp;end=278&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while it&amp;rsquo;s incredible to watch, this kind of improvisation also has huge implications outside of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans-and-how-they-never-work-out:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Plans, and How They Never Work Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I make a plan, it&amp;rsquo;s virtually guaranteed that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; will go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This used to drive me &lt;strong&gt;crazy.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d develop a vision of the way things ought to go, and when they failed to go &lt;em&gt;exactly right&lt;/em&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d be angry, disappointed, and resentful of the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-mad-bro:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;U Mad Bro?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It bothered me that I let myself get beat by a changed plan, so I started thinking about what it was that bothered me so much when a plan went off-track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, my plans went well. The outcome was really close to what I wanted. So what was the big deal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had set my expectations in such a way that only perfection would be considered a success.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anger, fear, and disappointment happen when our expectations are violated.﻿﻿&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This meant that even when things went my way, I&amp;rsquo;d still be upset because they &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t go exactly the way I&amp;rsquo;d imagined.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-improvisation:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;The Art of Improvisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing this, I had two choices: I could A) accept that I&amp;rsquo;d never be happy and resign myself to a life full of disappointing, mostly-successful plans, or B) figure out a better way to plan that allowed for some wiggle room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the two, the latter seemed more palatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jazz-musicians.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jazz musicians&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Making it up as they go.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://noblacktie.com.my/2011/04/28/photos-jazz-electronica-17-april-2011/&#34;&gt;No Black Tie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a large amount of trial and error, I finally came up with the jazz analogy, and built a new planning approach on two tenets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip the Details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expect Everything to Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;skip-the-details:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Skip the Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every plan is an effort to obtain a desirable outcome (e.g. &amp;ldquo;improve my client&amp;rsquo;s online marketing,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;have a nice dinner with my friends&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans, however, didn&amp;rsquo;t stop at the outcome; I&amp;rsquo;d work out which sides I would make to pair with the entrée, what games we&amp;rsquo;d play after dinner, and what cocktail I&amp;rsquo;d make to complement the meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inevitably, one or two details would change — no one would want to play a game, or I&amp;rsquo;d forget to grab an ingredient for the cocktails — and I&amp;rsquo;d be upset that it didn&amp;rsquo;t go according to plan, even though the dinner was a success overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By not worrying about the details, I&amp;rsquo;m free to focus on the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something will go wrong. So what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it does, I &lt;strong&gt;adjust within the framework of the plan and make something up.&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ll still get where we need to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forget about managing the details. Just focus on getting the desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;expect-everything-to-change:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Expect Everything to Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another case of framing, which I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/&#34;&gt;touched on before&lt;/a&gt;. If I enter a situation expecting only one outcome, I&amp;rsquo;m doomed to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I expect that things will change and trust myself to adjust accordingly, my expectations are very hard to violate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get sucked into believing that if anything goes wrong, all is lost. But in most cases, the only person who knows anything is amiss is the person who made the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where plans &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; get ruined is when the planner sinks into a funk and everyone else gets uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the musician misses a note, but powers through and just keeps playing, almost no one will notice. But if he stops mid-song to apologize about the mistake, it becomes a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-keep-playing:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Just Keep Playing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing I do ever turns out exactly the way I expect. But it usually goes pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I can do is keep playing, and, with enough practice, maybe everyone will believe that — for me at least — it&amp;rsquo;s all going according to plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;Or one of the people close enough to me that you&amp;rsquo;ve heard the lecture.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so much to be said about this — it really does explain almost every negative human interaction. Think about it next time you get mad: &amp;ldquo;What was I expecting here, and how does the reality differ from my expectations?&amp;rdquo; You&amp;rsquo;re in for a serious moment of zen, &lt;em&gt;mon frere&lt;/em&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See the Tree Coming</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When I fail, I&amp;rsquo;m presented with a choice: do I learn nothing, learn one thing, or learn a life lesson?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that sounds ridiculous. Of &lt;em&gt;course&lt;/em&gt; I should learn a life lesson, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for me, at least, learning something valuable from failure hasn&amp;rsquo;t always been easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-treadmill-treadmill:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The Treadmill Treadmill&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me try to explain with a story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled for years to stay consistent with my trips to the gym. I would get inspired, find a workout program, pick a diet plan, write a detailed daily fitness agenda, and start planning how I&amp;rsquo;d handle the dozens of beautiful women who would undoubtedly be throwing themselves at me in the coming weeks.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, despite my initial optimism, I&amp;rsquo;d find myself feeling discouraged, making excuses, and eventually abandoning the whole idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was failing. And I was being presented with a choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-five-times-i-failed-in-exactly-the-same-way:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The First Five Times I Failed In Exactly the Same Way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I made the choice to learn nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made excuses. I blamed external circumstances. I tried to convince myself that I was just better off ignoring my health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d brush it off, the memory would fade, and eventually I&amp;rsquo;d start the cycle over again &amp;ndash; only to fail in exactly the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was learning nothing, and it showed in my embarrassing lack of progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-next-five-times-i-failed-creatively:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The Next Five Times I Failed Creatively&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I recognized that I was stuck in a loop, I started choosing to learn one thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I learned that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good at working out first thing in the morning. Then I learned I couldn&amp;rsquo;t always make the afternoons work. After that I discovered that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sustain a chicken-and-steamed-broccoli diet like my bodybuilder friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time I failed again, I was learning one thing &amp;ndash; one precise set of circumstances &amp;ndash; that led to my failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-last-time-i-failed-i-learned:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The Last Time I Failed, I Learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After repeating this cycle maybe a dozen times, I finally took a step back and thought about my situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I was, trying to stay consistent with a plan to make myself healthier &amp;ndash; what better motivation is there? &amp;ndash; and somehow &lt;em&gt;I was failing every time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d learned lots of &amp;ldquo;one thing&amp;rdquo; lessons, but I&amp;rsquo;d never taken the time to examine the root of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was treating the symptoms instead of the disease.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I analyzed, and I ultimately came to the conclusion that the common thread in all my failures was that I gave up after I started to fail: if I missed a workout or had some ice cream, I felt like I&amp;rsquo;d ruined everything and just gave up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an &amp;ldquo;all or nothing&amp;rdquo; type. So when I made a plan, I had to execute it flawlessly or I was wasting my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I learned a life lesson: &lt;strong&gt;I need to set my bar low enough that I can always hit my goal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans started out as, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to do this huge workout and eat exactly these things.&amp;rdquo; The simple lowering of that bar to, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to do something active every day and make sure I eat vegetables with every meal,&amp;rdquo; has made it possible for me to always hit my goal, and as a result I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed consistent for nearly a year now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To clarify, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that I set low expectations that allow me to skate by. I&amp;rsquo;m just adjusting the definition of &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; so that I can sustainably hit my goals. If my goal is &amp;ldquo;just get to the gym, even if you show up, turn around, and go back home,&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve set the bar really low. However, while I&amp;rsquo;ve been to the gym and done a less-than-stellar workout, I&amp;rsquo;ve never showed up to the gym and done &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no picture of perfect human health or anything, but I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; climb stairs without wheezing and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any aches or pains &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s all I really need to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m taking care of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-working-out.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf working out&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One of my &amp;ldquo;get moving&amp;rdquo; activities: conditioning class at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elementalfitnesslab.com/&#34;&gt;Elemental Fitness Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-the-source:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;Finding the Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the obvious benefit to my physical well-being, dealing with my failures taught me one of the most useful life skills I&amp;rsquo;ve come across yet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you fail, try to understand &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you failed instead of just learning how to avoid repeating this one mistake.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I run into a tree, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t just glare at the tree and then go about my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t just make a note of where the tree is so I can avoid it next time I pass this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I should try to understand why I didn&amp;rsquo;t see the tree coming in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-practice:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond my fitness goals, this approach to failure has helped me in every area of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s helped me understand that when I lose clients, it&amp;rsquo;s not because that client is beyond help or because I worded something incorrectly; it&amp;rsquo;s because I violated their expectations, which put them on edge and started a downward spiral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s helped me understand that when I end up fighting with my girlfriend, it&amp;rsquo;s not because she&amp;rsquo;s irrational or because I&amp;rsquo;m too detached; it&amp;rsquo;s because I made her feel attacked, or unimportant, or a similarly unsavory emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This applies to dozens of other examples that I could have brushed past as one-off incidents (or worse, forgotten entirely). Each failure gives me a little window into how I&amp;rsquo;m perceived by others, or how I&amp;rsquo;m wired, and it allows me to &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; my personality &amp;ndash; I can see certain trees coming and avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll hit hundreds more trees &amp;ndash; thousands even &amp;ndash; as I continue to grow and learn and fail, but if I&amp;rsquo;m doing this right, they won&amp;rsquo;t be the same trees all that often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/27139502@N00/460096222/&#34;&gt;Andy Cox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;I had this all worked out: there would be a reality show where these women would showcase their intelligence, strength, and wit through a Billy Madison-esque decathlon featuring such events as &amp;ldquo;Carry Me Up the Stairs as if I&amp;rsquo;ve Been Injured&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Write Me a Haiku About Bears&amp;rdquo;. There would be laughter, tears, strategy, and a Final Challenge that probably involved the Nerf guns from &lt;em&gt;American Gladiators&lt;/em&gt;. The series would be met with lackluster reviews, but a strong cult following.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;The big difference here is &lt;em&gt;framing&lt;/em&gt;. Before, when I was failing, doing a quick workout because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling 100% would constitute a failure; now, I look at &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; workout being better than no workout. Get it?
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Alone with My Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/time-alone-with-my-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 22:23:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/time-alone-with-my-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Or, the measures I’m taking to avoid sinking into the trap of dying frustrated and ignorant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest things about writing is just sitting down to write. I&amp;rsquo;ve been telling myself that I&amp;rsquo;d get around to blogging again for&amp;hellip;three years, now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like writing. I think thoughts that I find helpful. I believe that some of those thoughts &amp;ndash; in theory, at least &amp;ndash; are valuable when applied by humans other than myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the silence, then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a lack of desire, certainly. At least once a day it occurs to me that something I&amp;rsquo;ve said or done or learned or screwed up could be worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not fear. I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly long to spill my guts publicly, but I&amp;rsquo;m far from shy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My literary cease-fire, then, boils down to either inertia or screwy priorities. Probably, if I&amp;rsquo;m being completely honest, a fair amount of both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That, or just my own unwillingness to spend an extended amount of time alone with my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a trend right now in the circles I run in: more and more people around me are meditating or keeping gratitude journals or something similarly, inwardly peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not me, though. I can&amp;rsquo;t do it; meditation feels forced and awkward, and a gratitude journal is just homework from a lifestyle blogger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even though my knee-jerk reaction is to write it all off as new agey, touchy-feeley, hippie dippy bullshit, I see the value in it. We need to be alone with our thoughts; to spend some time sifting through all the noise in our minds; to think a little bit about the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; of what we&amp;rsquo;re feeling instead of just the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s next&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s some pretty important, grownup-level business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That leaves me with a bit of a conundrum: I feel like an asshole counting my breaths or keeping a diary of warm fuzzies, but I see a valid and pressing need to stay mindful of where I am, what I&amp;rsquo;m feeling, and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m here to learn. If I&amp;rsquo;m not learning from the things I feel, I&amp;rsquo;m just barreling toward death as a ball of unexamined loneliness, momentary joy, and mystery boners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes sense to me is to just take half an hour each day and write. No set subject matter, no agenda, no business model &amp;ndash; just a (completely public) space to spend a little alone time with the chaos in my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And really, this may just prove to be my way of both meditating &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; keeping a gratitude journal, tweaked just enough that I can convince myself it&amp;rsquo;s neither.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>