<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Success on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Success on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 09:35:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizards and Assholes</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/wizards-and-assholes</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 09:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/wizards-and-assholes</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One of my early jobs was at a local publishing house, where I did typesetting and rudimentary layout work for field guides. There was a guy there — we&amp;rsquo;ll call him Carl — who handled the still-new digital aspect of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had built a website or two at this point. My work was total amateur hour, but I could tell that this kind of work was something I enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl was the first person I&amp;rsquo;d met who worked on websites for a living.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; At the time, he represented all of the things I wanted in my career. So I looked up to him as a mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, Carl, can I ask you a question? How can I get to where you are? What should I do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl looked at me, sizing me up. He had a smirk on his face. His condescending gaze was amused, like, &amp;ldquo;Who the fuck does this kid think he is?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ron-swanson-condescending.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Ron Swanson condescending&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  I want to make sure you feel like a complete idiot.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1266020/&#34;&gt;Parks and Recreation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt ashamed. I wanted to take my question back. I wanted to hide under the desk until Carl left for the day so I could slink home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked at me for a long time. I shriveled under his stare, questioning everything about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can you tell me the difference between cell padding and cell spacing?&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty sure I knew the answer. I thought maybe it was a trick question. I second-guessed myself. I hesitated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He chuckled and shook his head, disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re not ready to handle the kinds of work I do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-was-an-asshole:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;Carl Was an Asshole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl was forty-something years old, working a job that — in retrospect — was entry-level at best. His skill level was nothing to brag about; he could get the job done, but no one was going to knock any doors down to hire him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Carl was a big fish in a small pond. There was no competition for his job, because no one in Montana at the time was taking digital media very seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/the-wizard.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;The Wizard of Oz&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Pay no attention to the dickhead lording his junior-level skill set over your head.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1JF0EdZ&#34;&gt;The Wizard of Oz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made Carl a lot like the Wizard of Oz: he was mysterious and powerful, dealing in forces that few people really understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I was Dorothy, lost on this brand new career path, looking for someone to guide me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was an eager student. Carl was in a position to help me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, he chose to be an elitist asshole and made me feel stupid for not knowing the things I&amp;rsquo;d just asked him for help with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-of-becoming-irrelevant:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;Fear of Becoming Irrelevant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to think that Carl just didn&amp;rsquo;t like me. He thought I was some dumb kid who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t amount to much and who was probably just on his hobby of the week. Why waste time on the likes of me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think something else may have been at play: Carl might have seen me as a threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not directly. Carl wasn&amp;rsquo;t thinking, &amp;ldquo;Oh no! This kid&amp;rsquo;s about to take my job!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On some level, though, I think Carl may have seen my questions as a threat to his job security. After all, if enough people learned this stuff, it&amp;rsquo;d be a lot more difficult for him to remain the big fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl wanted to be indispensable. He wanted to be the lynchpin in the organization, without which everything would go off the rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That meant treating his knowledge like a trade secret, and boxing out anyone who might weaken his grip on this job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it didn&amp;rsquo;t excuse humiliating a teenager for showing interest in his field of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-be-like-carl:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Be Like Carl&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I was in Boston speaking at an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one of the evenings there was a cocktail mixer at a bar called Lucky&amp;rsquo;s, a basement bar in South Boston. It was the sort of dimly lit, brick-walled dive where you imagine finding disreputable people discussing unsavory acts, but actually find disinterested twenty-somethings discussing undiscovered bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jake-pruitt.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jake Pruitt&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the night wound down, the group I was standing with was approached by this kid, &lt;a href=&#34;http://javascriptjake.com/&#34;&gt;Jake&lt;/a&gt;, who looked like he was about 12 years old. He was 20, in college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment, I was dismissive. &lt;em&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s probably out of his depth,&lt;/em&gt; I thought. &lt;em&gt;I hope he doesn&amp;rsquo;t start asking a bunch of dumb questions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I was angry with myself for letting thoughts like that into my head. I remembered how it felt when I asked Carl for advice, and how humiliated I was when he talked down to me and made me feel like I was too dumb to play on his level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be like Carl,&lt;/em&gt; I reminded myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake was outgoing, curious, personable. He asked a ton of questions, and the whole group joined in to answer them as best we could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point I started giving him shit because he kept pulling his phone out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m taking notes on what you&amp;rsquo;re saying,&amp;rdquo; he told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was both flattering and terrifying. &lt;em&gt;This kid is listening to me? Is that&amp;hellip; Should he be doing that?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it felt good. Here was this kid: excited to learn, passionate about building a career, and looking to me for a little guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake was an eager student. I was in a position to help him out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have been an elitist asshole. I could have done my best to assert my superiority and make him feel dumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it felt way better to help him out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Jake felt good about things, too; later that evening, I got a note from him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Really great chatting with you, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jlengstorf&#34;&gt;@jlengstorf&lt;/a&gt;. Super great life tips, I hope to be like you when I grow up!
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Jake Pruitt (@thejakepruitt)&lt;/small&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thejakepruitt/status/527644976113803265&#34;&gt;October 30, 2014&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;there-s-room-for-all-of-us:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s Room for All of Us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake will end up being pretty successful. He&amp;rsquo;s smart, ambitious, and he&amp;rsquo;s got a head start on his career. He&amp;rsquo;s years ahead of where I was at his age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So should I worry about Jake replacing me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe. But at least now I can remind him that I was a helping hand on his way up, and hope that he&amp;rsquo;ll give me a job when he does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;During the early 2000s in Montana, there were approximately seven people who knew what the internet was.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;For the non-nerds in the room, let me try to put this question into perspective. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re curious to know more about engines, and you ask a mechanic how what you should do to learn more about cars. In response, he says to you, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between using a horse to pull your carriage, or using a donkey?&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me Against the World</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/me-against-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 23:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/me-against-the-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The idea of &amp;ldquo;me against the world&amp;rdquo; is strange. It implies that, for whatever reason, I pose a threat to The World and, therefore, must be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World will strike at me with weather and illness; with fairweather friends and canceled flights; with unrequited love and full seasons of &lt;em&gt;Entourage&lt;/em&gt; on demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World is out to get me. The World wants me to fail. The World is an unstoppable current against which I have to battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World is Dr. Doom, hellbent on ruining my happiness and success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/dog-against-the-world.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Dog Against the World&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The World is out to get this dog, too. Look how thoughtful he is.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s how it works. There&amp;rsquo;s no supervillain manifested in The World; there&amp;rsquo;s just the world: at best an indifferent observer, and more likely an inanimate object that doesn&amp;rsquo;t do too much of anything except &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; notice when I succeed, fail, live, or die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-is-not-against-me:545e32d7f89a68970f2c2d20a1ec1a67&#34;&gt;The World Is Not Against Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t even know I&amp;rsquo;m here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, this is terrifying. I&amp;rsquo;m a boat on the ocean, fighting wind and waves, and the storm would swallow me, my hopes, and dreams, all without a thought about me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How insignificant and small I must be, for the world to take no notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world doesn&amp;rsquo;t care if I fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-also-doesn-t-care-if-i-succeed:545e32d7f89a68970f2c2d20a1ec1a67&#34;&gt;The World Also Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Care If I Succeed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can die in my parents&amp;rsquo; basement as a jobless, dreamless nobody, or I can die as the best version of myself I can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world doesn&amp;rsquo;t care either way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the world won&amp;rsquo;t try to hold me back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the game of life, I&amp;rsquo;m playing without an opponent. I can succeed or fail, and the only person who really gives a shit is me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most hopeful, empowering phrase I can think of: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;no one but me cares about this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means I can do what makes me happy. I can put myself first. I can write, or create, try something I&amp;rsquo;m not good at, or change my ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also means I&amp;rsquo;m free to avoid anything hard, scary, uncomfortable, or unfamiliar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or I can charge headlong into this burning building and carry out my dreams before there&amp;rsquo;s nothing left to burn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-ll-go-as-far-as-i-m-willing-to-go:545e32d7f89a68970f2c2d20a1ec1a67&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll Go as Far as I&amp;rsquo;m Willing to Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only have two obstacles in life: willpower and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one will try to stop me from learning enough to gain understanding. So really, understanding is just another test of willpower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So will I dig in, trust myself, and push until I get what I want in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or will I give up, settle in, and tell myself The World is out to get me?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Not a Phony</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/not-a-phony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 15:24:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/not-a-phony/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Confidence is kind of a dirty word these days. Talking about our strengths and abilities makes us feel like impostors. We&amp;rsquo;re all insecure, and &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sick of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I read an old post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/ImAPhonyAreYou.aspx&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; about feeling like a phony. It reminded me of another post by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scrawnytobrawny.com/my-success-is-a-lie&#34;&gt;Nate Green&lt;/a&gt; on the same subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sentiment behind both of these articles is summed up pretty well in this quote from Nate (for context, he&amp;rsquo;s talking about how he got &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1m1oy3S&#34;&gt;a book deal&lt;/a&gt; at 23 with no formal education):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who the hell did I think I was?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only a matter of time, I thought. Only a matter of time before everyone realizes I have no business doing any of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any moment, I would be exposed as a fraud. On a large scale. And it scared the shit out of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-get-trained-to-feel-like-phonies:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;We Get Trained to Feel Like Phonies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty widespread sentiment among the people I know who are successful. Far too many things are working against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the slow build, which pretty much guarantees that you never really notice your success.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Lots of things have improved for me since I was a broke freelancer working 16-hour days in an apartment that I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure had black mold — but I don&amp;rsquo;t really &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; different than that younger, less experienced version of myself.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the realization that knowing almost everything about Thing A only leads to the further realization that — in order to &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; understand the &amp;ldquo;big picture&amp;rdquo; — a complete knowledge of Things B, C, and D is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, most importantly, we get told that feeling competent and self-assured is socially unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;apologize-for-your-progress:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;Apologize for Your Progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the lines, it became unacceptable to feel proud of our success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying out loud that you&amp;rsquo;re skilled is met with derision. &amp;ldquo;You sound arrogant.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re acting like you&amp;rsquo;re better than everyone else.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s be clear: I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about &lt;em&gt;bragging&lt;/em&gt;, here. There&amp;rsquo;s a world of difference between, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m making a lot of progress at work right now; all that hard work is finally paying off,&amp;rdquo; and, &amp;ldquo;I am &lt;em&gt;killing it&lt;/em&gt; right now — who wants to touch me?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels, though, that the pursuit of political correctness has made it a &lt;em&gt;faux pas&lt;/em&gt; to talk about what you&amp;rsquo;re capable of in most situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I find myself actively try to steer conversations away from what I&amp;rsquo;m doing because I&amp;rsquo;m worried that I&amp;rsquo;ll come off like an asshole if I talk about the things I&amp;rsquo;m working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-am-not-a-phony:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;I Am NOT a Phony&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not the smartest guy in the world. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the most things about anything. There are much smarter people, much more experienced people, much better-looking people, much funnier people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet I still represent myself as an expert on certain topics, and I still think I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just because someone else is better doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m not good.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, on top of that, I have a very unique blend of strengths that make me extremely valuable in certain situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people ask for my services, I don&amp;rsquo;t look around like &lt;em&gt;who, me?&lt;/em&gt; — I take the compliment and get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-okay-to-be-confident:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Okay to Be Confident&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate that when I compliment someone, the expected response is, &amp;ldquo;Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m not any good. I just got lucky.&amp;rdquo; Or, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by a great team.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We deflect the praise because it just feels too &lt;em&gt;icky&lt;/em&gt; to admit we&amp;rsquo;re good at things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear myself say shit like this all the time. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be branded a cocky prick, so I give all the credit to other people, or hide behind some self-deprecating wisecrack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of this is humility, which is a good thing. But it&amp;rsquo;s been taken to the extreme where accepting &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; praise is somehow uncouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: I have been fortunate, and I do have an incredible team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;but I&amp;rsquo;m also really fucking good at what I do.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve put in tens of thousands of hours learning this craft, and every year I put in thousands more continuing my education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a phony. I belong here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-guy-s-a-dick:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;This Guy&amp;rsquo;s a Dick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post sounds like bragging. Like I&amp;rsquo;m trying to tell everyone how great I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say here is that &lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s okay to be proud of your accomplishments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re being honest with yourself, talking about your accomplishments is perfectly acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;m not advocating constant self-adulation. It requires a little tact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-own-your-success-without-being-a-dick:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;How to Own Your Success Without Being a Dick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know my friends, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I still struggle with &amp;ldquo;the line&amp;rdquo; sometimes. But I&amp;rsquo;m working on a system of rules to keep myself from being a dick in conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never bring up your own success.&lt;/strong&gt; You can&amp;rsquo;t avoid sounding self-serving if you insert praise for yourself into a conversation; let someone else ask first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t exaggerate.&lt;/strong&gt; Hyperbole is great for a cute anecdote, but if it turns out you&amp;rsquo;re telling a success story that&amp;rsquo;s been embellished, you&amp;rsquo;ll look like a liar. If anything, play &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt; the details a bit.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop at one.&lt;/strong&gt; If you end up telling a success story, don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself get sucked into telling another one. This is hard, because once you start talking about yourself it&amp;rsquo;s hard to stop. But, seriously. Stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spend more time asking questions and listening than talking.&lt;/strong&gt; This is huge. Unless you&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to speak, spend more time seeing what you can learn from everyone else at the table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a complete list, but it (usually) keeps me from coming off like a douchebag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-not-a-phony-either:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re Not a Phony, Either&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we make a deal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, let&amp;rsquo;s try to own our successes. We&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s recognize that we&amp;rsquo;re not the best or the smartest, but we&amp;rsquo;re pretty damn good, and we&amp;rsquo;re pretty damn smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are NOT impostors. We are NOT frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are fucking awesome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;This is called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normalcy&#34;&gt;creeping normalcy&lt;/a&gt;, which is the idea that we don&amp;rsquo;t notice changes if they happen in small increments over a long period of time. Usually this is used to describe negative changes, but the same effects seem to be present with the positive as well.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;Except for the whole &amp;ldquo;not dying of black mold-related illness&amp;rdquo; thing.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;I am. I&amp;rsquo;m awesome.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;For example, if you launched a successful company, don&amp;rsquo;t talk about the press or awards you&amp;rsquo;re getting. Instead, talk about what you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt;, and let someone else talk about how much everyone else likes you.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>