<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Excitement on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/excitement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Excitement on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:08:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/excitement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/leaving</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/leaving</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was eating leftovers over the sink with plastic silverware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous morning, Marisa, her mother, and I had braved the line at Screen Door for one last Portland brunch. I finished the remnants of my chicken and waffles, doing my best to not to make a mess on the freshly-scrubbed counter and floor in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apartment was completely empty. The cleaning service had left it sparkling. There was so much reverb when I spoke that it felt closer to an echo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The giant living room I&amp;rsquo;d loved so much was bare. I&amp;rsquo;d taken the blanket and pillows we&amp;rsquo;d slept on the night before out to the trash.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:donations&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:donations&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Nicole from the cleaning service had taken nearly everything else — &amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t bill you for the hour I spent loading your stuff into my car,&amp;rdquo; she texted me later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only two small suitcases, two backpacks, a box of last-minute chores, and a couple small trash cans remained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is everything I own,&lt;/em&gt; I thought to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/everything-i-own.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;everything I own in two carry-on bags&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marisa showed up around five thirty. We threw away the final few items from the fridge and tossed the trash — cans and all — into the compactor on the building&amp;rsquo;s first floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wheeled our luggage out of the apartment and I locked the door. I stopped by the manager&amp;rsquo;s office. My heart was hurling itself against the walls of my ribcage, and I ran through the checklist for the hundred-thousandth time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all done. The apartment is empty. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing left to forget.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt a little dizzy as I dropped the keys in the mail slot. They hit the bottom of the container on the other side with a nauseating finality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s it,&amp;rdquo; I said. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m officially homeless.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;my experiment in permanent travel&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been met with some variation on the question, &amp;ldquo;Are you excited?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reactions from my friends and family have ranged from excitement and good-natured jealousy to near-panic and quiet disapproval,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:disapproval&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:disapproval&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but — regardless of their view — everyone wants to know how I&amp;rsquo;m feeling about the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a question that feels like small talk. But as I went through the motions of responding — &amp;ldquo;Yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a great adventure!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I know, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard amazing things about Italy!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;There won&amp;rsquo;t be any pizza left by the time I leave!&amp;rdquo; — pointed out something disconcerting to me as the kick-off date drew nearer: &lt;em&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling excited.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t nervous. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t afraid. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t second-guessing my decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;anything.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flight DAL418 to Milan was to me — as far as I was emotionally processing things — just another flight. My 59th of the year. Another 3,982 miles added to my SkyMiles balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The realization that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t emotionally addressing this trip concerned me a little. Was I compartmentalizing too much? Was I bottling up my excitement and fear, wiring up an emotional booby trap that could detonate at at any moment? Was I in for a truly spectacular breakdown in JFK, collapsed in on myself in the Terminal 4 Starbucks, sobbing uncontrollably, feeling a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of repressed feelings all at once?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night before the flight, I was restless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the work was done. The tickets were purchased. All we had left to do was show up at the airport on time in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ate our last meal in Portland at Robo Taco around nine. We ordered burritos and settled into a dimly lit corner. To my left, a muted television played PBS reruns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are you okay?&amp;rdquo; Marisa asked me between bites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was giddy. Nervous. Excited. Relieved that the work of severing my ties to Oregon was finally done. Happy that I&amp;rsquo;d found a traveling partner. Scared that I was jumping with both feet into a world I don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This feels like the first day of school,&amp;rdquo; I said. I was eating my burrito with a fork and knife because I&amp;rsquo;d squeezed too hard and broken the tortilla, spilling the contents out the back. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m happy and sad and excited and scared. It&amp;rsquo;s that feeling of &amp;lsquo;into the unknown&amp;rsquo;, you know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation lulled as we finished eating, and we watched Bob Ross paint some happy little trees. Then we headed for the airport hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At four this morning, Marisa&amp;rsquo;s alarm went off. She got up to shower, and I went back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At ten to six we were in the security line. Six fifteen we were at the gate with coffee in hand. On the plane by seven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this, I&amp;rsquo;m somewhere over the Atlantic Ocean, getting further and further away from a home I no longer have. All of my former possessions are settling into new homes with the friends and strangers on Craigslist who bought them. The apartment I locked up last night has already been rented to new tenants; I imagine they&amp;rsquo;ll start moving in this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything I own in the world is in two bags: one at my feet, and one above my head. I didn&amp;rsquo;t leave behind a storage unit, or an attic-load of furniture for my parents to hold onto. &lt;em&gt;This is it.&lt;/em&gt; These bags. The clothes I&amp;rsquo;m wearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a few hours I&amp;rsquo;ll be in Milan, Italy, hauling my two bags into a stranger&amp;rsquo;s home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should be sleeping to ward off the imminent jet lag, but I&amp;rsquo;m still restless. I can feel the weight of my eyelids, but I can&amp;rsquo;t stop thinking about the adventures that lie ahead — pizza! gelato! and I guess some old buildings and stuff&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:food&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:food&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; — and the problems I haven&amp;rsquo;t solved yet.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:problems&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:problems&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still don&amp;rsquo;t feel as excited as is maybe appropriate. And I certainly don&amp;rsquo;t feel as worried as my mom probably is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I feel a pressure building in my chest and throat that makes me want to either burst into laughter or tears. I feel proud that I have built a career that allows me to take this trip. I feel lucky to live in an age where technology allows a lifestyle like this to exist. I feel hopeful that my research and preparation will prove to be at least mostly correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly sure how I should feel about all of this. But I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely sure that I&amp;rsquo;m ready for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:donations&#34;&gt;I sold, donated, or gave away nearly everything I owned that was suitable for reuse. However, bedding is gross to share with a stranger, and my sheets had worn to the point where — a couple weeks prior to throwing them away — a hole had opened up near my (apparently) razor-sharp toenails.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:donations&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:disapproval&#34;&gt;Not disapproval in the sense of, &amp;ldquo;You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do this, it&amp;rsquo;s a bad idea,&amp;rdquo; but more in the sense of, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t understand how you&amp;rsquo;re going to make this work and therefore cannot condone your actions.&amp;rdquo; No one has told me I &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; take this trip; I&amp;rsquo;ve just had a few people find the whole concept too big and daunting, and from them I&amp;rsquo;ve been met with a lot of uncomfortable silences and worried groans. (&amp;ldquo;Mom, I&amp;rsquo;m going to live in Europe for a year.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Mom emits a sound similar to&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/F_XaIuw6K6Q?t=9s&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tina in&lt;/em&gt; Bob&amp;rsquo;s Burgers&lt;/a&gt;.)
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:disapproval&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:food&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marisa:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;You talk like we&amp;rsquo;re only going to be eating while we&amp;rsquo;re there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Well, we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; only going to be eating while we&amp;rsquo;re there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marisa:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going to see museums and architecture and stuff, too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;I mean, sure — on the way to our next meal.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:food&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:problems&#34;&gt;I still don&amp;rsquo;t know for sure how this whole &amp;ldquo;unlocked phone with a SIM card&amp;rdquo; thing will work. I forgot to save the directions to the first Airbnb, so I need to find wifi access before we can get there. I don&amp;rsquo;t speak Italian. I just learned that &lt;a href=&#34;http://barcelona.de/en/barcelona-languages.html&#34;&gt;people in Barcelona speak Catalan&lt;/a&gt;, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know was a language until a few days ago.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:97550d4b9bf5d0424943b399f8ecfa49:problems&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>