<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stayingconnected on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/stayingconnected/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stayingconnected on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 06:44:03 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/stayingconnected/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Essentials: How to Set Up a Mobile Phone Abroad</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-mobile-phone-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 06:44:03 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-mobile-phone-abroad/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Since having a mobile phone is now more or less a requirement for being a functional member of society, it&amp;rsquo;s important to find a way to get your hands on a phone while abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key benefit to having a working phone is access to wireless data, which is invaluable when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to navigate a new city where the street signs aren&amp;rsquo;t in English, or if you need to quickly look up how to say &amp;ldquo;coconut oil&amp;rdquo; in Thai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the benefits of data, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to receive calls and texts from your friends and family in your home country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a slightly confusing setup — I&amp;rsquo;ll explain thoroughly, I promise — you can keep a local number while abroad, complete with text and picture message, while also setting up a local phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s all &lt;em&gt;way cheaper&lt;/em&gt; than a mobile contract in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/how-to-set-up-a-mobile-phone-abroad.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;How to set up a mobile phone while traveling abroad.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-an-unlocked-phone-with-a-sim-card-slot:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Buy an Unlocked Phone with a SIM Card Slot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you&amp;rsquo;ve got your phone numbers and forwarding worked out, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a phone that works in all the countries you want to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most US mobile carriers subsidize the cost of phones with contracts, the phones they sell are locked — this makes them useless if they&amp;rsquo;re not on that carrier&amp;rsquo;s network and plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To avoid insane roaming fees, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to buy an unlocked phone.&lt;/strong&gt; When you see the cost of an unlocked phone, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably shit your pants — just remember that when you &amp;ldquo;buy&amp;rdquo; a phone with a contract, you&amp;rsquo;re also committing to about $1,200 in phone bills over the next year, so a $600 phone isn&amp;rsquo;t actually that expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure the phone you buy allows you to swap out the SIM card, and that it will work on GSM networks. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what that means, do a search for the phone model you want to buy and whether or not it works in the countries you want to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1GyjrWh&#34;&gt;purchased an unlocked iPhone 6&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s worked in the US, Europe, and Southeast Asia without any issues so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-a-prepaid-sim-card-once-you-land:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Buy a Prepaid SIM Card Once You Land&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I found out how cheap it was to have a prepaid SIM in other countries, I spent a half-hour ranting about how criminal the mobile carrier racket is in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve left the United States, I have spent less than $40/month on prepaid voice/text/data plans.&lt;/strong&gt; Usually much less.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:uk&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:uk&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick search will point you to several discussions about the best SIM for whichever country you&amp;rsquo;re headed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we&amp;rsquo;ve used Three in both Italy and the UK, Yoigo in Spain, and TrueMove H in Thailand. Italy has been the most expensive so far at €35 for a month, and I think that was mainly because I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what the hell I was doing and bought a more expensive package than I actually needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way I&amp;rsquo;ve found to get a SIM is to &lt;strong&gt;go directly to a retail store&lt;/strong&gt; for whichever carrier you choose, then &lt;strong&gt;find the prepaid plan that suits your needs.&lt;/strong&gt; (We&amp;rsquo;ve been able to find brochures in English almost everywhere, as well as people working the counters who are able to speak English well enough to get us set up.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A word of advice: &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t leave the store until you&amp;rsquo;ve verified that you can get online, make a call, and send a text message.&lt;/strong&gt; You probably won&amp;rsquo;t run into any issues, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to find out an hour later that a step was missed — and you &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t want to try and explain what&amp;rsquo;s happened to a different employee whose English is about as good as your Italian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;having-a-local-number-helps:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Having a Local Number Helps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A benefit that I didn&amp;rsquo;t initially consider when getting SIM cards is the bonus of having a local number wherever you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Barcelona, we made friends with some locals, and being able to shoot them texts without anyone spending a fortune was very handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In London, calling local businesses to ask if they had something we needed was an enormous time-saver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It won&amp;rsquo;t come up often, but when it does, it&amp;rsquo;s great to know you&amp;rsquo;ve got that covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-data-plans-are-cheap-if-you-re-reasonable:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;The Data Plans Are Cheap — If You&amp;rsquo;re Reasonable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data usage is usually pretty cheap, and the allowances are reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, &amp;ldquo;normal usage&amp;rdquo; consists of getting directions and looking up places in Google Maps, checking various social networks once or twice a day, sending a few photos to my friends via MMS, and occasionally asking Google to settle debates.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:debates&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:debates&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re live-streaming everything you do through Periscope, your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;staying-connected-to-your-us-based-friends-and-family:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Staying Connected to Your US-Based Friends and Family&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure your loved ones don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay international calling rates to get in touch with you, you can leverage Google and Skype to make sure you can still receive calls — just like you were still in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-a-google-voice-number:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Get a Google Voice Number&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re in the US, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/googlevoice/about.html&#34;&gt;Google Voice&lt;/a&gt; is a simple option to give yourself a US-based number that friends can call or text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a Google Voice number, you can call or text your friends right from the Gmail app, as well as from the Hangouts app. &lt;strong&gt;Your incoming calls and texts can be forwarded to any US-based phone number&lt;/strong&gt; — I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how to work around this a bit later — or to your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re also able to set up voicemail with custom greetings, call blocking, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you use your computer (or the Hangouts app on wifi) &lt;strong&gt;you can make calls and send texts from your Google Voice number for free.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great way to make sure your family and friends don&amp;rsquo;t have to contact you through an app — my parents, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, greatly appreciate not having to learn what the hell a WhatsApp is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-up-a-skype-number-for-call-forwarding:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Set Up a Skype Number for Call Forwarding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To work around Google Voice&amp;rsquo;s US-only call-forwarding restriction, &lt;strong&gt;you can get a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skype.com/en/features/&#34;&gt;Skype number&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for $60/year, which allows you to forward the calls to international numbers in most countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you&amp;rsquo;ve set up the Skype number, &lt;strong&gt;set your Google Voice number to forward to it.&lt;/strong&gt; Turn off any of Skype&amp;rsquo;s extra features, like voicemail, to make sure that the call goes through to your phone and your Google Voice voicemail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this is set up, you just have to remember to set the Skype number to forward to your local number wherever you&amp;rsquo;re staying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;staying-connected-is-easier-and-cheaper-than-you-might-think:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Staying Connected Is Easier (and Cheaper) than You Might Think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was concerned before I left that I&amp;rsquo;d have a really difficult and expensive time trying to stay connected abroad. I was concerned I&amp;rsquo;d need to ration my data usage, tell my friends to stop texting me, and pay a fortune to call home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with a little bit of legwork up front, it turns out that &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll actually &lt;em&gt;save a shitload of money&lt;/em&gt; this year over what I was spending to keep a phone through Verizon in the US.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After seeing the ease of setting it up, and the savings of going prepaid, I&amp;rsquo;m a believer; I&amp;rsquo;ll be a hard sell to ever get a mobile contract again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:uk&#34;&gt;In London I put £15 on a SIM from Three and — after normal use — still had £5 of credit left when I headed to the airport a month later.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:uk&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:debates&#34;&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to stop this. Google ruins &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/funny-stuff/the-fine-art-of-bullshit-c09f7bbb391e&#34;&gt;the art of bullshit&lt;/a&gt;, which is half the reason it&amp;rsquo;s fun to debate things over dinner in the first place.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:debates&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>