<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stats on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/stats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stats on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 01:05:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/stats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The No-Distractions Productivity Experiment Results and Stats</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 01:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-results/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I made today an experiment in single-tasking to see if it would make me more productive without setting the house on fire. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I talked about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-experiment/&#34;&gt;benefits of working without distractions&lt;/a&gt; and laid the ground rules for an experiment with my own working style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s currently just before midnight, and I&amp;rsquo;m willing to call the experiment a resounding success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a recap and some stats from my No-Distractions Experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-schedule:66dccf2bda6baf27f2868184e0c5b386&#34;&gt;The Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:00AM:&lt;/strong&gt; Alarm goes off. I have two hours before I have to be anywhere — I told myself last night that I&amp;rsquo;d use this time to shoot off a couple quick emails before the experiment officially started. Instead I hit the snooze for half an hour, then get sucked into an article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/&#34;&gt;The Pastry Box Project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8:00AM:&lt;/strong&gt; I finally get out of bed and walk over to get a cup of coffee. I talk with Tim the barista about Miami and how he almost moved to Little Haiti once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:00AM:&lt;/strong&gt; I arrive at &lt;a href=&#34;http://elementalfitnesslab.com/&#34;&gt;Elemental Fitness Lab&lt;/a&gt; and manage to neither throw up nor cry during the workout. I take this as a good omen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10:15AM:&lt;/strong&gt; Ali and I head for a quick breakfast so we can spend some time together before I abandon her for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10:52AM:&lt;/strong&gt; I notify the world that this experiment is beginning, because &lt;em&gt;obviously&lt;/em&gt; everyone is waiting with bated breath to hear the details of my work day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Autoresponder on, email closed &amp;amp; after this tweet the phone is going on airplane mode. No distractions! &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/At03t5gqrJ&#34;&gt;http://t.co/At03t5gqrJ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/productivity?src=hash&#34;&gt;#productivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jason Lengstorf (@jlengstorf) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jlengstorf/status/420629077381246976&#34;&gt;January 7, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:00AM:&lt;/strong&gt; The first no-distractions block begins, scheduled for 3 hours. I am able to accomplish:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A preliminary reorganization of my todos by difficulty, since the hard stuff should probably happen while I have time to focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clearing of the Bitbucket issue tracker on two works in progress for Copter clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site adjustments for the paperback release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://louschuler.com/&#34;&gt;Lou Schuler&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; latest book, &lt;em&gt;The New Rules of Lifting: Supercharged&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design updates for a site we&amp;rsquo;re working on with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jon_ptdc&#34;&gt;Jon Goodman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3:00PM:&lt;/strong&gt; Break for lunch. It&amp;rsquo;s been nice not having my phone buzzing at me, so I leave it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4:15PM:&lt;/strong&gt; The second no-distractions block kicks off. I had originally planned this to go from 3:30–6:30, but I worked a little longer on the first block than I expected, so I decide to play this one by ear. I accomplish:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art revisions for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nutritiouslife.com/&#34;&gt;Keri Glassman&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s forthcoming new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New functionality over on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://trainheroic.com/&#34;&gt;Train Heroic&lt;/a&gt; site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style and navigation improvements for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.proteinpow.com/&#34;&gt;Protein Pow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site tweaks and a couple new features for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.romanfitnesssystems.com/&#34;&gt;Roman&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A quick fix for &lt;a href=&#34;http://negharfonooni.com/&#34;&gt;Neghar Fonooni&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:45PM:&lt;/strong&gt; I realize that I&amp;rsquo;m still working. Ali has food for us, so I eat with her and decide that the no-distractions part of my day is over. I still feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve got some productive hours left in the tank, though, so I put together two new logo concepts while we catch up on a couple TV shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:45PM:&lt;/strong&gt; I stop working and start writing this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-few-key-metrics:66dccf2bda6baf27f2868184e0c5b386&#34;&gt;A Few Key Metrics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had two big concerns coming into this experiment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was worried my team and my clients would be stuck waiting on me for something, causing tension and delays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was worried the lack of interruption might result in a lackadaisical attitude on my part, resulting in &lt;em&gt;lower&lt;/em&gt; overall productivity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To measure the validity of my first concern, I figured the easiest way would be to see A) how much email I received during the day, and B) whether I had actually caused any bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current number of emails in my inbox: 173&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of emails that are unread (from today): 67&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of emails (estimated) that will require action on my part: ~40&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of bottlenecks I created: 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second concern definitely proved false, but just for fun, here are some stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of todos I started the day with: 52&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of todos I completed: 27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, just because I&amp;rsquo;m using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://timingapp.com/&#34;&gt;cool app&lt;/a&gt; that lets me track this crap, here&amp;rsquo;s where my time &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; went today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total time on the computer today: 12:05&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Chrome: 4:22 (with only 16 minutes total between Facebook and Twitter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photoshop: 3:08&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Illustrator: 2:43&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sublime Text: 0:46&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remainder of my time was split up between apps like Finder, Transmit, Font Book, and other utility apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-m-taking-away-from-this:66dccf2bda6baf27f2868184e0c5b386&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m Taking Away from This&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a few important things today that I think will benefit me quite a bit moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, I learned that &lt;strong&gt;the world doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop if I&amp;rsquo;m not around.&lt;/strong&gt; My team had no issues keeping the wheels turning on open projects, and not a single issue came up that wasn&amp;rsquo;t handled easily and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned that &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m well-suited for work-a-thons.&lt;/strong&gt; I put in about 12 hours today, and as I write this I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling drained, overworked, or unhappy about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel good about the way today went, and it shows the potential to give me a way to get the high-concentration work during the week instead of on the weekends when email dies down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, at least, &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to give the no-distractions day a shot once a week&lt;/strong&gt; and see how things go. If it goes well enough, I might even try a Tuesday-Thursday no-distractions schedule, with Monday-Wednesday-Friday dedicated to email, meetings, phone calls, and other lower-concentration tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If every no-distractions day goes as well as today for me, I might even — *GASP!* — get &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/losing-the-weekend/&#34;&gt;my weekends back&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>