<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Happiness on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/happiness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Happiness on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 04:34:12 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/happiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Do More with Less: Drop Dead Physical &amp; Psychological Weight</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/do-more-with-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 04:34:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/do-more-with-less/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re serious? I can just&amp;hellip;take whatever I want?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pile of stuff in the corner of my apartment was huge. A drill I&amp;rsquo;d only used once sat on top of a box full of cables I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize I still had. An empty TV stand was littered with basically-new kitchen utensils and three different wifi routers. A full set of throw pillows I found in a closet sat on top of a toolbox full of art supplies I hadn&amp;rsquo;t opened since I dropped out of college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My neighbor had responded to a message I sent out to the building announcing a giveaway. I&amp;rsquo;ve never met this woman before. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming we live in the same building, but I can&amp;rsquo;t recall having seen her before — but then again, I&amp;rsquo;m not usually one to notice people passing by unless they&amp;rsquo;re holding food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She picks out some kitchen utensils, a whiteboard, and a package of AA batteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re sure? Anything?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Absolutely,&amp;rdquo; I reassure her. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re doing me a favor by taking this. Honest.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She leaves with her armload of booty, looking over her shoulder at me as if I&amp;rsquo;m going to change my mind and tackle her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, Marisa arrives with her own pile of stuff. A few hours later our friends arrive at the going-away-slash-holiday party we&amp;rsquo;ve arranged so we can see everyone before we leave the country the following Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friends all have the same bewildered look my neighbor wore when we start shoving our possessions into their arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, Nicole from the cleaning service arrives to do the move-out clean. I tell her to take anything she wants, and I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to see that she wants pretty much everything. She borrows the hand truck from the building to take a few loads out to her car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take everything that&amp;rsquo;s left and load it into Marisa&amp;rsquo;s trunk. At the donation drop, a man opens the door for Marisa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What a lovely day it is! What a lovely day to be alive! And how are you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marisa loves this guy. He&amp;rsquo;s a bit disheveled and wild-looking, like James Brown&amp;rsquo;s mugshot, and has the best attitude I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wow! Look at all this great stuff! Miss, you have excellent taste in movies — see this one right here? I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; this one right here!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He runs a cheerful commentary the whole time he helps us unload the trunk. (&amp;ldquo;This is a fantastic coat! I may have to buy this coat! You think it&amp;rsquo;ll fit me?&amp;rdquo;) His attitude is contagious. (&amp;ldquo;My oh my this blanket is &lt;em&gt;lovely!&lt;/em&gt; If I had this blanket and a mugful of hot cocoa I&amp;rsquo;d be the happiest man on Earth.&amp;ldquo;) As we pull out of the lot, waving, Marisa and I are wearing wide grins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop is a used car dealer, who buys Marisa&amp;rsquo;s car. He surprises her by offering more than she had expected for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, lying on the floor of my now-empty apartment, staring at the entirety of my worldly possessions in two small bags against the wall, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the way I&amp;rsquo;d expected to feel. I thought giving away all my things — possessions I&amp;rsquo;d carefully curated over the last few years — would feel like losing a limb. There was the art I&amp;rsquo;d collected from local cafés that showed my aesthetic preferences. The couch I&amp;rsquo;d had custom-built that was wide enough for four people to sit on and deep enough for two people to spoon. The bar full of all my favorite spirits and the proper glasses to serve drinks that announced to the world I was a whiskey kind of guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d feel empty.&lt;/strong&gt; I thought the absence of my things — this stuff that turned my insides out — would leave me hollowed out, back at Square One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But I felt exactly the opposite.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked down on the sum total of everything I owned with an incredible feeling of lightness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tiny pile of clothes and electronics was all I had to worry about. The internal pressure I felt to make sure my actions matched up with the material presentation I&amp;rsquo;d constructed — &amp;ldquo;is my attitude right now the attitude of a man who owns Herman Miller furniture?&amp;rdquo; — dissolved. My external pressure was gone; I only needed to make sure my actions matched up with the way I believed a man like me should act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/do-more-with-less.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;do more with less — emotional and material minimalism&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;minimalism-without-the-bullshit:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Minimalism, Without the Bullshit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try pretty hard to avoid labeling myself — I don&amp;rsquo;t want the actions of a group I don&amp;rsquo;t control to affect how people perceive me — so I don&amp;rsquo;t call myself a minimalist. But the core idea of the minimalist lifestyle does align with how I see the world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism is a lifestyle that helps people question what things add value to their lives. By clearing the clutter from life’s path, we can all make room for the most important aspects of life: health, relationships, passion, growth, and contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theminimalists.com/pitch/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Minimalists&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dropping-dead-weight:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Dropping Dead Weight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, &lt;strong&gt;every single thing we add to our lives, both physical and psychological, adds a tiny bit of extra weight that we have to carry around.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My operating view of the world is that my &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; self — the part that makes me a free-thinking, individual entity — is very small and virtually weightless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I experience the world, the things I do form memories, associations, and predictive models that help me navigate the world. These are the building blocks of my identity. I once threw up after eating cooked spinach from a can, and now I don&amp;rsquo;t like cooked spinach at all. I learned from my dad to always try to understand why things work, so I&amp;rsquo;m a shitty employee because I second-guess my bosses at every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These experiences make me into the person I am today, informing my personality and worldview, but each one adds a little weight to my identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To express my identity, I build a model of the kind of person I want to be seen as. I want to be seen as successful, so I only want to buy nice things. I want to be seen as discerning and stylish, so I only buy clothes and furniture with designs that have stood the test of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These possessions echo my experiences and reinforce them. If I thought I was a whiskey guy before I put a bunch of effort into finding a bottle of Black Maple Hill, I was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; a whiskey guy once I had that bottle in my bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The added weight of the material possessions and emotional biases on my decisions made it hard to be objective. &lt;strong&gt;Instead of asking, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s best in this situation?&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d find myself asking, &amp;ldquo;What would a guy like me do here?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cutting-the-crap:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Cutting the Crap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I pushed all of the possessions out of my life that weren&amp;rsquo;t essential for my daily life, it became easier for me to make objective decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, my plans to travel the world came with caveats: I&amp;rsquo;ll have to find a place to keep my Dordoni Worktop Table — I love that table — and my art collection will need a storage unit with climate control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could do what I wanted, but only after I&amp;rsquo;d made sure to take care of all my crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once those things were gone, I could weigh my options objectively and make quick, agile decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I want to go to Madrid? Well&amp;hellip;sure. Let&amp;rsquo;s do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No conditions or caveats — I can just pick up my two small bags and go with no guilt, no worries, and no hassles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;people-like-me:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;People Like Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I haven&amp;rsquo;t reduced my essential self back down to its weightless state. I&amp;rsquo;ve only changed my view of what &amp;ldquo;people like me&amp;rdquo; do; instead of thinking of myself as the kind of person who owns nice things and drinks good whiskey, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a new description for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of person who values experience over things and doesn&amp;rsquo;t worry about material possessions because they add stress instead of happiness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not enlightened, superior, or even better off; I&amp;rsquo;ve simply traded one guiding philosophy for another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this transition has allowed me to pursue the things I find meaningful. My old guiding philosophy was holding me back, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see it — the threat to my view of &amp;ldquo;people like me&amp;rdquo; was blocking me from seeing that I could be happier by trying a different outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-people-like-you-holding-you-back:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Are People Like You Holding You Back?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separating ourselves from our experiences is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; — there&amp;rsquo;s no denying it. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason people dedicate their whole lives to meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we don&amp;rsquo;t need to reach enlightenment to try and spot our own biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the easiest ways to catch ourselves being owned by our emotional and physical crap is to ask what we&amp;rsquo;d advise our friends to do if they were facing the same decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a friend came to you and asked, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve got this opportunity to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;travel the world&lt;/a&gt; while still making a living, but I&amp;rsquo;d have to sell all of my stuff in order to do it — what should I do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve known your friend has wanted to travel as long as you&amp;rsquo;ve been friends. What would you tell your friend to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re facing the same opportunity to travel right now. What would you tell yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your answers are different, you&amp;rsquo;re probably letting your physical and psychological dead weight get in the way of making objective decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard. You have to be really honest with yourself. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to face some uncomfortable personal demons. But think of everything you stand to gain by freeing yourself from the useless burdens you carry around — both in the closets you haven&amp;rsquo;t opened since you jammed your box full of &amp;ldquo;just in case&amp;rdquo; shit inside, and in the biased corners of your mind that hinder your ability to act objectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Work: Are We Just Working for Work&#39;s Sake?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/work-to-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 04:10:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/work-to-live/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to remember that we don&amp;rsquo;t live to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultural pressure is high to have a good job, and to work hard in that job to get a better job. To make more money so we can buy more stuff. To work the hardest and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/&#34;&gt;sacrifice&lt;/a&gt; the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stigmatize leisure as the mark of someone who won&amp;rsquo;t get far in life. We furrow our brows disapprovingly at the high school graduate who wants to take a year or two off before deciding what to study in college (or whether they should go at all). We look down on the smart kid who works a part-time job because he&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;not living up to his potential.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does all that really mean? Do leisure time, taking a break to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/growing-up-vs-growing-older/&#34;&gt;find yourself&lt;/a&gt;, and working just hard enough to get by really signify a problem? Or are we uncomfortable with the idea of valuing something else over work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can feel a lot like the latter in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t live to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We work to live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/dont-live-to-work-work-to-live.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;we don&amp;#39;t live to work; we work to live&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  What are you working for?

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-work-to-have-freedom:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;We Work to Have Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was eleven, I wanted a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nintendo_64&#34;&gt;Nintendo 64&lt;/a&gt; in the worst way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at $200, my chances were slim. I got a weekly allowance of $10, so by my estimation it would be a thousand years before I&amp;rsquo;d saved up enough to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to beg my parents and promise that they&amp;rsquo;d never have to buy me anything ever again&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in order to get one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 14 I got my first job washing dishes at a local restaurant. My first paycheck blew me away: I&amp;rsquo;d made over $160&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in just two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the next gaming console rolled out, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to beg anyone for it — I could buy it with my own money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The freedom that I felt when I made my first big purchase with money I&amp;rsquo;d earned at my job was intoxicating.&lt;/strong&gt; I knew I never wanted to be stuck begging for the things I wanted again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-shouldn-t-rob-us-of-freedom:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;Work Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Rob Us of Freedom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work to remove the limitations that exist when we can&amp;rsquo;t afford to do the things we want and need. &lt;strong&gt;Income gives us the ability to choose what&amp;rsquo;s best for ourselves, rather than being beholden to someone in a position of power over us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult/&#34;&gt;let work become the dominant force&lt;/a&gt; in our lives, we start to give away that same freedom we&amp;rsquo;ve worked to gain. Only this time it&amp;rsquo;s not a shortage of income that shackles us, but a shortage of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we&amp;rsquo;re trading our freedom for higher wages, or for career advancement, or for anything at all, really, we&amp;rsquo;re actively undermining one of the core principles of work: &lt;strong&gt;we work so we have the freedom to choose.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-work-to-have-purpose:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;We Work to Have Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently visited the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elephantnaturepark.org/&#34;&gt;Elephant Nature Park&lt;/a&gt;, run by Lek Chailert, a tiny woman from a rural part of Thailand with deep reverence for elephants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an adult, she works hard to rescue abused, disabled, and unwanted domesticated elephants and raise awareness about the rapidly disappearing elephant population and mistreatment of elephants as livestock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s found purpose in her work — or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s better to say she found work in her purpose. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that she finds her work incredibly important and fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even if our work isn&amp;rsquo;t our main purpose, it provides a means to pursue that purpose.&lt;/strong&gt; To quote the words of modern-day philosopher Jay-Z:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t help the poor if I&amp;rsquo;m one of them So I got rich and gave back, to me that&amp;rsquo;s the win/win&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jay-Z, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genius.com/9545/Jay-z-moment-of-clarity/Since-i-know-what-im-up-against-we-as-rappers-must-decide-whats-most-important-and-i-cant-help-the-poor-if-im-one-of-them-so-i-got-rich-and-gave-back-to-me-thats-the-win-win&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moment of Clarity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-shouldn-t-rob-us-of-purpose:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;Work Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Rob Us of Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By working, we create the opportunity for ourselves to apply time, money, and effort on the things that we think are most important in life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we let work spill over into our personal lives, the means to pursue our passions begins to diminish. We don&amp;rsquo;t have the energy to go after the things that we used to consider most important — we&amp;rsquo;re too exhausted from working, too preoccupied with meaningless metrics, or too worried about moving up the corporate ladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we let our work displace our purpose, we start to lose steam, and the results can be disastrous: midlife crises, depression, a sense of purposelessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-is-a-tool-not-a-burden:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;Work Is a Tool, Not a Burden&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work because we want to live better lives, and to do that we need to have a way to make an income. For most of us, that means a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is a tool that gives us access to meet our needs and fulfill our various wants. And when it&amp;rsquo;s treated like a tool, we&amp;rsquo;re able to control our efforts in a way that creates a better life for ourselves and our loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if we lose sight of what&amp;rsquo;s important to us, work can become the sole focus in our lives — it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a tool, it&amp;rsquo;s a burden that prevents us from doing what we want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to remember that we weren&amp;rsquo;t put on this planet to punch a clock and die on a pile of money; &lt;strong&gt;we were put here to live.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So repeat after me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t live to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We work to live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You never have to buy me anything, ever again!&amp;rdquo; was recently ranked #14 on the &lt;em&gt;Top 100 Phrases Children Don&amp;rsquo;t Fully Understand&lt;/em&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;Suck it, allowance!
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Have It All: Living for Now AND Later</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 01:01:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of guilt packed into our culture. We hear phrases like &amp;ldquo;hard work and sacrifice&amp;rdquo; tossed around to describe virtuous lifestyles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re trained to feel ashamed of having a good time.&lt;/strong&gt; We can only allowed to enjoy ourselves for an allotted number of vacation days — any further enjoyment is a sure sign that you don&amp;rsquo;t give a fuck about The Future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, would you like to come on this trip to Costa Rica with us?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, I can&amp;rsquo;t. I have The Future to consider, you know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what good is that sacrifice, really? &lt;strong&gt;Does the decision to suffer today for the sake of The Future actually result in a better future?&lt;/strong&gt; Or are we just depriving ourselves because we&amp;rsquo;ve been told it&amp;rsquo;s the right thing to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sacrifices-make-sense-sometimes:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Sacrifices Make Sense — Sometimes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly some sacrifice is a good thing. But how do we tell the difference between a sacrifice that will benefit us and a sacrifice that just makes us miserable for no reason?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ramen.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;ramen&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  #thestruggleisreal

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was building my business, I took a contract that barely covered my living expenses, quit my day job, and bought a pallet of ramen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the decision to sacrifice my short-term comfort for the potential to significantly improve my life in the long run. &lt;strong&gt;I felt comfortable making this sacrifice because there was a concrete goal, a timeline, and a measurable outcome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be self-employed (concrete goal). I had three months (timeline) on the contract to either make a livable wage (measurable outcome) — or decide I would be better off hunting for a new employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By making this sacrifice, I was able to make the jump from moonlighting as a web designer to working as a full-time freelancer — and this has paid me back many times over since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;base-decisions-on-tangible-criteria:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Base Decisions on Tangible Criteria&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should all be aware of what our later years will hold. But we &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; be blindly denying ourselves enjoyment today for the sake of The Future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid making unnecessary sacrifices for The Future — and to avoid making decisions that could negatively affect our &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; future — &lt;strong&gt;we need to define what The Future actually looks like.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a standard of living, an &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/calculator/retirement/retirement-need/&#34;&gt;exact dollar amount&lt;/a&gt;, or whatever you decide your future will require — it just needs to be concrete. Make sure it&amp;rsquo;s not, &amp;ldquo;I want to be able to live comfortably.&amp;rdquo; What does &amp;ldquo;comfortably&amp;rdquo; mean?&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you defined your future as requiring, say, $60,000/year for retirement, and you want to retire at 67, then you&amp;rsquo;d need to put a plan in place to save at least $1.5M between now and your 67th birthday.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By creating a plan, you now have a concrete goal with a timeline and a measurable outcome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-whatever-doesn-t-interfere-with-the-plan:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Do Whatever Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Interfere with the Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a real plan, anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect it is fair game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to go on a trip, see a concert, or blow off work for the afternoon to visit your friends? Do it, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s not to the detriment of your plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we have a clear plan, the guilt and uncertainty associated with The Future goes away. We can now test the things we want now against the things we want later — and I think we&amp;rsquo;ll all be shocked by how rarely the two are opposed to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/crippling-fear-of-uncertainty.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Sorry I couldn&amp;#39;t come with you, but I have my crippling fear of uncertainty to consider, you know.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This is what we&#39;re saying when we turn down the things we want &#34;for The Future&#34;.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keep-the-future-in-context:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Keep the Future in Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Without context, The Future is just a foggy, looming uncertainty.&lt;/strong&gt; It has nothing to do with our comfort or wealth in years to come — it&amp;rsquo;s just a nagging fear that we don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s next, so maybe we should hedge our bets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d be better off calling it The Crippling Fear of Uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, would you like to come on this trip to Costa Rica with us?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, I can&amp;rsquo;t. I have my Crippling Fear of Uncertainty to consider, you know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living the lives we want to live today is certainly a threat to The Future. But &lt;strong&gt;to a well-considered plan for the future, our happiness is no threat at all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have to ask ourselves: are we holding back because this sacrifice will have a measurable impact on our plans for the future? Or are we just scared of The Future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;For me, that might mean a house made out of hammocks where I&amp;rsquo;ll be fed various morsels of imported cheese by an extremely well-trained octopus. Your &amp;ldquo;comfortable&amp;rdquo; living situation may vary.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;This is an incredibly simplified approach to saving money for retirement, and it&amp;rsquo;s most likely wrong. Please do research and talk to a professional about your own retirement plans.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Know If You&#39;ve Joined a Cult</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 01:07:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You didn&amp;rsquo;t mean to end up here. You didn&amp;rsquo;t even see it coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with a chance to earn a living doing something you loved. Your dream job. Creating things instead of rotting in a cubicle. You weren&amp;rsquo;t just going to make a living — &lt;em&gt;you were going to leave your mark on the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, you loved the work; it was challenging and fast-paced. Everyone around you was crazy smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You brainstormed in your off time. Took projects home with you. Put in extra hours on weekends. It never felt like overworking because it never felt like work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You put in way more than 40 hours a week, but who was counting? This was &lt;em&gt;fun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But weeks passed into months and somehow you ended up here: Working 60 hours a week minimum, usually more. You greet your coworkers, bleary-eyed, half-joking about needing coffee to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work is still fun, but you don&amp;rsquo;t feel the same passion anymore. Whole days slip by sometimes and you have no idea what happened; you certainly don&amp;rsquo;t have much to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goals outside of work are on hold. You&amp;rsquo;d love to find out if the Belgians have anything to be cocky about waffle-wise, but you don&amp;rsquo;t have time for a big trip right now. You know you need to get into an exercise routine, but something always comes up and you skip the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Later,&amp;rdquo; you promise yourself, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to it soon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not exactly &lt;em&gt;un*happy, but something&amp;rsquo;s off. You can&amp;rsquo;t put your finger on it. You&amp;rsquo;ve just always felt that there would be &amp;hellip; *more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/a-clockwork-orange.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Cultural pressure to work long hours creates false obligation.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  You&#39;re being force-fed an &#34;ideal&#34; work ethic that&#39;s actually toxic for everyone involved.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1VqP36g&#34;&gt;A Clockwork Orange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-ve-been-absorbed:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve Been Absorbed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re no longer a free member of society. You&amp;rsquo;ve been lured into the &lt;strong&gt;Overkill Cult&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Overkill Cult is a cultural delusion that working 60+ hour weeks at the expense of everything else in our lives is not only a necessary part of success, but that doing so is somehow *honorable.&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The insidious thing about the Overkill Cult is that it masquerades as all the things we like most about ourselves: dedication, ambition, follow-through, responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It tells us to push harder, stay later, sleep when we&amp;rsquo;re dead. It tells us we&amp;rsquo;re never going to get ahead if we don&amp;rsquo;t show up first and go home last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleverly, wickedly, the Overkill Cult persuades us to hang ourselves with our own strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if we don&amp;rsquo;t break free, we&amp;rsquo;re all going to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-overkill-cult-will-kill-you-like-it-tried-to-kill-me:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;The Overkill Cult Will Kill You (Like It Tried to Kill Me)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance is the first thing to go once the Overkill Cult has us in its grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it started with my health. I skipped the gym — &lt;em&gt;too busy&lt;/em&gt;, I thought. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to cook — &lt;em&gt;too busy&lt;/em&gt; — so I ordered delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hobbies went next. Everything that wasn&amp;rsquo;t work fell away — &lt;em&gt;too busy, too busy&lt;/em&gt; — until I was on the computer constantly, working.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;strong&gt;In 2012, I was working 70–90 hours a week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I lost my social life. Friends knew I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t show up — &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t; too busy&lt;/em&gt; — so they stopped calling. Some days my only human interaction was ordering coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then — and this, sadly, is where I finally realized there was a problem — I lost my beard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-canary-in-the-coal-mine-or-how-i-killed-my-beard:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;The Canary in the Coal Mine, or How I Killed My Beard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2012, I landed the biggest project of my career at that point: a Black Friday sales site for a Fortune 100 company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thrilled and terrified. A project like this had the potential to move my company to the next level, and I decided to do whatever it took to make this project the best I&amp;rsquo;d ever built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The designers had great ideas, and I sat with them to make sure they were possible on our timeline. We came up with a slick, modern idea built on cutting-edge technology. The client loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then bureaucracy came into play. The legal department made changes. Brand adherence contradicted legal. Design went over schedule. &lt;em&gt;Way&lt;/em&gt; over schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time the design was approved, I had a third of the time we&amp;rsquo;d scheduled. And — since this was a Black Friday site — we couldn&amp;rsquo;t push back the release date. It either launched on time or I was a failure. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to be defeated, I powered through four straight days leading up to Black Friday, sleeping &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; six hours total. On Thanksgiving Day I skipped family get-togethers in favor of making the final push.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was exhausted. Delirious. But, goddammit, &lt;em&gt;I finished the project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client was thrilled. The site won a couple Addy Awards. I assume they made a metric fuckton in holiday sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few months, patches of my beard started to turn white. The whiskers became ultra-fine. Then they fell out altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/overwork-stress-unhealthy.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;effect of overwork on the body&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  May, 2013 — about six months after my Black Friday fiasco.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly afterward, I lost my ability to grow a beard entirely — I was left with the unsavory choice between a clean-shaven &amp;ldquo;giant fat baby&amp;rdquo; look and a creepy mustache.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had stressed myself out so badly that my body had forgotten how to grow a beard. And for what? So I could work 19-hour days and skip family holidays to meet crazy deadlines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was exhausted. My body was failing. I was overwhelmed and unhappy and isolated. &lt;em&gt;I had a mustache, for chrissakes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been guzzling the Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s Kool-Aid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something had to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-tell-if-you-re-in-a-cult:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;How to Tell If You&amp;rsquo;re in a Cult&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telltale signs we&amp;rsquo;ve fallen prey to the Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s influence are subtle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequently working more than 40 hours a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequently sleeping less than 6 hours a night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feeling guilty about any time away from work— even if that time is with family and friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t join overnight — this is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality&#34;&gt;death by a thousand cuts&lt;/a&gt; — and once we&amp;rsquo;ve joined, we&amp;rsquo;ll probably deny it.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;rsquo;ve joined. By the thousands, we&amp;rsquo;ve joined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lies-of-the-overkill-cult:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;The Lies of the Overkill Cult&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s siren song seems like a healthy sense of ambition. &amp;ldquo;We have to work hard to get ahead.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s something we&amp;rsquo;ve been told our entire lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re doing what we think is best for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Overkill Cult doesn&amp;rsquo;t plan for survivors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the symptoms of the Overkill Cult grow from good intentions, they&amp;rsquo;re short-sighted habits that ultimately do more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of the Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s telltale signs, and how each of them is a long-term detriment disguised as a healthy work ethic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-working-more-than-40-hours-a-week:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Frequently Working More than 40 Hours a Week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long hours often feel mandatory — it&amp;rsquo;s just part of the culture. We think, &amp;ldquo;My boss/coworkers/cat will judge me if I&amp;rsquo;m not working the same long hours as everyone else. I&amp;rsquo;ll never get ahead if I don&amp;rsquo;t go above and beyond.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just what it takes to make it, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrong.&lt;/strong&gt; Incredibly, terribly, &lt;em&gt;spectacularly&lt;/em&gt; wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research has proven over and over again that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to be productive for more than 40 hours a week.&lt;/strong&gt; At least not for sustained periods of time. Henry Ford introduced the 40-hour work week in 1914 because he saw — through research — that workers on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salon.com/2012/03/14/bring_back_the_40_hour_work_week/&#34;&gt;five eight-hour shifts kept up the highest sustained levels of productivity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite over 100 years of research supporting shorter work weeks, many companies still push for long hours, under the claims of a &amp;ldquo;sprint&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;crunch time&amp;rdquo; period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/overwork-hurts-productivity.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;overtime causes negative productivity after a short time&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This diagram is loosely based on one included in Sidney J. Chapman&#39;s *Hours of Labor*.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony comes in when we look at productivity over time. After just two months of 60-hour weeks, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enginesofmischief.com/makers/evan/pubs/crunch.html&#34;&gt;productivity goes &lt;em&gt;negative&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; compared to what a 40 hour week would have produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you catch that? &lt;strong&gt;By working 150% of the hours, you accomplish &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; in the long run.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-sleeping-less-than-6-hours-a-night:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Frequently Sleeping Less than 6 Hours a Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, sleeplessness has become a strange badge of honor. We swap &amp;ldquo;war stories&amp;rdquo; of sleeping two hours a night with an odd, martyred pride shining dimly in our bloodshot eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I never sleep because &lt;a href=&#34;http://genius.com/3012/Nas-ny-state-of-mind/I-never-sleep-cause-sleep-is-the-cousin-of-death&#34;&gt;sleep is the cousin of death&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; we murmur drowsily. So many projects, so little time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this belief that burning the midnight oil somehow gets us ahead is utterly, tragically wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1739867/pdf/v057p00649.pdf&#34;&gt;cognitive equivalent of a drunk driver&lt;/a&gt; after being awake about 18 hours. But the problem compounds: if you don&amp;rsquo;t get enough sleep, that level of impairment comes faster the next day. After a few days of too little sleep, you&amp;rsquo;re a drunken zombie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go to work drunk, so why the hell do we go to work on four hours&amp;rsquo; sleep, when we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; impaired than if we were hammered?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, sleeping less than six hours a night &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/8660373.stm&#34;&gt;may lead to an early death&lt;/a&gt;. The Overkill Cult is &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; killing you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;feeling-guilty-about-any-time-away-from-work-even-time-with-family-and-friends:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Feeling Guilty About Any Time Away from Work — Even Time with Family and Friends &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we&amp;rsquo;re in the clutches of the Overkill Cult, we feel a stab of guilt when we&amp;rsquo;re not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d love to go to this holiday party, but I really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t; this project won&amp;rsquo;t finish itself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fear that any time not spent working is wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony is — yet again — science tells us &lt;em&gt;exactly the opposite&lt;/em&gt; is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overworking leads to higher stress levels and burnout, which have been linked to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.3200/BMED.31.1.18-32#.VP2vuYGsWlI&#34;&gt;increased health risks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, time away from work is proven to &lt;a href=&#34;http://depts.washington.edu/hhwb/Thm_Mental.html&#34;&gt;relieve stress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2014-14435-001/&#34;&gt;boost creativity&lt;/a&gt;, among numerous other benefits.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, if we accept that the ideal is to sleep 8 hours a night and work 8 hours a day, that leaves us with 8 hours&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for non-work activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking time away from work gives us time to recharge. It puts distance between us and our projects, giving us time to remember why we like doing what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-our-escape:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Making Our Escape&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we may have been duped into joining the Overkill Cult, it&amp;rsquo;s not too late to escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been conned using our own best qualities to develop habits that — even though it &lt;em&gt;seems&lt;/em&gt; like they&amp;rsquo;d make us better — make us worse at our jobs, less satisfied with our work, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; less happy in our day-to-day lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leveraging the same strengths the Overkill Cult exploits, we can break free of its clutches and take back our happiness and passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my beard died, I felt the full weight of burnout. &lt;em&gt;I was burnt to a fucking crisp.&lt;/em&gt; I realized I could either leave my career altogether, or make some fundamental changes to my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, here are the promises I made to myself that helped me break away from the Overkill Cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-work-as-much-as-i-can-but-not-more:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;I Work as Much as I Can — But Not More&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before anything else, I had to accept that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s only possible to do 6–8 hours of quality work each day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to work longer hours will not make me more productive. In fact, working longer hours actually results in me getting less done as time drags on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose the latter, and implemented some radical (to me) &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-experiment/&#34;&gt;strategies for controlling my time&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;I cut from an average of 70–90 hours a week in 2013 to an average 38 hours per week over the last year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected to see less professional success in favor of better overall balance in my life — a sacrifice I was willing to make — instead I saw &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; productivity at work: my turn-around times went down&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and I was more consistently hitting my deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was floored at the time, but in retrospect I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-make-sleep-a-top-priority:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;I Make Sleep a Top Priority&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting enough sleep is beneficial on every level. Yet it&amp;rsquo;s always the first thing I would sacrifice when life got busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too little sleep wreaks havoc on my ability to think clearly, and that hurts me at work in a big, bad way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I cut my hours down, I started sleeping without an alarm.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Since I&amp;rsquo;m not working crazy hours, I close my computer by six or seven in the evening, and by eleven I&amp;rsquo;m usually in bed, where I read for a bit before falling asleep. I wake up naturally between seven and eight-thirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has changed my life. No bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waking up to an alarm before I&amp;rsquo;m fully rested starts the day in a groggy, stressful way. Waking up naturally after getting as much sleep as my body needs leaves me much happier to be awake, and far more ready to start my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-dedicate-a-reasonable-amount-of-time-to-not-working:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;I Dedicate a Reasonable Amount of Time to NOT Working&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was — and still is — the biggest challenge I faced in breaking away from the Overkill Cult. I love what I do, and I want to get my projects finished. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to rationalize working more hours and skipping activities that keep me from working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I know that taking breaks makes me more productive: time away from work lets my passion and excitement for the work renew itself; taking my mind off of a project allows my subconscious to roll around abstract ideas that result in better solutions; breaks from the job lower my stress levels and boost my creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I make sure to do it, even if my gut (incorrectly) tells me it&amp;rsquo;s a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take walks. I leave my phone in my pocket when I&amp;rsquo;m out with friends or eating my meals. I spend a fair amount of time on my hobbies, like writing and hunting for the world&amp;rsquo;s best cheeseburger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happier today than I can ever remember being in my life. I feel excited to work on my projects, to pursue my hobbies, and to spend time with people I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to be alive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leaving-the-overkill-cult-saved-my-life:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Leaving the Overkill Cult Saved My Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When my beard died in 2013, I feared it was only the first sign of an impending decline in my health that would ultimately kill me.&lt;/strong&gt; It was a glimpse into my future, and I was terrified that if I didn&amp;rsquo;t change, I was in for a life of isolation, ulcers, alopecia, and an eventual heart attack or stress-induced brain tumor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By changing my lifestyle, I was able to turn things around. After just a year of balancing my work with the rest of my life, my beard grew back. I lost 30 pounds because I was actually going outside and making it to the gym. I felt more awake, and I &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jlengstorf/stop-glossing-over-the-good-stuff-b89e25f7c714&#34;&gt;became more positive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I left the Overkill Cult, &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; in my life improved. Not one single thing got worse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-costa-rica.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf in front of a volcano in Costa Rica after fixing his work-life balance&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Doing a superhero pose in front of a volcano in Costa Rica. (Notice my beard.)

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://marisamorby.com&#34;&gt;Marisa Morby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-ready-to-make-your-escape:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Are You Ready to Make Your Escape?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been sucked into the Overkill Cult, know that you&amp;rsquo;re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be facing cultural pressure to keep this crazy pace. You may be struggling with your identity as &amp;ldquo;a hard worker&amp;rdquo; and feeling that scaling back somehow makes you lazy or useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I promise you — despite the doubts the Overkill Cult will force into your mind — there&amp;rsquo;s a better way. Better for your career. Better for your health. Better for your relationships. Better for your happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ended up in the Overkill Cult because you&amp;rsquo;re smart, ambitious, and dedicated. But you were misled by your good qualities and turned them into bad habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a better way, and you&amp;rsquo;re smart enough to pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dump your Kool-Aid in the sink. Take back your freedom. Find the happiness and success you were looking for when you started this career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Close your computer. Go outside. And call your friends; they miss you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;Hardly any of these hours were productive. Often I&amp;rsquo;d refresh my email, or stare at a code editor in a daze before realizing I&amp;rsquo;d been sitting there with my mouth open for half an hour.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll look like Magnum,&amp;rdquo; I tried to tell myself. But I knew — even then, I knew — it was all a horrible, creepy lie.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re currently rationalizing how you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in the Overkill Cult even though you meet all the criteria, you&amp;rsquo;re definitely a member.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;These studies focus on walking a few minutes a day. Not even an actual hobby or dedicated non-work activity. The negative effects of &amp;ldquo;all work and no play&amp;rdquo; are staggering, if you think about it.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;Or, if you want to exclude meals and such, &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; four hours. That&amp;rsquo;s enough time to go to the gym &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; pick up a hobby. Or even, you know, hang out with other humans or something.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;I also made other changes that helped with turn-around times, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/effective-project-planning/&#34;&gt;planning more effectively&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;Waking up without an alarm is, by far, my favorite thing about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;digital nomad lifestyle&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful to lead.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ll Be Happy When...</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/finding-happiness</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/finding-happiness</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy once I solve this problem.&amp;rdquo; But with the solution comes new problems. Can we ever be happy? Or do we only pursue happiness and never feel it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-get-this-toy:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;I Get This Toy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1989 I was obsessed with the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dressed up as a Ninja Turtle for something like four straight Halloweens, watched a VHS tape with a few cartoon episodes until I literally wore it out, and owned dozens of TMNT toys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/pizza-thrower.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles Pizza Thrower&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The epitome of combat effectiveness and practicality.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lQOo17fHTKE&#34;&gt;pizza thrower&lt;/a&gt; came out, &lt;em&gt;I had to have it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ninja-rap.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Vanilla Ice — Ninja Rap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Go ninja! Go ninja! Go!

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1O1Ldwi&#34;&gt;TMNT II: The Secret of the Ooze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I begged. I bargained.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:next-birthday&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:next-birthday&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I threw tantrums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on Christmas morning, 1989, I found a gift just the right size under the tree. The clouds parted, an other-worldly glow illuminated the box, and an angelic Foot Clan choir burst into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R_K6971WmAs&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ninja Rap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as I unwrapped the pizza thrower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had imagined this moment for months.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:reality&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:reality&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It was going to &lt;em&gt;change playtime forever&lt;/em&gt; — all of my friends would be &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; jealous. I would &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; get sick of this toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be so happy once I had this toy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within days — maybe even hours — I had lost all the pizzas. And besides, I could never hit my target anyways because the pizzas were stupid and probably broken or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lost interest before the batteries died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-get-some:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;I &amp;ldquo;Get Some&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1999 I was obsessed with getting a girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I — like every other kid my age — was the only one who was single, and I was &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; the only virgin left in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my room, listening to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2s3iGpDqQpQ&#34;&gt;Korn&lt;/a&gt; and writing poetry, I&amp;rsquo;d imagine how different life would be for me once I had a girlfriend. I&amp;rsquo;d be popular. Better-looking. I&amp;rsquo;d get invited to parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be so happy once I had a girlfriend.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In history class I sat next to Tammy West.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:fake-name&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:fake-name&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We were both weird kids, but in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tammy had grown up fast, and tried to dress and act the part — except she&amp;rsquo;d built her entire model of how a sexy, adult woman acted from &lt;em&gt;Sex and the City&lt;/em&gt; and various James Bond films.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She wore pleather bodysuits. Vinyl miniskirts. Knee-high boots. Crimson lipstick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wore heavy metal t-shirts, glow-in-the-dark sneakers with a hidden compartment for drugs in the soles, and black nail polish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of us stood a little outside the group, and our mutual lack of belonging helped us form a bond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tammy — despite her efforts to appear grown-up and sexy — was a virgin, just like me.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:clever&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:clever&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And — despite my attempts to end my sex life before it began with my fashion choices — Tammy had a crush on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We became an odd couple. My friends teased me. I imagine her friends teased her. But we didn&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks into our strange relationship, Tammy rented a hotel room&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:pervert&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:pervert&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and she took me upstairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t know about foreplay. We didn&amp;rsquo;t know about &amp;ldquo;being sexy&amp;rdquo;. We just awkwardly undressed in front of each other and climbed into the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the time it took me to say, &amp;ldquo;Oh my god, it&amp;rsquo;s in!&amp;ldquo; — it was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/its-in.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Oh my god, it&amp;#39;s in!&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    


    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1LLT6IK&#34;&gt;Superbad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a man now. I had a girlfriend. I was no longer a virgin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel any different. I certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t any cooler. My locker wasn&amp;rsquo;t flooded with notes inviting me to parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was just a weird kid who had a weird girlfriend. We didn&amp;rsquo;t last a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-free:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m Free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009 I was obsessed with independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had just ended a serious relationship, and I had a job at FedEx Office to keep the lights on while I pursued a full-time freelancing career in web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had imagined self-employment for years. No boss! No office! No pants!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be so happy once I worked for myself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of the year, I had landed one client. He agreed to pay me an amount that would &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; cover my rent and phone bill. The contract would last three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put in my notice at FedEx, bought a pallet of Top Ramen, and took the plunge into working for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/sriracha.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;sriracha&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My business grew, and soon I was able to buy a bottle of sriracha to add a little excitement to my ramen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I needed to pay taxes. And decide if I was going to be a sole-proprietor, and LLC, or an S-corporation. And figure out how billing works. And come up with an agreement to sign with new clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list grew so quickly that I went to bed most nights feeling that I&amp;rsquo;d made a huge mistake and that I needed to find a new job immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ever-i-m-moving-forward:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;Ever I&amp;rsquo;m Moving Forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, I&amp;rsquo;m obsessed with the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that I won&amp;rsquo;t find happiness in a goal: not a toy, not an act, not an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those goals are all milestones. Progress markers to let me know that I&amp;rsquo;m moving in the direction I want to move in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But they&amp;rsquo;re not the end of the journey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is a continuum, not an possession. I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that I was looking at happiness as a prize that I&amp;rsquo;d receive once I&amp;rsquo;d solved &amp;ldquo;the right problems&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;rsquo;t thought all that hard about it, but I was imagining a finish line, where I&amp;rsquo;d cross the threshold, be greeted by [insert current celebrity crush here] with a bouquet of flowers and a magic amulet that granted me happiness henceforth, and I&amp;rsquo;d just be&amp;hellip;done. With being alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I win, your princess is in this castle, game over, congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is the entire problem: &lt;strong&gt;I was looking at happiness as a destination.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, &amp;ldquo;Oh, I know I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy once I get to the top of this mountain. I just have to suffer through the climb and then all my problems will be solved!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, upon reaching the summit, I&amp;rsquo;d think, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s awful cold on this mountaintop. What a fool I&amp;rsquo;ve been! Clearly, the answer is to make my way to that valley — once I get there, all my problems will be solved!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, climbing the mountain was necessary, because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the valley until I reached the summit. But I was looking at it all wrong: I was looking at the mountain as the end of the journey instead of simply the next step in a journey that only ends when I die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was assigning all of the happiness to &lt;em&gt;completing&lt;/em&gt; the task, rather than finding joy in the process of learning, of working toward a goal, of improving bit by bit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowing myself to enjoy the fun part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m working toward a goal, I&amp;rsquo;m challenged. I&amp;rsquo;m out of my comfort zone and learning new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved the goal, all of those challenges are gone (momentarily) and I feel a sense of loss. Loss of purpose. Loss of a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not until I find the next milestone to work toward that I&amp;rsquo;m happy again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;changing-the-conversation:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;Changing the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I no longer say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy when&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy as long as&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;as long as there&amp;rsquo;s a new adventure ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;as long as there&amp;rsquo;s a challenge to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;as long as I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by people who are smarter than me in the areas where I want to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;as long as I am doing the things that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided are important to me (and not putting them off for the sake of obligations or laziness).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I want tomorrow. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;ll see from the top of the next mountain that I climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But I know that I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy as long as I&amp;rsquo;m climbing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:next-birthday&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, Mom, I promise! If you get me this you don&amp;rsquo;t have to get &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; for my next birthday! Honest,&amp;rdquo; he said, for the third straight year.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:next-birthday&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:reality&#34;&gt;In fairness, I was four years old, so it was probably only a few days.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:reality&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:fake-name&#34;&gt;Not her real name, for reasons that will become apparent.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:fake-name&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:clever&#34;&gt;I discovered this through masterfully surreptitious methods: &amp;ldquo;Are you a virgin?&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:clever&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:pervert&#34;&gt;Tammy was able to rent a hotel room at 16 because a middle-aged man ogling a teenage girl doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to look at her ID to learn exactly how big a pervert he is.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:pervert&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Something</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/create-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 17:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/create-something/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I feel restless or unhappy, it usually means I&amp;rsquo;m not creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always feel better when I&amp;rsquo;m creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/create-something.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;create something&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of what I create comes in the form of pixels and code for my clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I do a personal website project — like this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other times I&amp;rsquo;ll draw little characters on bar napkins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while I&amp;rsquo;ll pick up my guitar and strum, or I&amp;rsquo;ll meet up with an old friend and we&amp;rsquo;ll record &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/bearbak/trouble&#34;&gt;Taylor Swift covers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll work out a new cocktail recipe that I can make at home. Or make pizza from scratch. Or whatever. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I always feel better when I&amp;rsquo;m creating.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creation is the intersection of learning and doing.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s the application and proofing of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creation is a way of stating that — &lt;em&gt;hey, everyone!&lt;/em&gt; — there are things that I value, and that I&amp;rsquo;m willing to work for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creation is chasing ideas that inspire us, intrigue us, make us wonder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing I can imagine is to live without wonder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because when I wonder, I want to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I want to know, I learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I learn, I want to test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I test, I create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; feel better when I&amp;rsquo;m creating.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do What You Love</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/do-what-you-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 01:37:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/do-what-you-love/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/technology/2014/01/do_what_you_love_love_what_you_do_an_omnipresent_mantra_that_s_bad_for_work.single.html&#34;&gt;Slate.com ran an essay&lt;/a&gt; by Miya Tokumitsu that claims the advice, &amp;ldquo;Do what you love. Love what you do,&amp;rdquo; is devaluing &amp;ldquo;actual work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s total horseshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-do-what-you-love:c2fa42bd148e97e6412808480e6573f8&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Do What You Love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article leads off by making the case that Doing What You Love (DWYL) – trying to line up your profession with your passion – is a bad idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superficially, DWYL is an uplifting piece of advice, urging us to ponder what it is we most enjoy doing and then turn that activity into a wage-generating enterprise. But why should our pleasure be for profit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because &lt;em&gt;why not?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your pleasure doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be for profit. For a lot of folks, it won&amp;rsquo;t be; some of the things we love don&amp;rsquo;t line up with paying jobs. That&amp;rsquo;s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if it&amp;rsquo;s possible, &lt;em&gt;why the hell would you turn down the opportunity?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And furthermore, even if what you&amp;rsquo;re doing isn&amp;rsquo;t THE thing you love in life, what&amp;rsquo;s damaged or lost by finding joy in it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;only-certain-careers-attract-passionate-workers:c2fa42bd148e97e6412808480e6573f8&#34;&gt;Only Certain Careers Attract Passionate Workers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author goes on to issue a blanket statement about what kinds of work people could conceivably be passionate about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we believe that working as a Silicon Valley entrepreneur or a museum publicist or a think-tank acolyte is essential to being true to ourselves, what do we believe about the inner lives and hopes of those who clean hotel rooms and stock shelves at big-box stores? The answer is: nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This assertion is shockingly derisive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea that DWYL is limited to the &amp;ldquo;glamorous&amp;rdquo; professions is forced throughout this article. The author&amp;rsquo;s obvious distaste for &amp;ldquo;the elite&amp;rdquo; – not to mention the casual assertion that neither housekeeping nor retail can be emotionally rewarding careers – is misguided at best, and dangerous at worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing on a large soapbox and declaring that someone who makes a living cleaning hotel rooms is A) not being true to himself, and B) not valued by those who work in &amp;ldquo;elite&amp;rdquo; professions, is exactly the kind of polarizing, inflammatory crap that enforces the very class distinctions that this article is claiming to rail against.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:c2fa42bd148e97e6412808480e6573f8:external-valuation&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:c2fa42bd148e97e6412808480e6573f8:external-valuation&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pay to have my house cleaned every two weeks by a local company, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thegreencleanqueen.com&#34;&gt;The Green Clean Queen&lt;/a&gt;. Joanna, the owner, loves her work. She has a huge amount of knowledge about natural cleaning solutions, and shows a lot of passion for doing a good job and growing her business. That passion spills over to her employees, who also take a lot of pride in what they do, and – in all outward appearances – are very happy people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, according to Tokumitsu, these ladies couldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;possibly&lt;/em&gt; be doing what they love, because she doesn&amp;rsquo;t consider their work to be desirable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iladio is the groundskeeper in my building. He&amp;rsquo;s responsible for cleaning gum off the sidewalks, sweeping leaves out of the stairwells, and emptying trash cans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the author&amp;rsquo;s reckoning, Iladio is miserable, undervalued, and unrewarded by his work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, Iladio is one of the happiest guys I know. He&amp;rsquo;s a bright spot for many of the tenants in my building as they come and go during the day; even when he&amp;rsquo;s on his hands and knees scraping something sticky off the lobby tiles, he&amp;rsquo;s got a big smile on his face and wants to hear how your day has gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe Joanna and Iladio aren&amp;rsquo;t intensely passionate about what they do for a living, but you&amp;rsquo;d have a hard time convincing me that there&amp;rsquo;s no joy or pride in their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-have-to-be-privileged-to-do-what-you-love:c2fa42bd148e97e6412808480e6573f8&#34;&gt;You Have to Be Privileged to Do What You Love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tokumitsu goes on to complain that Doing What You Love is &lt;em&gt;just not possible&lt;/em&gt; for normal folk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be no surprise that unpaid interns abound in fields that are highly socially desirable, including fashion, media, and the arts. These industries have long been accustomed to masses of employees willing to work for social currency instead of actual wages, all in the name of love. Excluded from these opportunities, of course, is the overwhelming majority of the population: those who need to work for wages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The undertone here is that only &amp;ldquo;the elite&amp;rdquo; can afford to put in the hours as an unpaid intern to make it in &amp;ldquo;socially desirable&amp;rdquo; careers. And to be fair, I have zero experience in fashion and television, so the claim may be true in those cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the arts – at least if we&amp;rsquo;re talking about arts like web design – that claim is utter bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I started working as a full-time web developer, I worked as a night audit clerk in a hotel. As a cook at a local pizza chain. As a project coordinator at A FedEx Office. These were full-time jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My passion, though, was web design. I&amp;rsquo;d caught the bug. I knew I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you know what I did?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I fucking made it happen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would get off work and put in four or five moonlight hours on a project. I&amp;rsquo;d spend my days off experimenting with new front-end techniques and back-end programming patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put in my unpaid hours whenever I could. Because it was important to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see a path to do what you love, and that path is overgrown and littered with obstacles, you have two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can take Tokumitsu&amp;rsquo;s advice and resign yourself to the fact that work is work and you should just grind it out and live for the weekend until you die.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Or you can tear down that path with a bulldozer named Determination until get where you want to go.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-being-brainwashed-to-love-your-work:c2fa42bd148e97e6412808480e6573f8&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re Being Brainwashed to Love Your Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article wraps up by plainly stating that DWYL is an elaborate ruse designed by elite capitalists to sucker the Noble Worker into working longer hours for lower pay and lesser benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In masking the very exploitative mechanisms of labor that it fuels, DWYL is, in fact, the most perfect ideological tool of capitalism. If we acknowledged all of our work as work, we could set appropriate limits for it, demanding fair compensation and humane schedules that allow for family and leisure time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is tinfoil hat paranoid, not to mention &lt;em&gt;completely&lt;/em&gt; misguided. Encouraging people to distrust the enjoyment of their work because it benefits their company is just bonkers-level poisonous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of &lt;em&gt;course&lt;/em&gt; having employees who love what they do is beneficial to a company, and of &lt;em&gt;course&lt;/em&gt; bosses want their employees to love their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: &lt;strong&gt;if a boss is exploiting her employees, they&amp;rsquo;re not going to love their work.&lt;/strong&gt; The idea that using &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; as a way to drive class separation and abuse is fatally flawed. No one loves a job that bullies. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in toxic environments where the expectations are for long hours and little reward; the morale is abysmal, and resentment is high. I doubt many people who are &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; being exploited would describe any love for their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My employees love their jobs. But if I cross the line and ask more of them than they&amp;rsquo;re comfortable giving, my team&amp;rsquo;s happiness will suffer and they&amp;rsquo;ll start looking elsewhere for love and passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;elitists-are-out-to-ruin-your-life:c2fa42bd148e97e6412808480e6573f8&#34;&gt;Elitists Are Out to Ruin Your Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think – or at least I hope – that Tokumitsu&amp;rsquo;s aim was to raise a cautionary flag: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bosses, don&amp;rsquo;t take advantage of your employees&amp;rsquo; passion, because it&amp;rsquo;ll fade quickly if you do. Employees, don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself believe you love a job you don&amp;rsquo;t actually love.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those sentiments are good ones, and worth bearing in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this sensationalized idea of an elitist upper class seeking work they love, and encouraging everyone else to do the same, is somehow oppressive and belittling to the folks in the stock room at Best Buy is ridiculous, inflammatory, and just plain wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take pride in what you do. Make your work &lt;em&gt;part&lt;/em&gt; of your happy life – alongside your family, your leisure time, and your friends – instead of an unpleasant necessity that stands in the way of your happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you want something different than what you&amp;rsquo;re doing now, don&amp;rsquo;t ever let anything – especially not the shitty idea that loving your work is an elitist privilege – keep you from pushing toward your goals. Because &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/not-a-phony/&#34;&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re awesome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s all find the love in our work, because it certainly beats the shit out of the alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:c2fa42bd148e97e6412808480e6573f8:external-valuation&#34;&gt;If everyone tells the girl stocking shelves that her job isn&amp;rsquo;t glamorous, she&amp;rsquo;ll have a hard time shaking that external valuation of what she does for a living.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:c2fa42bd148e97e6412808480e6573f8:external-valuation&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me Against the World</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/me-against-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 23:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/me-against-the-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The idea of &amp;ldquo;me against the world&amp;rdquo; is strange. It implies that, for whatever reason, I pose a threat to The World and, therefore, must be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World will strike at me with weather and illness; with fairweather friends and canceled flights; with unrequited love and full seasons of &lt;em&gt;Entourage&lt;/em&gt; on demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World is out to get me. The World wants me to fail. The World is an unstoppable current against which I have to battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World is Dr. Doom, hellbent on ruining my happiness and success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/dog-against-the-world.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Dog Against the World&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The World is out to get this dog, too. Look how thoughtful he is.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s how it works. There&amp;rsquo;s no supervillain manifested in The World; there&amp;rsquo;s just the world: at best an indifferent observer, and more likely an inanimate object that doesn&amp;rsquo;t do too much of anything except &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; notice when I succeed, fail, live, or die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-is-not-against-me:545e32d7f89a68970f2c2d20a1ec1a67&#34;&gt;The World Is Not Against Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t even know I&amp;rsquo;m here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, this is terrifying. I&amp;rsquo;m a boat on the ocean, fighting wind and waves, and the storm would swallow me, my hopes, and dreams, all without a thought about me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How insignificant and small I must be, for the world to take no notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world doesn&amp;rsquo;t care if I fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-also-doesn-t-care-if-i-succeed:545e32d7f89a68970f2c2d20a1ec1a67&#34;&gt;The World Also Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Care If I Succeed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can die in my parents&amp;rsquo; basement as a jobless, dreamless nobody, or I can die as the best version of myself I can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world doesn&amp;rsquo;t care either way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the world won&amp;rsquo;t try to hold me back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the game of life, I&amp;rsquo;m playing without an opponent. I can succeed or fail, and the only person who really gives a shit is me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most hopeful, empowering phrase I can think of: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;no one but me cares about this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means I can do what makes me happy. I can put myself first. I can write, or create, try something I&amp;rsquo;m not good at, or change my ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also means I&amp;rsquo;m free to avoid anything hard, scary, uncomfortable, or unfamiliar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or I can charge headlong into this burning building and carry out my dreams before there&amp;rsquo;s nothing left to burn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-ll-go-as-far-as-i-m-willing-to-go:545e32d7f89a68970f2c2d20a1ec1a67&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll Go as Far as I&amp;rsquo;m Willing to Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only have two obstacles in life: willpower and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one will try to stop me from learning enough to gain understanding. So really, understanding is just another test of willpower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So will I dig in, trust myself, and push until I get what I want in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or will I give up, settle in, and tell myself The World is out to get me?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All Jazz</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/jazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:37:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/jazz/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have a mantra. It&amp;rsquo;s the metronome that keeps me from going into a tailspin when things go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s my reminder to keep perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all jazz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s simple. Almost silly. And it probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense unless you&amp;rsquo;re me.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-wait-jazz:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;So, Wait. Jazz?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you listen to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jazz_improvisation&#34;&gt;jazz improv&lt;/a&gt;, the musicians are all working within the general framework of the song, but they each take turns making shit up as they play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good jazz musician will play something he&amp;rsquo;s never played before — &lt;em&gt;something he&amp;rsquo;s literally making up on as he goes&lt;/em&gt; — with the kind of skill and ease that makes everyone watching feel as though it&amp;rsquo;s a standard that&amp;rsquo;s been thoroughly rehearsed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ta_UByyi4Z0?rel=0&amp;start=179&amp;end=278&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while it&amp;rsquo;s incredible to watch, this kind of improvisation also has huge implications outside of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans-and-how-they-never-work-out:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Plans, and How They Never Work Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I make a plan, it&amp;rsquo;s virtually guaranteed that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; will go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This used to drive me &lt;strong&gt;crazy.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d develop a vision of the way things ought to go, and when they failed to go &lt;em&gt;exactly right&lt;/em&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d be angry, disappointed, and resentful of the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-mad-bro:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;U Mad Bro?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It bothered me that I let myself get beat by a changed plan, so I started thinking about what it was that bothered me so much when a plan went off-track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, my plans went well. The outcome was really close to what I wanted. So what was the big deal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had set my expectations in such a way that only perfection would be considered a success.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anger, fear, and disappointment happen when our expectations are violated.﻿﻿&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This meant that even when things went my way, I&amp;rsquo;d still be upset because they &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t go exactly the way I&amp;rsquo;d imagined.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-improvisation:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;The Art of Improvisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing this, I had two choices: I could A) accept that I&amp;rsquo;d never be happy and resign myself to a life full of disappointing, mostly-successful plans, or B) figure out a better way to plan that allowed for some wiggle room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the two, the latter seemed more palatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jazz-musicians.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jazz musicians&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Making it up as they go.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://noblacktie.com.my/2011/04/28/photos-jazz-electronica-17-april-2011/&#34;&gt;No Black Tie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a large amount of trial and error, I finally came up with the jazz analogy, and built a new planning approach on two tenets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip the Details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expect Everything to Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;skip-the-details:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Skip the Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every plan is an effort to obtain a desirable outcome (e.g. &amp;ldquo;improve my client&amp;rsquo;s online marketing,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;have a nice dinner with my friends&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans, however, didn&amp;rsquo;t stop at the outcome; I&amp;rsquo;d work out which sides I would make to pair with the entrée, what games we&amp;rsquo;d play after dinner, and what cocktail I&amp;rsquo;d make to complement the meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inevitably, one or two details would change — no one would want to play a game, or I&amp;rsquo;d forget to grab an ingredient for the cocktails — and I&amp;rsquo;d be upset that it didn&amp;rsquo;t go according to plan, even though the dinner was a success overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By not worrying about the details, I&amp;rsquo;m free to focus on the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something will go wrong. So what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it does, I &lt;strong&gt;adjust within the framework of the plan and make something up.&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ll still get where we need to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forget about managing the details. Just focus on getting the desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;expect-everything-to-change:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Expect Everything to Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another case of framing, which I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/&#34;&gt;touched on before&lt;/a&gt;. If I enter a situation expecting only one outcome, I&amp;rsquo;m doomed to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I expect that things will change and trust myself to adjust accordingly, my expectations are very hard to violate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get sucked into believing that if anything goes wrong, all is lost. But in most cases, the only person who knows anything is amiss is the person who made the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where plans &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; get ruined is when the planner sinks into a funk and everyone else gets uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the musician misses a note, but powers through and just keeps playing, almost no one will notice. But if he stops mid-song to apologize about the mistake, it becomes a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-keep-playing:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Just Keep Playing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing I do ever turns out exactly the way I expect. But it usually goes pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I can do is keep playing, and, with enough practice, maybe everyone will believe that — for me at least — it&amp;rsquo;s all going according to plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;Or one of the people close enough to me that you&amp;rsquo;ve heard the lecture.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so much to be said about this — it really does explain almost every negative human interaction. Think about it next time you get mad: &amp;ldquo;What was I expecting here, and how does the reality differ from my expectations?&amp;rdquo; You&amp;rsquo;re in for a serious moment of zen, &lt;em&gt;mon frere&lt;/em&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>