<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Happiness on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/category/happiness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Happiness on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:22:56 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/category/happiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>No one is coming to save you. Are you going to save yourself?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/no-one-is-coming-to-save-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:22:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/no-one-is-coming-to-save-you/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At fourteen, I felt a lot of rage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, my anger wasn&amp;rsquo;t much more than the vinegar-and-baking-soda aftermath of my first waves of conscious individualism breaking against jagged, hormonal shores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-high-school-bad-attitude.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf in high school with a shitty attitude.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This is the face of struggle.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the time, my rage felt like my only defense against the countless injustices I was forced to endure&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the cruelty of a world out to keep me from feeling any real joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was angry because it felt like things were out of my control. I was debris swept away in a flood — a helpless, hapless bystander caught in a cosmic battle that had nothing at all to do with me: the victim of cruel happenstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world was happening &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; me, and I felt helpless.&lt;/strong&gt; So &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; I was pissed; helplessness has got to be in the Top 5 for Reasons People Get Angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovering-logical-thought:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Discovering Logical Thought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere around fifteen or sixteen, my great-aunt sent me a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1T2FuaG&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which started me down a philosophical rabbit-hole.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1eSrpPt&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1MMo4jH&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I read generation-defining pop-philosophy in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1IkeUXC&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fight Club&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and learned about the true nature of not giving a fuck in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1KQ4Dq0&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Factotum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and realized I&amp;rsquo;d never even come close to hitting bottom from &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1IGLrV4&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus&amp;rsquo; Son&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reading led to questions, which led to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2FTAT.com&#34;&gt;deep conversations with a friend&lt;/a&gt;, which led to critical&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; insights, and — finally — to actual changes in my behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, after a few minutes&amp;rsquo; logical thought, I realized two things that drastically changed my life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-no-one-is-out-to-get-me:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;1. No one is out to get me.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no dark force or diabolical villain working to make my life harder. It was hard to swallow, but I realized that &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just not that important.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, hardly anyone thinks about me &lt;em&gt;at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to imagine that I have critical importance and will therefore face critical opposition, but that&amp;rsquo;s an extraordinarily myopic view of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that — while I am the most important person in &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; world — I barely register in the broader scope of &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably 95% of the human beings I pass on the street receive zero attention. Of the 5% I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; notice, I only notice a single feature (&amp;ldquo;Cool shoes!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nice ass!&amp;rdquo;) and they&amp;rsquo;re forgotten the instant they leave my line of sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://38.media.tumblr.com/c958931381d9efa62f158d885f3ca811/tumblr_mirhy5eQPY1s6tut4o1_r1_500.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;House of Cards nobody cares&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1856010/&#34;&gt;House of Cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who am I to think I&amp;rsquo;m somehow deserving of everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention when I barely give them any thought at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To roughly 7,348,999,994 of the 7,349,000,000 people on the planet, I either don&amp;rsquo;t exist or don&amp;rsquo;t matter enough to occupy short-term memory.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a target. I&amp;rsquo;m not being singled out for cruelty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a victim.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-no-one-is-coming-to-save-me:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;2. No one is coming to save me.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my story has no villains, it&amp;rsquo;s safe to assume there aren&amp;rsquo;t any heroes, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As fate would have it, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fragile, extraterrestrial secret weapon&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/River_Tam&#34;&gt;severely damaged government experiment on the run&lt;/a&gt; — &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just a person.&lt;/strong&gt; My interests are all fairly commonplace, my talents are all borderline commodities, and my opinions are the mutant, amalgamated offspring of the opinions of authors and mentors I&amp;rsquo;ve paid attention to while I&amp;rsquo;ve been alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only unique thing about me is the &lt;em&gt;precise&lt;/em&gt; arrangement of my interests, talents, actions, and opinions. Otherwise, everything I am, do, and believe is more or less standard-issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s no need to save me; I&amp;rsquo;m not vital to the future of our planet. &lt;strong&gt;No one is going to &amp;ldquo;rescue me&amp;rdquo; from my life.&lt;/strong&gt; I won&amp;rsquo;t be &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lana_Turner&#34;&gt;discovered in a drug store&lt;/a&gt; and propelled to stardom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m on my own.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-empty-director-s-chair:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;The Empty Director&amp;rsquo;s Chair&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its face, this may sound bleak: I&amp;rsquo;m all alone and no one cares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is actually &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; news. It was probably the best news I&amp;rsquo;d ever received as a teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent most of my youth terrified of looking foolish. And when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t worried about looking foolish, I was convinced that I would get in trouble if I made the wrong decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I realized no one gave a shit about me, life became immeasurably easier.&lt;/strong&gt; I could strip down to one of those novelty thongs where my penis becomes an elephant trunk and sprint through a town hall meeting belting out the latest Taylor Swift single at the top of my lungs and &lt;em&gt;no one would care.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/elephant-g-string.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Elephant G-string&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Baby, I&#39;m just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake...

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teddygirl.com/elephant-gstring.html&#34;&gt;TGL, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, people would laugh, and someone would definitely put it on YouTube, but no one would &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; care. I&amp;rsquo;d be a momentary amusement, and then I&amp;rsquo;d fade right back into the anonymous social landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made it far easier to do things that were less ridiculous, like taking a chance on making it as a touring musician, or quitting my full-time job to give freelancing a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My whole life, I&amp;rsquo;d believed that &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/project-grownup/the-real-life-truman-show-1cd6b2aa9c34&#34;&gt;people were watching me&lt;/a&gt;, and that some unseen hand was shoving me along a path I had no control over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was wrong: &lt;strong&gt;there was no one making decisions about my life.&lt;/strong&gt; Except me, I guess — assuming I worked up the guts to make any decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my life was a movie, up until this point there&amp;rsquo;d been no director. I&amp;rsquo;d been carried along by the unstoppable current of time, but uncaptained, rudderless, drifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless I chose to act heroically, my movie had no hero. No villains unless I acted villainously. Unless I climbed in and took charge, the director&amp;rsquo;s chair was — and would remain — empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/whos-writing-your-story.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Who&amp;#39;s writing your story?&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-s-writing-your-story:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Who&amp;rsquo;s Writing Your Story?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I assumed responsibility for my own life, everything changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world didn&amp;rsquo;t happen &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; me anymore. &lt;em&gt;I happened to the world&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started steering myself away from the things that frustrated and depressed me, and toward things that excited and motivated me. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long road, and I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it today. I expect I&amp;rsquo;ll probably still be working on it when I die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started seeing immediate improvement: my life was now my choice, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a victim of anything. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t pleasant to admit that a relationship ended because I acted like a dick, or that a project failed because I let everyone down and slacked, but &lt;strong&gt;making my own mistakes was &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; better than feeling helpless against the whims of a malevolent universe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-in-my-own-way:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Getting in My Own Way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comfortably at the helm of my personal narrative, I immediately started closing doors and adding restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of man was I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the type of man who didn&amp;rsquo;t buy into bullshit corporate puppetry and advertising-driven entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the type of man who questioned all authority and made my own path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the type of man who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be lumped in with a group or clique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/south-park-non-conformists.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;South Park non-conformists&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://southpark.cc.com/clips/154322/non-conformist-coffee&#34;&gt;South Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, free thinker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, beacon of logical reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, renegade individualist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, prisoner of silly, self-imposed roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-are-you:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Who Are You?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I graduated high school, my parents took my whole family to Florida. It was half-intended as a graduation gift, and half-intended as a long-overdue family vacation. We went to Universal Studios and Disney World. Daytona Beach. Some enormous waterpark I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the name of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-high-school.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf high school photo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  &#34;As you&#39;ve probably already guessed by my hairstyle, I hate everything. Especially you.&#34;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And I — bound by my staunch opposition to corporate profiteering, herd mentality, and enjoying anything popular — made sure I was miserable the whole time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hot and muggy in the way Florida is usually hot and muggy, but I wore long sleeves and black pants the whole time. While my brother and sister carried their tubes to the top of a big-ass whirlpool-looking deathtrap, I sulked in the shade.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire premise of my family&amp;rsquo;s vacation violated my identity. It was an affront to the core of my being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, of course, that my parents&amp;rsquo; choice for a family vacation spot had exactly &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with my identity, and &lt;strong&gt;I was really just letting some dude in a Mickey Mouse costume ruin family time simply by standing nearby.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of power to give a stranger wearing a giant rubber head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-cages-we-build-for-ourselves:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;The Cages We Build for Ourselves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brick by brick, I&amp;rsquo;d built a wall between what was and was not acceptable for Someone Like Me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me listens to death metal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me would &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; shop at Walmart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me loves &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_the_Homicidal_Maniac&#34;&gt;Jhonen Vasquez&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me doesn&amp;rsquo;t love Jhonen Vasquez anymore because Hot Topic started carrying his comics.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was proud of the wall at first, because it created a clear separation between &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo; (me) and &amp;ldquo;them&amp;rdquo; (the sheeple).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building the wall was my tiny way of asserting a tiny bit of dominance over the tiny shadow I&amp;rsquo;d cast on the Earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/nate-green-jason-lengstorf_high-school-attitude.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Nate Green and Jason Lengstorf high school bad attitude&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt; and me showing the world just how cool we were.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: a wall is a wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, I was trapped by the imaginary Malevolent Universe that ensured my life happened &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now, I was trapped by the imaginary Someone Like Me who ensured only a tiny subset of all available choices were ever seriously considered.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-identity-snowball:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;The Identity Snowball&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was born, I was a tiny spark of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no memories. I knew nothing. All I cared about was whether I was hungry or sleepy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When something happened, I had no frame of reference. I could only observe, consider it as an isolated event, and make a decision about what that meant to me in that moment.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-childhood.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf childhood photo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  No agenda, no prejudices — just a sweet bear sweater.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no subtext or personal politics. &lt;strong&gt;Things were what they appeared to be. How could a thing be more than it is?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew, I learned language and fear and prejudice and opinion from my environment. Cat peed on me when I was four? Now I hate cats. Dog bit me? I&amp;rsquo;m scared of Dalmatians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends teased me about my Looney Tunes t-shirts, so that stuff was for babies. My mom knew the words to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2H5uWRjFsGc&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tubthumping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so it was clearly too mainstream for me to listen to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slow accumulation of experiential biases continued until &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d become so mired in my identity that I could no longer see an event as A Thing That Happened&lt;/strong&gt;; now it was inextricably linked to things I&amp;rsquo;d seen or heard before, opinions I&amp;rsquo;d adopted or developed, and my own historical stance on events of this type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My tiny spark of consciousness had grown into a hulking snowball of opinions and filters and fears and prejudices, and it was growing larger every day. There was no such thing as an isolated incident anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t asking myself what I should do in response to an event; I was asking myself what Someone Like Me would do in response to that event.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet again, I was out of the director&amp;rsquo;s chair and letting something else make my decisions for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-melt-the-snowball:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;How to Melt the Snowball&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 28, I was invited to try wake surfing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d always hated water: I nearly drowned on multiple occasions&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; when I was really young; I had a chip on my shoulder about being too cool for sports (especially water sports); but mostly I was chubby, pasty, and generally uncomfortable in anything but long sleeves and pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I made the decision to hate water before I can remember.&lt;/strong&gt; As a result, I&amp;rsquo;d spent nearly twenty years flatly refusing any activity involving water because — through the filter of my projected identity: Someone Like Me — water activities were stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my knee-jerk reaction was to refuse. Someone Like Me wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do it, so of course I won&amp;rsquo;t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then — at the insistence of my then-girlfriend — I started examining that refusal. Did I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; dislike water sports, or was it just something I&amp;rsquo;d told myself years ago and never since questioned? &lt;strong&gt;Was I cutting myself off from activities I might really enjoy because of something my idiot teenaged self had decided due to body issues and anti-conformity complexes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to test it: I&amp;rsquo;d go wake surfing, and if I hated it, my dislike for water sports was justified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I liked it, &lt;strong&gt;I needed to reevaluate my opinions about the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;taking-back-control-from-my-past-selves:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Taking Back Control from My Past Selves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wake surfing was a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;fb-video aligncenter&#34;
  data-href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/jlengstorf/videos/vb.107496345986942/519589568110949/&#34;
  data-width=&#34;730&#34;
  data-allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;
  data-autoplay=&#34;false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve since learned how to surf, snorkel, and kayak.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Each time, I was participating in water-based activities — the ones I&amp;rsquo;d always told myself I hated — and each time, I had a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many other decisions was I letting my pre-teen self make? My teenage self? My twenty-two-year-old post-rockstar-aspirational self?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been cheating myself out of dozens — if not &lt;em&gt;hundreds&lt;/em&gt; — of experiences because I&amp;rsquo;d let my unexamined emotional detritus hobble me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was I really in control of my life if a fifteen-year-old grudge against water was holding me back from things I truly enjoyed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-what-i-am:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;I Am What I Am&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the wake surfing incident, I&amp;rsquo;ve started running all my decisions through a do-I-really-feel-that-way-or-am-I-listening-to-my-idiot-teenaged-self-again filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/popeye-i-yam-what-i-yam.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Popeye I Yam What I Yam&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://popeye.com/&#34;&gt;Popeye the Sailor Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt I catch all of them. Good ideas still snag on my emotional barnacles more often than I&amp;rsquo;d prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m trying to keep my identity lean and adaptable. I&amp;rsquo;ve got new &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Popeye&#34;&gt;Popeye-esque mantra&lt;/a&gt;, even:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am who I am — not who I was — and I&amp;rsquo;m working to become who I want to be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, at least, I feel happier than I&amp;rsquo;ve ever felt — and significantly more in-control of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/marisa-morby-nate-green-jason-lengstorf-pot-luck-of-meaning.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Marisa Morby, Nate Green, Jason Lengstorf at a Precision Nutrition charity pot luck.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://marisamorby.com/&#34;&gt;Marisa&lt;/a&gt;, Nate, and me at a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.precisionnutrition.com/&#34;&gt;Precision Nutrition&lt;/a&gt; charity potluck. Big smiles brought to you by a low emotional bullshit quotient.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m free to become the hero of my story.&lt;/strong&gt; To take control of my part in its outcome. To try anything that might make me a better person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, I&amp;rsquo;m free to let my past experiences make me lighter — they&amp;rsquo;re there to show me what I &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; need to carry, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An abridged list of injustices endured by fourteen-year-old Jason Lengstorf:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mother who forced the removal of a tongue ring, despite the fact that it cost a week&amp;rsquo;s pay and several hours of subterfuge in order to get someone to do the piercing in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Girls who were mysteriously repelled by the black hair, zipper-and-safety-pin-laden clothing, death metal t-shirts, and generally shitty attitude of a &lt;em&gt;really nice guy&lt;/em&gt; (which they&amp;rsquo;d know, if they would stop being jerks and overlook all that so they could get to know him).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet commenters who couldn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp that the Insane Clown Posse is just &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt;, despite mountains of empirical evidence. Also, why were those idiot juggalos on the Eminem fan forum, anyways? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OvmvxAcT_Yc&#34;&gt;Fucking magnets&lt;/a&gt;, right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve read Ayn Rand. Yes, the books made me think and influenced me in certain ways. No, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to hang out, Glenn Beck.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;There were also non-critical insights: I realized that I was smarter than everyone else on the planet; I solved all the world&amp;rsquo;s problems (short version: &amp;ldquo;Everyone should just think and act &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; like me.&amp;ldquo;); I discovered rhetoric&amp;rsquo;s more sinister uses and brutally terrorized my less-eloquent teachers.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;The six people I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure think about me regularly: me, Marisa, Nate, my parents, and Nadia (whose job involves making sure I&amp;rsquo;m still alive and accomplishing things).
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leeloo Dallas &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119116/quotes?item=qt0464059&#34;&gt;mul-ti-pass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;No matter how I try to say this, it feels cheesy. I feel like some doofy motivational speaker trying to pump up an audience whenever I share this idea. But shifting that power dynamic changed everything in my life, so fuck it: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/kevinkruse/2012/11/28/zig-ziglar-10-quotes-that-can-change-your-life/&#34;&gt;call me Zig&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;I was probably doing something &lt;em&gt;totally unique&lt;/em&gt;, like writing emo lyrics or reading Chuck Palahniuk.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;When I got a JtHM tattoo at seventeen, I never imagined the sort of people who would — in their thirties — recognize and start a conversation with me because of said tattoo. I imagine it feels the same for people who got Disturbed tattoos.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Or maybe not. Maybe they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;stoked&lt;/em&gt; about the folks still down with the sickness twenty years later.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;My go-to responses were &amp;ldquo;crying&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;not crying&amp;rdquo;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;Turns out it&amp;rsquo;s bad news to be both A) recklessly inclined to jump into large bodies of water and B) the opposite of buoyant.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;I say &amp;ldquo;learned&amp;rdquo; loosely. I stood up on a surfboard a couple times, figured out that a snorkel is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a giant straw for drinking ocean water quickly, and dumped a kayak in the shallows while an older couple looked on and laughed.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Completely Alone at a Table of Friends</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/fomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 10:07:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/fomo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So these three statisticians go duck hunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;ve got the shotguns and the duck calls and the waders and the decoys, and they head out into a marsh and wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After a little while, they see some ducks, and the first statistician stands up to take a shot. He shoots — &lt;em&gt;BLAM&lt;/em&gt; — but the duck keeps flying; he&amp;rsquo;s missed high by about a foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The second statistician is ready, and he takes a second shot — &lt;em&gt;BLAM&lt;/em&gt; — but the duck&amp;rsquo;s still flying; the shot missed low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The third statistician jumps up and&amp;hellip; he, uhhh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking at my phone now. My friend&amp;rsquo;s mother just liked one of my photos on Facebook. How anticlimactic. She likes &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; photo I post, so it&amp;rsquo;s kind of like getting a participation trophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I look up, the table is staring at me expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; I ask.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phones-and-toddlers-are-dicks:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;Phones (and Toddlers) Are Dicks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/kids-are-assholes.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Kid being an asshole&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  &#34;Oh, you still needed this? ...yeah, I&#39;m not sorry.&#34;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/gallery/sO1Ok&#34;&gt;chaselye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends are getting to the age where some of them are married and have kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the kids are old enough to talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they do. Frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND:&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at remodeling the basement, but we think we&amp;rsquo;re going to—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY VOICE:&lt;/strong&gt; MOM MOM MOM THERE&amp;rsquo;S A DOG MOM DID YOU MOM DID YOU SEE THE DOG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND:&lt;/strong&gt; Just a minute, honey. We&amp;rsquo;re going to hold off until next—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY VOICE:&lt;/strong&gt; I WANT TO PET THE DOG MOM MOM CAN I PET THE DOG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND:&lt;/strong&gt; Sweetie, I need you to be quiet for a minute. We&amp;rsquo;re holding off until next Spring so we don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with the—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY VOICE:&lt;/strong&gt; MOM MOM CAN I HAVE MY JUICE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[FRIEND digs in cooler for a juicebox. 30 minutes pass. Interruptions continue. TINY VOICE becomes so insistent that FRIEND exits the table briefly. It becomes clear, finally, that FRIEND wants to remodel the basement, but will wait until Spring to avoid extra heating costs since they&amp;rsquo;re planning to replace the insulation. No further discussion is possible because TINY VOICE needs to be put down for a nap. FRIEND goes home.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barbecues aren&amp;rsquo;t that much fun anymore, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these days, neither is the bar. Or dinner. Or other kid-free events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jokes and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/funny-stuff/the-fine-art-of-bullshit-c09f7bbb391e&#34;&gt;silly arguments&lt;/a&gt; and general banter is all different now. Staccato bursts of conversation are all interrupted by flashing lights and three-second bursts of muzak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Two-thirds of a thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY ROBOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND 2:&lt;/strong&gt; New thought started in awkward silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Interruption to finish original thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY ROBOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see a group of friends in a bar isn&amp;rsquo;t much like watching humans who care about each other interact. It&amp;rsquo;s like watching four people sit alone at a communal table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alone-at-a-table-full-of-friends:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;Alone at a Table Full of Friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ignoring-friends-on-phones.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Ignoring friends at dinner on cell phones.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Dinner was great; I finally caught up on my Twitter feed!

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://grooverpr.wordpress.com/2014/03/29/topic-of-the-week-cell-phones-conversations/&#34;&gt;grooverpr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a true story: I was in Chiang Mai a few months back, and Marisa and I made a game of timing how long it took for various tables of 3+ college students to actually speak to each other. The game was boring; they almost never spoke to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one table — two guys and two girls — who never spoke at all. One of the girls didn&amp;rsquo;t even look at her friends; she spent the whole meal taking selfies at severe downward angles. The other girl photojournaled the entire meal and presumably starved to death because she never got around to eating anything. The guys buried their heads in an iPad game and Snapchat.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-let-em-get-the-hooks-in:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;We Let &amp;lsquo;Em Get the Hooks In&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change was slow for most of us. Almost imperceptible. Sometime in 2009 we became abruptly aware of a dozen unread notifications in our pockets and our stomachs went through the taffy puller because &lt;em&gt;things were happening&lt;/em&gt; and we were missing them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way someone&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; came up with the term FoMO and it started getting tossed around as a psychological disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And — like magic — being a total dick to your friends became a psychological disorder, in the same way that bringing a rooster&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; onto a plane somehow became medically valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;This is things that have gone to far: A rooster on a plane, in a pink tutu, as an &amp;ldquo;emotional support&amp;rdquo; animal. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/PLpuf4EH5Z&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/PLpuf4EH5Z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sue Strachan (@SueStrachan504) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SueStrachan504/status/511540289769844737&#34;&gt;September 15, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-want-to-be-everywhere:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;We Want to Be Everywhere&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren&amp;rsquo;t more things happening in the world now than there were thirty years ago. We&amp;rsquo;re just able to see more of it happening in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a practical demonstration of &amp;ldquo;ignorance is bliss&amp;rdquo;, our parents and grandparents never tasted the bitter anguish of realizing that nerds from the U.S. just &lt;a href=&#34;http://twistedsifter.com/videos/usa-challenges-japan-to-giant-robot-duel/&#34;&gt;challenged Japan to a mech-suit battle&lt;/a&gt; last week &lt;em&gt;and you didn&amp;rsquo;t hear about it until today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we unfortunate residents of The Future™ weren&amp;rsquo;t so lucky. Fate, with a mirthless grin and malevolently glittering eyes, thrust us into a world where Periscope and Facebook and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theonion.com/article/media-landscape-redefined-by-24-second-news-cycle-2213&#34;&gt;24-second news cycle&lt;/a&gt; exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our only weapon in this struggle against cultural irrelevance is a constant IV-drip of information, fed through our eyeballs and fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armed with the latest smart_______, we doggedly pursue Total Awareness. Legends are told of an elite few who know all things &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; they start trending on Facebook. These multi-screen samurai pursue 100% coverage of global occurrences with Neeson-esque determination.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-where-are-we-exactly:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;So Where Are We, Exactly?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the corners of our vision, just beyond the edge of what we can identify without turning our heads, another world is dimly lit with blue light, collecting dust and falling into disrepair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that world doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter now. We &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that world; it&amp;rsquo;s the other things that we need to keep tabs on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; our friends, and their stories.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We already &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; all our family&amp;rsquo;s dirty secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s exciting about the things we already know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing. &lt;em&gt;Nothing&lt;/em&gt; is exciting about the things we know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; exciting? Kid Rock acting like an ignorant hillbilly. &lt;em&gt;What drama and intrigue!&lt;/em&gt; And you know what else? Donald Trump on an escalator. If that&amp;rsquo;s not a memory that will bring you some small comfort in the final hours of your life, you&amp;rsquo;re probably dead inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Grandma can just hold her damn horses if she wants to spend the day with us; we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with matters of critical import, here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/fomo.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;FoMO: Fear of Missing Out&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  #thestruggleisreal

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-things-that-matter:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;The Things That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work endlessly — thanklessly — to keep drinking from the information firehose spraying from this pitiless world we live in. No one will sing songs of our dedication and perseverance. The history books won&amp;rsquo;t mention our names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;rsquo;ll know what we&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our old age, we want to look fondly back on a lifetime of accomplishment and contentment. Happy memories of happy days, where we did things that truly mattered to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom&amp;rsquo;s kinda-dry turkey dinner just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make that cut. Sorry, Mom, but there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;real struggle&lt;/em&gt; happening here. You&amp;rsquo;re just too old to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that we don&amp;rsquo;t love our friends and family — we do. Dearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just that we aren&amp;rsquo;t 100% sure there&amp;rsquo;s not something out there that we might love &lt;em&gt;more.&lt;/em&gt; So we have to keep our options open&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and stay diligent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise we&amp;rsquo;re just cheating ourselves, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may not be able to communicate our feelings without emoticons. We may not have spoken to our parents in weeks. Our friends may only know us as That Guy Who Plays on His Phone Through Lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we saw &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tvsV6nlLe1g&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; the day it came out. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VLEfrulUEcs&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, our sacrifice was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;The third statistician jumps up and starts fist-pumping and yelling, &amp;ldquo;Yeah! We got him, boys! We got him!&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;He was looking at snaps of beautiful women doing nothing: talking to the camera, pointing their cameras at what they were eating, waving and laughing. The two girls he was with were incredibly good-looking. They had food they could show him. They had (perhaps most importantly) agreed to hang out with him in person. I wanted to shake him: &amp;ldquo;Son, do you even understand what you&amp;rsquo;re doing wrong, here?&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bostonmagazine.com/news/article/2014/07/29/fomo-history/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boston Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, credit for FoMO (&amp;ldquo;Fear of Missing Out&amp;rdquo;) goes to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danherman.com/The-Fear-of-Missing-Out-(FOMO)-by-Dan-Herman.html&#34;&gt;Dan Herman&lt;/a&gt;, though it was really popularized by Patrick McGinnis in a 2004 op-ed on the subject. This will be on the quiz.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;Or pig, or mini-horse, or peacock. It&amp;rsquo;s so absurd that you have to wonder if it&amp;rsquo;s an attempt at satirizing rich white women with tiny dogs to help with their depression, or this subversion of cloying airline policy is being carried out by a subset of hipsters who decided mustaches weren&amp;rsquo;t ironic enough.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;Of course, no one can prove that the fabled Ultrainformed exist. They&amp;rsquo;ve never been spotted in the wild, and only surface for mere moments at a time under the guise of various throwaway Reddit accounts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The hopeful among Millennials (a.k.a. the Informationally Forsaken) speak of the Ultrainformed as possible saviors from our ignorance; the cynical write them off as the Illuminati; my grandpa says we should just close the fucking computer and go outside already.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;For the last time, Dave: we&amp;rsquo;ve all heard your goddamn Mariah-Carey-in-the-elevator story.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Nobody cares.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, yeah, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hang out, but I can&amp;rsquo;t actually commit to anything. There&amp;rsquo;s a possibility that something better than your shitty party will come up, and I want to keep my options open. I&amp;rsquo;ll show up if I show up.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Tourist Trap</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/navigating-the-tourist-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 08:00:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/navigating-the-tourist-trap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In my worst nightmare it goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m standing somewhere significant. Maybe historical, or cultural, or just &lt;em&gt;totally fucking majestic.&lt;/em&gt; The sort of place your well-traveled friends tell you no but seriously you &lt;em&gt;have to see it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of moment camera companies have trademarked. Before now the thing I&amp;rsquo;m looking at was only an &lt;em&gt;understanding&lt;/em&gt; of a place in my head, but now it&amp;rsquo;s becoming an experience; a memory: the image from Wikipedia grows a Z axis and I can touch it and there&amp;rsquo;s a smell and now I can give you directions to here complete with landmarks and everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I inhale deeply through my nose. &lt;em&gt;This is exactly the kind of shit that makes travel worth—&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reverie is shattered by a tiny old woman in a sleeveless floral blouse and a white visor who elbows past me to take a photo of the &amp;ldquo;Sortie / Exit, Toilettes / Washroom&amp;rdquo; sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A British tour group forces me forward, each of them labeled with a neon Post-It™ note signifying which bus brought them here. A middle-aged woman is digging in her purse in the middle of the path, preventing anyone from going around her, which has infuriated her husband up ahead to the point he&amp;rsquo;s now standing in the middle of the path with his hands cupped around his mouth screaming &lt;em&gt;get out of the damn path, Emily, no one can get around you&lt;/em&gt; as a queue builds on either side of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Japanese kid is switching out absurdly expensive optics on his DSLR and taking macro shots of a fencepost, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me except that I know his photos of nothing are better than any photo I will take in my lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind me, a meaty shoulder or belly or breast presses into the back of my arm, and in front of me a child who is far too young to have any hope of remembering this family outing is &lt;em&gt;melting the fuck down&lt;/em&gt; because he&amp;rsquo;s the only one of us sane enough to realize that being here, on this path, in this place, is the worst kind of hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gorgeous outdoor space starts to feel small, and the press of tourists is taking all of my oxygen. I suppress the urge to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5Iv9q9QI1g&#34;&gt;Barry Sanders&lt;/a&gt; my way to the nearest exit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/tourists-in-monets-garden.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Tourists at Monet&amp;#39;s Garden in Giverny, France.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Monet&#39;s water garden — home to the famous water lilies.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-and-self-loathing-in-claude-monet-s-garden:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;Fear and Self-Loathing in Claude Monet&amp;rsquo;s Garden&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday I lived my nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early afternoon, I climb out the back of a van and into an enormous parking lot&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:village&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:village&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to join a queue of art- and/or flower-enthused travelers who&amp;rsquo;ve made the trip to get a glimpse of Monet&amp;rsquo;s botanical muses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enter through a small gate at the southwestern corner of the property. Inside the gate, there&amp;rsquo;s a ticket booth and high hedges all around — no peeking, I guess. Marisa&amp;rsquo;s mom bought some package online that lets us skip the line and duck through the hedge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As weather for standing in a garden goes, this afternoon in Giverny is just about perfect. It&amp;rsquo;s about 20°C under a bright blue sky with what Bob Ross would certainly describe as &amp;ldquo;happy little clouds&amp;rdquo; hovering over the Seine in the western sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/blue-sky-over-the-seine-river.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Blue skies over Giverny, France.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The view from a hill just outside Giverny, France.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The garden is huge. Maybe a little bigger than a football field&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:pitch&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:pitch&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and crosshatched with paths that lead through intensely colorful landscaping that overflows with flowers I can&amp;rsquo;t identify&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:flowers&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:flowers&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in colors I didn&amp;rsquo;t know flowers could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden is a special place. And not just because it was the inspiration for a large number of his paintings — this is a place where it just feels good to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-the-locusts-descend:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;And the Locusts Descend&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, for all the beauty that the garden has to offer, there will be no peace or reflection here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By my estimation, roughly 30% of the global population is stuffed inside the walls of Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden, all jockeying for selfie-space along the garden paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dozens of old women&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:oldwomen&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:oldwomen&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from every corner of the globe totter along the path, asking each other how their cameras work and (loudly) discussing the scene:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aren&amp;rsquo;t these gorgeous?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The flowers!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The flowers?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What about the flowers?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aren&amp;rsquo;t they gorgeous?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s gorgeous?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teenage girls who&amp;rsquo;ve slipped away from their parents make doe-eyes and duck-faces for strangers on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young couple detains me and holds up foot traffic so I can take their picture in front of the main path. Four times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sayeth-the-locust:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;Sayeth the Locust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I fucking hate tourists,&lt;/em&gt; I think to myself as I crouch down in front of a flower that sort of looks like a popcorn ball to take a close-up with a shallow depth of field. Those tend to get more likes, I&amp;rsquo;ve found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/p/4AUts8zK9K/&#34; style=&#34; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;Claude Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;
A photo posted by Jason Lengstorf (@jlengstorf) on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2015-06-16T21:26:06+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 16, 2015 at 11:26pm CEST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smile apologetically at the people waiting behind me as I usher Marisa and Jil into position for a mother-daughter photo. Marisa keeps talking, so I have to try three or four times before she&amp;rsquo;s not pulling a goofy face in the photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a baby bird I think is a black swan starts jumping from lily pad to lily pad, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/video.php?v=839353302801239&#34;&gt;take a video&lt;/a&gt; and point it out to Jil and we discuss what type of bird it is. The ladies next to us start trying to take a video — &lt;em&gt;what button do I push again?&lt;/em&gt; — and point it out to each other and start calling it a baby duck, which I decide is wrong and hold against them as ignorant Americans.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:bird&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:bird&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marisa and I decide to skip Monet&amp;rsquo;s house&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:house&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:house&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and duck outside the walls to buy ice cream. We find a spot in the shade to sit down and I silently judge all the other fatties on tour buses eating ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-trouble-with-tourist-traps:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;The Trouble with Tourist Traps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cringe at the thought of waiting three hours to ride &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.londoneye.com/&#34;&gt;the London Eye&lt;/a&gt;. At &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sacre-coeur-montmartre.com/english/&#34;&gt;Sacre-Cœur&lt;/a&gt;, I came as close as I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been in adult life to starting a physical altercation with some overly-touchy peddler.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:touching&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:touching&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, I recoil from anything that would be called an &amp;ldquo;attraction&amp;rdquo; when I visit a new city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, these are the places that — once, long ago — had significance, but have now been roped off and sanitized and crammed full of souvenir shops to the point that, really, they&amp;rsquo;re not anything like what they were when they became significant.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:edinburgh&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:edinburgh&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything with any value to a city&amp;rsquo;s tourism board quickly becomes the Attraction &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ship_of_Theseus&#34;&gt;of Theseus&lt;/a&gt;: if an historically significant site, incrementally, has all its parts replaced by informational plaques and concession stands, is it still the same historically significant site?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/see-the-world-without-being-a-tourist.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;How can you see the world without being a tourist?&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-yet:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;And Yet&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the issues with tourist traps, there&amp;rsquo;s no denying that some of this stuff really does have historical significance. And really — significance aside — some of it is just &lt;em&gt;really fucking cool&lt;/em&gt; to see up close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Eiffel Tower is probably one of the top 5 most recognizable structures in the world. Almost everyone can sketch a rough approximation of what it looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, goddammit, standing on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Passerelle_Debilly&#34;&gt;Passerelle Debilly&lt;/a&gt; facing SSE at 23:00 is still breathtaking, no matter how many times I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the photos online before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for all the venom and vitriol I spit at tourist attractions, I&amp;rsquo;m still susceptible to the sense of wonder and awe that made these places attractions in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-a-better-mouse-trap:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;Building a Better Mouse Trap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, back in Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden, I started solving problems in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These paths should be made one-way to avoid this clusterfuck.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why are half the paths closed?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They should let us pay more for a ticket where only 25 people get to go in at a time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My claustrophobia and impatience grew in intensity, and my solutions became more extreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You should have to pass a basic camera competence exam to get into this place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everyone should be allowed three photos before moving further down the path.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end I was more or less a Marvel supervillain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Humanity has failed to make tourism work. To fix tourism, we must kill all tourists.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:exceptions&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:exceptions&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This is the only way.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/claude-monet-real-life-waterlilies.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Waterlilies in Claude Monet&amp;amp;#039;s garden, Giverny, France.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The waterlilies Claude Monet painted.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coming-to-terms-with-tourism:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;Coming to Terms with Tourism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m here, standing on a bridge over the world&amp;rsquo;s most famous waterlilies, fuming over the crowds and the chaos and the commercialization of history. I feel cheated because I can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; enjoy this experience with all these other jerks pushing their way past me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hypocrisy of it all sneaks up on me. I feel a little sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m one of them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came here to look at this place. To take iPhone photos and tell my Facebook friends I&amp;rsquo;m here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m probably less qualified than many of these people: they might be able to name a few Monet paintings — maybe they know more about this painter and his garden than his first name. Really I just came because Jil wanted to go and I wanted to make an effort and keep an open mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But really, at the core, I&amp;rsquo;m only one Tommy Bahama button-down removed from the guy next to me. We&amp;rsquo;re both foreigners. We both speak no French and have bad American habits and probably offend&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:offense&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:offense&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; nearly half the locals we meet. We wanted to see the best things the world has to offer, and this particular piece of the globe has been deemed noteworthy — so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-re-not-so-different-you-and-i:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re Not So Different, You and I&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My self-consciousness about being an outsider makes me quick to put some distance between myself and tourists. I don&amp;rsquo;t want French people to look at me and immediately peg me as an American&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:american&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:american&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and assume I&amp;rsquo;m just some tourist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; just some tourist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, sure, maybe the people in this garden with me will spend their vacations eating burgers because &lt;em&gt;coq au vin&lt;/em&gt; sounds too exotic, and maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll never leave Champs-Élysées unless it&amp;rsquo;s in the back of a tour van. Maybe they won&amp;rsquo;t even bother trying to speak French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of that makes me better than they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I sit next to an American couple and pretend not to speak English so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to talk to them, that&amp;rsquo;s not making me &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; worldly; it&amp;rsquo;s further isolating me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/make-money-like-claude-monet.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;I make Monet like Claude Money.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Get the Monet. Dolla dolla bills, y&#39;all.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-search-of-authenticity:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;In Search of Authenticity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to &amp;ldquo;live like a local&amp;rdquo; — it&amp;rsquo;s been this &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;location independence experiment&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;raison d&amp;rsquo;être&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:french&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:french&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from the start — but my eagerness to have an &amp;ldquo;authentic&amp;rdquo; experience built a wall between me and other travelers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to be seen as The Right Kind of Traveler™: when I meet someone from another country, I want to become the example they offer up as an exception to the rule during a discussion of how awful American tourists are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I let my desire to live as locally as someone can for a month become a default avoidance of anything that could be called &amp;ldquo;tourist activities&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on a huge percentage of the world&amp;rsquo;s beauty and history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because it&amp;rsquo;s popular doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s not worth doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;authentic-tourism:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;Authentic Tourism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden, Jil asks me, &amp;ldquo;Did you have a good time?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ride home is pulling into the parking lot, near the bench where we were all told to meet at 14:30. We hurry to polish off our ice cream cones and buy a bottled water for the drive. The older couple we rode up with looks exhausted — &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;can&amp;rsquo;t wait to get to Provence so we can finally slow down and relax,&amp;rdquo; the man is saying to his wife, who is flipping through the photos she&amp;rsquo;s taken today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/marisa-and-jil-in-monets-garden.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Marisa and Jil in Claude Monet&amp;amp;#039;s Garden, Giverny, France.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Marisa and Jil in Monet&#39;s Garden.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jil lives for this stuff: tomorrow she&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting outside a comfortable hotel in the shadow of the Eiffel Tower at 05:30 for a bus tour to Normandie in the morning, back in the late afternoon to haul ass to Musée d&amp;rsquo;Orsay before closing, off to the Eiffel Tower to see it sparkle at 23:00 on the dot, and in bed right away so she can get up at 04:00 to do it all again the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get exhausted just &lt;em&gt;reading&lt;/em&gt; her itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I can see on her face that this — standing on the bridge Claude Monet painted in 1899 — this is a &lt;em&gt;moment&lt;/em&gt; for her. Walking through Monet&amp;rsquo;s house, she could feel Monet in those rooms; she was sharing space with one of her favorite artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meaning — the emotion — that this trip held for her was beyond anything I could ever hope to feel about a house or a garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t hold that against her. I can&amp;rsquo;t hold that against any one of these people here to see something significant from human history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This was great, Jil.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She smiles and thanks me for putting up with the crowds. Then she asks if I want to go to Normandy tomorrow at 05:30. (I don&amp;rsquo;t.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ll go to Versailles&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:versailles&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:versailles&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; the day after. And then we&amp;rsquo;ll go to a local bar I like where we&amp;rsquo;re the only people who don&amp;rsquo;t speak French. Because I don&amp;rsquo;t have to choose: I can be a tourist sometimes without ruining my chances at experiencing local hangouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, quick: take my picture in front of this moment. I want all my friends to know I had a like &lt;em&gt;life-changing epiphany&lt;/em&gt; in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That shit gets retweeted like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:village&#34;&gt;Under which I assume used to stand a very charming village.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:village&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:pitch&#34;&gt;And just a tad smaller than a football pitch.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:pitch&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:flowers&#34;&gt;Though — let&amp;rsquo;s be honest — I can only identify maybe a half-dozen flowers without help from Google.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:flowers&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:oldwomen&#34;&gt;The relationship between septua- and octogenarian human females and botany has a distinctly moth:flame character to it. This was something I had always considered a kind of good-natured stereotype. At least until I entered the garden to find a field of blue and silver hair, about 1.5m tall, swaying slightly in the breeze.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:oldwomen&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:bird&#34;&gt;It was actually a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=baby+rail+bird&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=ZyeEVaDlO4HaUdKos4gM&amp;amp;ved=0CAcQ_AUoAQ&amp;amp;biw=1440&amp;amp;bih=801&amp;amp;dpr=2&#34;&gt;baby rail&lt;/a&gt; (I think). Which I didn&amp;rsquo;t know was a type of bird.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:bird&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:house&#34;&gt;Presumably, it was filled with doors, tables, chairs, and a fucking gift shop.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:house&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:touching&#34;&gt;Can we all agree that you just &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t touch strangers?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reactiongifs.us/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/no_touching_arrested_development.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NO TOUCHING!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:touching&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:edinburgh&#34;&gt;The castle in the center of Edinburgh, Scotland is a great (?) example of this. All the cannons are covered in high-gloss paint. The dungeons are gift shops now. There&amp;rsquo;s a concession stand. It feels about as authentic as an Olive Garden.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:edinburgh&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:exceptions&#34;&gt;Except me, of course.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:exceptions&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:offense&#34;&gt;Mostly because we&amp;rsquo;re ignorant and — despite our best efforts — just clueless about the proper approach to certain situations. Sometimes because we&amp;rsquo;re painfully, obviously American and bulling through the world&amp;rsquo;s china shop. And every once in a while because I can just be a dick when I&amp;rsquo;m hungry.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:offense&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:american&#34;&gt;They do. Every time. Usually before I even open my mouth. Serious question: do I look &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; American?
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:american&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:french&#34;&gt;Something I hadn&amp;rsquo;t realized when I first arrived in Paris was the astonishing number of French words and phrases that have been &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_French_expressions_in_English&#34;&gt;ported directly to English&lt;/a&gt;. I knew &lt;em&gt;raison d&amp;rsquo;être&lt;/em&gt; was French; I &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; know that (just in the As and Bs of the American lexicon) we&amp;rsquo;d borrowed &amp;ldquo;aperitif&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;armoire&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;belle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;boulevard&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;bourgeois&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;bouquet&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;brunette&amp;rdquo;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:french&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:versailles&#34;&gt;The grounds at Versailles were incredible, but the palace itself was awful because &lt;em&gt;holy shit&lt;/em&gt; the crowds. If there was anything worth seeing there, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it out over the sea of phone screens and miscellaneous objects waved by tour guides to keep their groups from disappearing into the mêlée. 0/10 would not return.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:versailles&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do More with Less: Drop Dead Physical &amp; Psychological Weight</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/do-more-with-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 04:34:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/do-more-with-less/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re serious? I can just&amp;hellip;take whatever I want?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pile of stuff in the corner of my apartment was huge. A drill I&amp;rsquo;d only used once sat on top of a box full of cables I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize I still had. An empty TV stand was littered with basically-new kitchen utensils and three different wifi routers. A full set of throw pillows I found in a closet sat on top of a toolbox full of art supplies I hadn&amp;rsquo;t opened since I dropped out of college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My neighbor had responded to a message I sent out to the building announcing a giveaway. I&amp;rsquo;ve never met this woman before. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming we live in the same building, but I can&amp;rsquo;t recall having seen her before — but then again, I&amp;rsquo;m not usually one to notice people passing by unless they&amp;rsquo;re holding food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She picks out some kitchen utensils, a whiteboard, and a package of AA batteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re sure? Anything?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Absolutely,&amp;rdquo; I reassure her. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re doing me a favor by taking this. Honest.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She leaves with her armload of booty, looking over her shoulder at me as if I&amp;rsquo;m going to change my mind and tackle her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, Marisa arrives with her own pile of stuff. A few hours later our friends arrive at the going-away-slash-holiday party we&amp;rsquo;ve arranged so we can see everyone before we leave the country the following Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friends all have the same bewildered look my neighbor wore when we start shoving our possessions into their arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, Nicole from the cleaning service arrives to do the move-out clean. I tell her to take anything she wants, and I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to see that she wants pretty much everything. She borrows the hand truck from the building to take a few loads out to her car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take everything that&amp;rsquo;s left and load it into Marisa&amp;rsquo;s trunk. At the donation drop, a man opens the door for Marisa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What a lovely day it is! What a lovely day to be alive! And how are you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marisa loves this guy. He&amp;rsquo;s a bit disheveled and wild-looking, like James Brown&amp;rsquo;s mugshot, and has the best attitude I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wow! Look at all this great stuff! Miss, you have excellent taste in movies — see this one right here? I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; this one right here!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He runs a cheerful commentary the whole time he helps us unload the trunk. (&amp;ldquo;This is a fantastic coat! I may have to buy this coat! You think it&amp;rsquo;ll fit me?&amp;rdquo;) His attitude is contagious. (&amp;ldquo;My oh my this blanket is &lt;em&gt;lovely!&lt;/em&gt; If I had this blanket and a mugful of hot cocoa I&amp;rsquo;d be the happiest man on Earth.&amp;ldquo;) As we pull out of the lot, waving, Marisa and I are wearing wide grins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop is a used car dealer, who buys Marisa&amp;rsquo;s car. He surprises her by offering more than she had expected for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, lying on the floor of my now-empty apartment, staring at the entirety of my worldly possessions in two small bags against the wall, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the way I&amp;rsquo;d expected to feel. I thought giving away all my things — possessions I&amp;rsquo;d carefully curated over the last few years — would feel like losing a limb. There was the art I&amp;rsquo;d collected from local cafés that showed my aesthetic preferences. The couch I&amp;rsquo;d had custom-built that was wide enough for four people to sit on and deep enough for two people to spoon. The bar full of all my favorite spirits and the proper glasses to serve drinks that announced to the world I was a whiskey kind of guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d feel empty.&lt;/strong&gt; I thought the absence of my things — this stuff that turned my insides out — would leave me hollowed out, back at Square One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But I felt exactly the opposite.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked down on the sum total of everything I owned with an incredible feeling of lightness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tiny pile of clothes and electronics was all I had to worry about. The internal pressure I felt to make sure my actions matched up with the material presentation I&amp;rsquo;d constructed — &amp;ldquo;is my attitude right now the attitude of a man who owns Herman Miller furniture?&amp;rdquo; — dissolved. My external pressure was gone; I only needed to make sure my actions matched up with the way I believed a man like me should act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/do-more-with-less.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;do more with less — emotional and material minimalism&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;minimalism-without-the-bullshit:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Minimalism, Without the Bullshit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try pretty hard to avoid labeling myself — I don&amp;rsquo;t want the actions of a group I don&amp;rsquo;t control to affect how people perceive me — so I don&amp;rsquo;t call myself a minimalist. But the core idea of the minimalist lifestyle does align with how I see the world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism is a lifestyle that helps people question what things add value to their lives. By clearing the clutter from life’s path, we can all make room for the most important aspects of life: health, relationships, passion, growth, and contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theminimalists.com/pitch/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Minimalists&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dropping-dead-weight:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Dropping Dead Weight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, &lt;strong&gt;every single thing we add to our lives, both physical and psychological, adds a tiny bit of extra weight that we have to carry around.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My operating view of the world is that my &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; self — the part that makes me a free-thinking, individual entity — is very small and virtually weightless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I experience the world, the things I do form memories, associations, and predictive models that help me navigate the world. These are the building blocks of my identity. I once threw up after eating cooked spinach from a can, and now I don&amp;rsquo;t like cooked spinach at all. I learned from my dad to always try to understand why things work, so I&amp;rsquo;m a shitty employee because I second-guess my bosses at every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These experiences make me into the person I am today, informing my personality and worldview, but each one adds a little weight to my identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To express my identity, I build a model of the kind of person I want to be seen as. I want to be seen as successful, so I only want to buy nice things. I want to be seen as discerning and stylish, so I only buy clothes and furniture with designs that have stood the test of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These possessions echo my experiences and reinforce them. If I thought I was a whiskey guy before I put a bunch of effort into finding a bottle of Black Maple Hill, I was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; a whiskey guy once I had that bottle in my bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The added weight of the material possessions and emotional biases on my decisions made it hard to be objective. &lt;strong&gt;Instead of asking, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s best in this situation?&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d find myself asking, &amp;ldquo;What would a guy like me do here?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cutting-the-crap:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Cutting the Crap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I pushed all of the possessions out of my life that weren&amp;rsquo;t essential for my daily life, it became easier for me to make objective decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, my plans to travel the world came with caveats: I&amp;rsquo;ll have to find a place to keep my Dordoni Worktop Table — I love that table — and my art collection will need a storage unit with climate control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could do what I wanted, but only after I&amp;rsquo;d made sure to take care of all my crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once those things were gone, I could weigh my options objectively and make quick, agile decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I want to go to Madrid? Well&amp;hellip;sure. Let&amp;rsquo;s do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No conditions or caveats — I can just pick up my two small bags and go with no guilt, no worries, and no hassles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;people-like-me:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;People Like Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I haven&amp;rsquo;t reduced my essential self back down to its weightless state. I&amp;rsquo;ve only changed my view of what &amp;ldquo;people like me&amp;rdquo; do; instead of thinking of myself as the kind of person who owns nice things and drinks good whiskey, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a new description for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of person who values experience over things and doesn&amp;rsquo;t worry about material possessions because they add stress instead of happiness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not enlightened, superior, or even better off; I&amp;rsquo;ve simply traded one guiding philosophy for another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this transition has allowed me to pursue the things I find meaningful. My old guiding philosophy was holding me back, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see it — the threat to my view of &amp;ldquo;people like me&amp;rdquo; was blocking me from seeing that I could be happier by trying a different outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-people-like-you-holding-you-back:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Are People Like You Holding You Back?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separating ourselves from our experiences is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; — there&amp;rsquo;s no denying it. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason people dedicate their whole lives to meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we don&amp;rsquo;t need to reach enlightenment to try and spot our own biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the easiest ways to catch ourselves being owned by our emotional and physical crap is to ask what we&amp;rsquo;d advise our friends to do if they were facing the same decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a friend came to you and asked, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve got this opportunity to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;travel the world&lt;/a&gt; while still making a living, but I&amp;rsquo;d have to sell all of my stuff in order to do it — what should I do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve known your friend has wanted to travel as long as you&amp;rsquo;ve been friends. What would you tell your friend to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re facing the same opportunity to travel right now. What would you tell yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your answers are different, you&amp;rsquo;re probably letting your physical and psychological dead weight get in the way of making objective decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard. You have to be really honest with yourself. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to face some uncomfortable personal demons. But think of everything you stand to gain by freeing yourself from the useless burdens you carry around — both in the closets you haven&amp;rsquo;t opened since you jammed your box full of &amp;ldquo;just in case&amp;rdquo; shit inside, and in the biased corners of your mind that hinder your ability to act objectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Work: Are We Just Working for Work&#39;s Sake?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/work-to-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 04:10:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/work-to-live/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to remember that we don&amp;rsquo;t live to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultural pressure is high to have a good job, and to work hard in that job to get a better job. To make more money so we can buy more stuff. To work the hardest and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/&#34;&gt;sacrifice&lt;/a&gt; the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stigmatize leisure as the mark of someone who won&amp;rsquo;t get far in life. We furrow our brows disapprovingly at the high school graduate who wants to take a year or two off before deciding what to study in college (or whether they should go at all). We look down on the smart kid who works a part-time job because he&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;not living up to his potential.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does all that really mean? Do leisure time, taking a break to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/growing-up-vs-growing-older/&#34;&gt;find yourself&lt;/a&gt;, and working just hard enough to get by really signify a problem? Or are we uncomfortable with the idea of valuing something else over work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can feel a lot like the latter in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t live to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We work to live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/dont-live-to-work-work-to-live.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;we don&amp;#39;t live to work; we work to live&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  What are you working for?

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-work-to-have-freedom:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;We Work to Have Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was eleven, I wanted a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nintendo_64&#34;&gt;Nintendo 64&lt;/a&gt; in the worst way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at $200, my chances were slim. I got a weekly allowance of $10, so by my estimation it would be a thousand years before I&amp;rsquo;d saved up enough to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to beg my parents and promise that they&amp;rsquo;d never have to buy me anything ever again&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in order to get one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 14 I got my first job washing dishes at a local restaurant. My first paycheck blew me away: I&amp;rsquo;d made over $160&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in just two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the next gaming console rolled out, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to beg anyone for it — I could buy it with my own money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The freedom that I felt when I made my first big purchase with money I&amp;rsquo;d earned at my job was intoxicating.&lt;/strong&gt; I knew I never wanted to be stuck begging for the things I wanted again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-shouldn-t-rob-us-of-freedom:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;Work Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Rob Us of Freedom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work to remove the limitations that exist when we can&amp;rsquo;t afford to do the things we want and need. &lt;strong&gt;Income gives us the ability to choose what&amp;rsquo;s best for ourselves, rather than being beholden to someone in a position of power over us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult/&#34;&gt;let work become the dominant force&lt;/a&gt; in our lives, we start to give away that same freedom we&amp;rsquo;ve worked to gain. Only this time it&amp;rsquo;s not a shortage of income that shackles us, but a shortage of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we&amp;rsquo;re trading our freedom for higher wages, or for career advancement, or for anything at all, really, we&amp;rsquo;re actively undermining one of the core principles of work: &lt;strong&gt;we work so we have the freedom to choose.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-work-to-have-purpose:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;We Work to Have Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently visited the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elephantnaturepark.org/&#34;&gt;Elephant Nature Park&lt;/a&gt;, run by Lek Chailert, a tiny woman from a rural part of Thailand with deep reverence for elephants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an adult, she works hard to rescue abused, disabled, and unwanted domesticated elephants and raise awareness about the rapidly disappearing elephant population and mistreatment of elephants as livestock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s found purpose in her work — or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s better to say she found work in her purpose. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that she finds her work incredibly important and fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even if our work isn&amp;rsquo;t our main purpose, it provides a means to pursue that purpose.&lt;/strong&gt; To quote the words of modern-day philosopher Jay-Z:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t help the poor if I&amp;rsquo;m one of them So I got rich and gave back, to me that&amp;rsquo;s the win/win&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jay-Z, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genius.com/9545/Jay-z-moment-of-clarity/Since-i-know-what-im-up-against-we-as-rappers-must-decide-whats-most-important-and-i-cant-help-the-poor-if-im-one-of-them-so-i-got-rich-and-gave-back-to-me-thats-the-win-win&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moment of Clarity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-shouldn-t-rob-us-of-purpose:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;Work Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Rob Us of Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By working, we create the opportunity for ourselves to apply time, money, and effort on the things that we think are most important in life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we let work spill over into our personal lives, the means to pursue our passions begins to diminish. We don&amp;rsquo;t have the energy to go after the things that we used to consider most important — we&amp;rsquo;re too exhausted from working, too preoccupied with meaningless metrics, or too worried about moving up the corporate ladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we let our work displace our purpose, we start to lose steam, and the results can be disastrous: midlife crises, depression, a sense of purposelessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-is-a-tool-not-a-burden:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;Work Is a Tool, Not a Burden&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work because we want to live better lives, and to do that we need to have a way to make an income. For most of us, that means a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is a tool that gives us access to meet our needs and fulfill our various wants. And when it&amp;rsquo;s treated like a tool, we&amp;rsquo;re able to control our efforts in a way that creates a better life for ourselves and our loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if we lose sight of what&amp;rsquo;s important to us, work can become the sole focus in our lives — it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a tool, it&amp;rsquo;s a burden that prevents us from doing what we want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to remember that we weren&amp;rsquo;t put on this planet to punch a clock and die on a pile of money; &lt;strong&gt;we were put here to live.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So repeat after me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t live to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We work to live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You never have to buy me anything, ever again!&amp;rdquo; was recently ranked #14 on the &lt;em&gt;Top 100 Phrases Children Don&amp;rsquo;t Fully Understand&lt;/em&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;Suck it, allowance!
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Know If You&#39;ve Joined a Cult</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 01:07:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You didn&amp;rsquo;t mean to end up here. You didn&amp;rsquo;t even see it coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with a chance to earn a living doing something you loved. Your dream job. Creating things instead of rotting in a cubicle. You weren&amp;rsquo;t just going to make a living — &lt;em&gt;you were going to leave your mark on the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, you loved the work; it was challenging and fast-paced. Everyone around you was crazy smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You brainstormed in your off time. Took projects home with you. Put in extra hours on weekends. It never felt like overworking because it never felt like work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You put in way more than 40 hours a week, but who was counting? This was &lt;em&gt;fun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But weeks passed into months and somehow you ended up here: Working 60 hours a week minimum, usually more. You greet your coworkers, bleary-eyed, half-joking about needing coffee to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work is still fun, but you don&amp;rsquo;t feel the same passion anymore. Whole days slip by sometimes and you have no idea what happened; you certainly don&amp;rsquo;t have much to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goals outside of work are on hold. You&amp;rsquo;d love to find out if the Belgians have anything to be cocky about waffle-wise, but you don&amp;rsquo;t have time for a big trip right now. You know you need to get into an exercise routine, but something always comes up and you skip the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Later,&amp;rdquo; you promise yourself, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to it soon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not exactly &lt;em&gt;un*happy, but something&amp;rsquo;s off. You can&amp;rsquo;t put your finger on it. You&amp;rsquo;ve just always felt that there would be &amp;hellip; *more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/a-clockwork-orange.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Cultural pressure to work long hours creates false obligation.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  You&#39;re being force-fed an &#34;ideal&#34; work ethic that&#39;s actually toxic for everyone involved.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1VqP36g&#34;&gt;A Clockwork Orange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-ve-been-absorbed:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve Been Absorbed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re no longer a free member of society. You&amp;rsquo;ve been lured into the &lt;strong&gt;Overkill Cult&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Overkill Cult is a cultural delusion that working 60+ hour weeks at the expense of everything else in our lives is not only a necessary part of success, but that doing so is somehow *honorable.&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The insidious thing about the Overkill Cult is that it masquerades as all the things we like most about ourselves: dedication, ambition, follow-through, responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It tells us to push harder, stay later, sleep when we&amp;rsquo;re dead. It tells us we&amp;rsquo;re never going to get ahead if we don&amp;rsquo;t show up first and go home last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleverly, wickedly, the Overkill Cult persuades us to hang ourselves with our own strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if we don&amp;rsquo;t break free, we&amp;rsquo;re all going to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-overkill-cult-will-kill-you-like-it-tried-to-kill-me:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;The Overkill Cult Will Kill You (Like It Tried to Kill Me)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance is the first thing to go once the Overkill Cult has us in its grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it started with my health. I skipped the gym — &lt;em&gt;too busy&lt;/em&gt;, I thought. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to cook — &lt;em&gt;too busy&lt;/em&gt; — so I ordered delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hobbies went next. Everything that wasn&amp;rsquo;t work fell away — &lt;em&gt;too busy, too busy&lt;/em&gt; — until I was on the computer constantly, working.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;strong&gt;In 2012, I was working 70–90 hours a week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I lost my social life. Friends knew I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t show up — &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t; too busy&lt;/em&gt; — so they stopped calling. Some days my only human interaction was ordering coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then — and this, sadly, is where I finally realized there was a problem — I lost my beard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-canary-in-the-coal-mine-or-how-i-killed-my-beard:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;The Canary in the Coal Mine, or How I Killed My Beard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2012, I landed the biggest project of my career at that point: a Black Friday sales site for a Fortune 100 company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thrilled and terrified. A project like this had the potential to move my company to the next level, and I decided to do whatever it took to make this project the best I&amp;rsquo;d ever built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The designers had great ideas, and I sat with them to make sure they were possible on our timeline. We came up with a slick, modern idea built on cutting-edge technology. The client loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then bureaucracy came into play. The legal department made changes. Brand adherence contradicted legal. Design went over schedule. &lt;em&gt;Way&lt;/em&gt; over schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time the design was approved, I had a third of the time we&amp;rsquo;d scheduled. And — since this was a Black Friday site — we couldn&amp;rsquo;t push back the release date. It either launched on time or I was a failure. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to be defeated, I powered through four straight days leading up to Black Friday, sleeping &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; six hours total. On Thanksgiving Day I skipped family get-togethers in favor of making the final push.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was exhausted. Delirious. But, goddammit, &lt;em&gt;I finished the project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client was thrilled. The site won a couple Addy Awards. I assume they made a metric fuckton in holiday sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few months, patches of my beard started to turn white. The whiskers became ultra-fine. Then they fell out altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/overwork-stress-unhealthy.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;effect of overwork on the body&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  May, 2013 — about six months after my Black Friday fiasco.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly afterward, I lost my ability to grow a beard entirely — I was left with the unsavory choice between a clean-shaven &amp;ldquo;giant fat baby&amp;rdquo; look and a creepy mustache.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had stressed myself out so badly that my body had forgotten how to grow a beard. And for what? So I could work 19-hour days and skip family holidays to meet crazy deadlines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was exhausted. My body was failing. I was overwhelmed and unhappy and isolated. &lt;em&gt;I had a mustache, for chrissakes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been guzzling the Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s Kool-Aid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something had to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-tell-if-you-re-in-a-cult:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;How to Tell If You&amp;rsquo;re in a Cult&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telltale signs we&amp;rsquo;ve fallen prey to the Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s influence are subtle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequently working more than 40 hours a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequently sleeping less than 6 hours a night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feeling guilty about any time away from work— even if that time is with family and friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t join overnight — this is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality&#34;&gt;death by a thousand cuts&lt;/a&gt; — and once we&amp;rsquo;ve joined, we&amp;rsquo;ll probably deny it.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;rsquo;ve joined. By the thousands, we&amp;rsquo;ve joined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lies-of-the-overkill-cult:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;The Lies of the Overkill Cult&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s siren song seems like a healthy sense of ambition. &amp;ldquo;We have to work hard to get ahead.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s something we&amp;rsquo;ve been told our entire lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re doing what we think is best for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Overkill Cult doesn&amp;rsquo;t plan for survivors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the symptoms of the Overkill Cult grow from good intentions, they&amp;rsquo;re short-sighted habits that ultimately do more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of the Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s telltale signs, and how each of them is a long-term detriment disguised as a healthy work ethic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-working-more-than-40-hours-a-week:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Frequently Working More than 40 Hours a Week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long hours often feel mandatory — it&amp;rsquo;s just part of the culture. We think, &amp;ldquo;My boss/coworkers/cat will judge me if I&amp;rsquo;m not working the same long hours as everyone else. I&amp;rsquo;ll never get ahead if I don&amp;rsquo;t go above and beyond.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just what it takes to make it, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrong.&lt;/strong&gt; Incredibly, terribly, &lt;em&gt;spectacularly&lt;/em&gt; wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research has proven over and over again that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to be productive for more than 40 hours a week.&lt;/strong&gt; At least not for sustained periods of time. Henry Ford introduced the 40-hour work week in 1914 because he saw — through research — that workers on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salon.com/2012/03/14/bring_back_the_40_hour_work_week/&#34;&gt;five eight-hour shifts kept up the highest sustained levels of productivity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite over 100 years of research supporting shorter work weeks, many companies still push for long hours, under the claims of a &amp;ldquo;sprint&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;crunch time&amp;rdquo; period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/overwork-hurts-productivity.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;overtime causes negative productivity after a short time&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This diagram is loosely based on one included in Sidney J. Chapman&#39;s *Hours of Labor*.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony comes in when we look at productivity over time. After just two months of 60-hour weeks, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enginesofmischief.com/makers/evan/pubs/crunch.html&#34;&gt;productivity goes &lt;em&gt;negative&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; compared to what a 40 hour week would have produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you catch that? &lt;strong&gt;By working 150% of the hours, you accomplish &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; in the long run.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-sleeping-less-than-6-hours-a-night:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Frequently Sleeping Less than 6 Hours a Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, sleeplessness has become a strange badge of honor. We swap &amp;ldquo;war stories&amp;rdquo; of sleeping two hours a night with an odd, martyred pride shining dimly in our bloodshot eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I never sleep because &lt;a href=&#34;http://genius.com/3012/Nas-ny-state-of-mind/I-never-sleep-cause-sleep-is-the-cousin-of-death&#34;&gt;sleep is the cousin of death&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; we murmur drowsily. So many projects, so little time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this belief that burning the midnight oil somehow gets us ahead is utterly, tragically wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1739867/pdf/v057p00649.pdf&#34;&gt;cognitive equivalent of a drunk driver&lt;/a&gt; after being awake about 18 hours. But the problem compounds: if you don&amp;rsquo;t get enough sleep, that level of impairment comes faster the next day. After a few days of too little sleep, you&amp;rsquo;re a drunken zombie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go to work drunk, so why the hell do we go to work on four hours&amp;rsquo; sleep, when we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; impaired than if we were hammered?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, sleeping less than six hours a night &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/8660373.stm&#34;&gt;may lead to an early death&lt;/a&gt;. The Overkill Cult is &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; killing you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;feeling-guilty-about-any-time-away-from-work-even-time-with-family-and-friends:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Feeling Guilty About Any Time Away from Work — Even Time with Family and Friends &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we&amp;rsquo;re in the clutches of the Overkill Cult, we feel a stab of guilt when we&amp;rsquo;re not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d love to go to this holiday party, but I really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t; this project won&amp;rsquo;t finish itself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fear that any time not spent working is wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony is — yet again — science tells us &lt;em&gt;exactly the opposite&lt;/em&gt; is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overworking leads to higher stress levels and burnout, which have been linked to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.3200/BMED.31.1.18-32#.VP2vuYGsWlI&#34;&gt;increased health risks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, time away from work is proven to &lt;a href=&#34;http://depts.washington.edu/hhwb/Thm_Mental.html&#34;&gt;relieve stress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2014-14435-001/&#34;&gt;boost creativity&lt;/a&gt;, among numerous other benefits.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, if we accept that the ideal is to sleep 8 hours a night and work 8 hours a day, that leaves us with 8 hours&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for non-work activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking time away from work gives us time to recharge. It puts distance between us and our projects, giving us time to remember why we like doing what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-our-escape:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Making Our Escape&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we may have been duped into joining the Overkill Cult, it&amp;rsquo;s not too late to escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been conned using our own best qualities to develop habits that — even though it &lt;em&gt;seems&lt;/em&gt; like they&amp;rsquo;d make us better — make us worse at our jobs, less satisfied with our work, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; less happy in our day-to-day lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leveraging the same strengths the Overkill Cult exploits, we can break free of its clutches and take back our happiness and passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my beard died, I felt the full weight of burnout. &lt;em&gt;I was burnt to a fucking crisp.&lt;/em&gt; I realized I could either leave my career altogether, or make some fundamental changes to my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, here are the promises I made to myself that helped me break away from the Overkill Cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-work-as-much-as-i-can-but-not-more:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;I Work as Much as I Can — But Not More&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before anything else, I had to accept that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s only possible to do 6–8 hours of quality work each day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to work longer hours will not make me more productive. In fact, working longer hours actually results in me getting less done as time drags on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose the latter, and implemented some radical (to me) &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-experiment/&#34;&gt;strategies for controlling my time&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;I cut from an average of 70–90 hours a week in 2013 to an average 38 hours per week over the last year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected to see less professional success in favor of better overall balance in my life — a sacrifice I was willing to make — instead I saw &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; productivity at work: my turn-around times went down&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and I was more consistently hitting my deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was floored at the time, but in retrospect I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-make-sleep-a-top-priority:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;I Make Sleep a Top Priority&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting enough sleep is beneficial on every level. Yet it&amp;rsquo;s always the first thing I would sacrifice when life got busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too little sleep wreaks havoc on my ability to think clearly, and that hurts me at work in a big, bad way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I cut my hours down, I started sleeping without an alarm.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Since I&amp;rsquo;m not working crazy hours, I close my computer by six or seven in the evening, and by eleven I&amp;rsquo;m usually in bed, where I read for a bit before falling asleep. I wake up naturally between seven and eight-thirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has changed my life. No bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waking up to an alarm before I&amp;rsquo;m fully rested starts the day in a groggy, stressful way. Waking up naturally after getting as much sleep as my body needs leaves me much happier to be awake, and far more ready to start my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-dedicate-a-reasonable-amount-of-time-to-not-working:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;I Dedicate a Reasonable Amount of Time to NOT Working&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was — and still is — the biggest challenge I faced in breaking away from the Overkill Cult. I love what I do, and I want to get my projects finished. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to rationalize working more hours and skipping activities that keep me from working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I know that taking breaks makes me more productive: time away from work lets my passion and excitement for the work renew itself; taking my mind off of a project allows my subconscious to roll around abstract ideas that result in better solutions; breaks from the job lower my stress levels and boost my creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I make sure to do it, even if my gut (incorrectly) tells me it&amp;rsquo;s a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take walks. I leave my phone in my pocket when I&amp;rsquo;m out with friends or eating my meals. I spend a fair amount of time on my hobbies, like writing and hunting for the world&amp;rsquo;s best cheeseburger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happier today than I can ever remember being in my life. I feel excited to work on my projects, to pursue my hobbies, and to spend time with people I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to be alive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leaving-the-overkill-cult-saved-my-life:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Leaving the Overkill Cult Saved My Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When my beard died in 2013, I feared it was only the first sign of an impending decline in my health that would ultimately kill me.&lt;/strong&gt; It was a glimpse into my future, and I was terrified that if I didn&amp;rsquo;t change, I was in for a life of isolation, ulcers, alopecia, and an eventual heart attack or stress-induced brain tumor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By changing my lifestyle, I was able to turn things around. After just a year of balancing my work with the rest of my life, my beard grew back. I lost 30 pounds because I was actually going outside and making it to the gym. I felt more awake, and I &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jlengstorf/stop-glossing-over-the-good-stuff-b89e25f7c714&#34;&gt;became more positive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I left the Overkill Cult, &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; in my life improved. Not one single thing got worse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-costa-rica.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf in front of a volcano in Costa Rica after fixing his work-life balance&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Doing a superhero pose in front of a volcano in Costa Rica. (Notice my beard.)

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://marisamorby.com&#34;&gt;Marisa Morby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-ready-to-make-your-escape:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Are You Ready to Make Your Escape?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been sucked into the Overkill Cult, know that you&amp;rsquo;re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be facing cultural pressure to keep this crazy pace. You may be struggling with your identity as &amp;ldquo;a hard worker&amp;rdquo; and feeling that scaling back somehow makes you lazy or useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I promise you — despite the doubts the Overkill Cult will force into your mind — there&amp;rsquo;s a better way. Better for your career. Better for your health. Better for your relationships. Better for your happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ended up in the Overkill Cult because you&amp;rsquo;re smart, ambitious, and dedicated. But you were misled by your good qualities and turned them into bad habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a better way, and you&amp;rsquo;re smart enough to pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dump your Kool-Aid in the sink. Take back your freedom. Find the happiness and success you were looking for when you started this career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Close your computer. Go outside. And call your friends; they miss you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;Hardly any of these hours were productive. Often I&amp;rsquo;d refresh my email, or stare at a code editor in a daze before realizing I&amp;rsquo;d been sitting there with my mouth open for half an hour.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll look like Magnum,&amp;rdquo; I tried to tell myself. But I knew — even then, I knew — it was all a horrible, creepy lie.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re currently rationalizing how you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in the Overkill Cult even though you meet all the criteria, you&amp;rsquo;re definitely a member.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;These studies focus on walking a few minutes a day. Not even an actual hobby or dedicated non-work activity. The negative effects of &amp;ldquo;all work and no play&amp;rdquo; are staggering, if you think about it.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;Or, if you want to exclude meals and such, &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; four hours. That&amp;rsquo;s enough time to go to the gym &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; pick up a hobby. Or even, you know, hang out with other humans or something.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;I also made other changes that helped with turn-around times, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/effective-project-planning/&#34;&gt;planning more effectively&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;Waking up without an alarm is, by far, my favorite thing about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;digital nomad lifestyle&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful to lead.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is the Magic?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/magic</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 09:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/magic</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As kids, we see a lot of the world around us as magical. Then, as we get older, the magic gives way to understanding. &lt;strong&gt;But is losing the magic a good thing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/where-is-the-magic.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Where is the magic?&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/bobjagendorf/&#34;&gt;Bob Jagendorf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-curse-of-knowledge:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;The Curse of Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was first starting out in business, I read a book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://cptr.me/XoBEmg&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Made to Stick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Among other things, I was introduced to The Curse of Knowledge, which is the idea that — as we become more familiar with a given topic — we are unable to explain an idea well to someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about any time you&amp;rsquo;ve played charades, and by the end you&amp;rsquo;re ready to scream at your team, &amp;ldquo;How could you &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; get that?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your head you were perfectly pantomiming &lt;em&gt;Gone with the Wind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What your team saw was you riding an imaginary horse and waving your fingers like you were casting a spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; something, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely difficult to see it from the perspective of someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-other-curse-of-knowledge:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;The Other Curse of Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another curse of knowledge, though, and it&amp;rsquo;s a little sneakier. &lt;em&gt;The Revenge of the Curse of Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/are-you-wizard.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;are you a wizard&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young, I thought my dad was basically a wizard because he could tie shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought my mom was conjuring up cookies through some dark art or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiny people lived in my television to entertain me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rabbit and a fat man broke into my house to leave candy and gifts every so often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My closet was a portal to the worst place imaginable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world was full of magic, and I was awestruck.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disillusionment-or-how-the-magic-died-in-a-book:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;Disillusionment, or How the Magic Died in a Book&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I learned how to tie my shoes. I added the ingredients my mom had measured out into a bowl and watched cookies take shape. I learned enough about TV signals to know there weren&amp;rsquo;t actually tiny people in there. Dad spilled the beans about Santa and the Easter Bunny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The closet still creeps me out, though.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bit by bit, the magic was stripped away and the simple truth about how things worked was laid plain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was no longer awestruck. Instead, I was condescending to the people around me who hadn&amp;rsquo;t learned yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-world-without-magic:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;A World without Magic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I see something amazing, it feels like magic. I&amp;rsquo;m blown away. I tell my friends. If there&amp;rsquo;s a YouTube clip, I&amp;rsquo;m sharing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8F6EoMdn95E?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw this guy — &lt;a href=&#34;http://dubfx.com/&#34;&gt;Dub FX&lt;/a&gt; — on the streets of Amsterdam, and I was &lt;em&gt;convinced&lt;/em&gt; he was a sorceror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just a dude with a microphone. He starts singing. Then&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;holy shit what just happened? &lt;strong&gt;It must be magic!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not. It&amp;rsquo;s a talented musician who can beatbox and operate a looping station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impressive? Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic? Not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;losing-my-sense-of-wonder:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;Losing My Sense of Wonder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not just entertainment and childhood stories that have lost the soft glow of pixie dust; I&amp;rsquo;ve felt a similar sense of disillusionment with my own life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started &lt;a href=&#34;http://copterlabs.com/&#34;&gt;building websites&lt;/a&gt;, code was still fairly mystical to me. I could do a few things, but most of what I saw was beyond my grasp; otherworldly manifestations brought forth by the legendary Mystics of Nerd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful freelancing was a dark art. Saving money required an incantation from a book bound in human skin. If I wanted to be any good at sex, I needed to sacrifice a goat at Kilauea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the more I learned, the more I realized that none of this is sacred, supernatural, or even secret. There are no shortcuts. No &amp;ldquo;weird tricks&amp;rdquo; to make someone suddently good at a skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no magic. It&amp;rsquo;s all just hard work, practice, actually giving a shit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;does-magic-matter:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;Does Magic Matter?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/Justin-Flom-Magic-Trick.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Justin Flom magic trick&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    


    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.justinflom.com/&#34;&gt;Justin Flom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, who cares if there&amp;rsquo;s no magic? We&amp;rsquo;re adults, dammit, and magic is for children. And David Blaine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure. That&amp;rsquo;s fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m not ready to give up my sense of wonder. I like being blown away by something that I don&amp;rsquo;t understand.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I want to be surrounded by wizards and fairies and sorceresses who are making impossible things happen all around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I lose my sense of wonder, then I&amp;rsquo;m resigning to a life of familiar, comfortable tasks. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing left to surprise me.&lt;/strong&gt; Giving in to the part of me that&amp;rsquo;s jaded and pessimistic that beleives there&amp;rsquo;s nothing new anyways and why bother at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d like myself without the hope for magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-how-can-we-bring-the-magic-back:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;So How Can We Bring the Magic Back?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with The Revenge of the Curse of Knowledge is that once you&amp;rsquo;ve seen behind the curtain, you can&amp;rsquo;t unsee it. The wizard is just a dude with a killer pyrotechnics setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s no going back to the kind of awe and wonder we felt as children. And that&amp;rsquo;s probably okay; I lost a lot of sleep wondering if my uncle would ever give my nose back, and I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford that today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we can find new magic, and remember to &lt;em&gt;actually feel&lt;/em&gt; that amazement that comes along with seeing something new and wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be big stuff, like learning that there were &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iflscience.com/plants-and-animals/first-ever-swimming-dinosaur-ate-sharks&#34;&gt;shark-eating dinosaurs&lt;/a&gt; or that scientists are working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nature.com/ncomms/2014/140826/ncomms5712/full/ncomms5712.html&#34;&gt;tiny robots that fight cancer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or it can be the little things we might completely dismiss if we&amp;rsquo;re not paying attention: when the new project you&amp;rsquo;re working on falls into place for the first time; when the outfit you chose today gets compliments from everyone you meet; when you think to yourself, &amp;ldquo;I really wish I had a blueberry muffin,&amp;rdquo; and then someone from the office lets you know there are muffins in the break room and should they save you one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our lives are full of small, magical moments.&lt;/strong&gt; If we&amp;rsquo;re looking for them, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-magical-in-your-life-right-now:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Magical in Your Life Right Now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think back over the last few days. &lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s happened that felt like magic?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted cheesecake the other night, and a local bar had a cheesecake special that night. I toured the Willett Distillery, saw how some of my favorite bourbon is made, and sampled some of the very rare, expensive labels. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gsnrzr0Bm80&#34;&gt;discovered a band&lt;/a&gt; that makes my hair stand on end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not quite Santa Claus, but it&amp;rsquo;s enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where have you felt a little bit of magic in your life lately?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;At least at first; eventually I want to know how it works.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Men Have Best Friends?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/best-friends</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 09:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/best-friends</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have a best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To say that feels weird. I&amp;rsquo;m almost thirty; thirty-year-old men don&amp;rsquo;t have &amp;ldquo;best friends&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have drinking/golfing/hunting buddies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have their wives&amp;rsquo; friends&amp;rsquo; husbands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they certainly &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; have a Bee Eff Eff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I read Stephen Marche&amp;rsquo;s article for &lt;em&gt;Esquire&lt;/em&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.esquire.com/blogs/culture/on-bro-0914&#34;&gt;the abuse of the word &amp;ldquo;bro&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. I thought it was going to be a silly piece about pop culture, but then I ran into this line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mature as a female person is to mature into female friendships. To mature as a male person is to mature out of male friendships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a sort of shyness I&amp;rsquo;ve felt about telling anyone that I have a best friend. It feels roughly equivalent to admitting I still sleep with a nightlight or that my mom still packs a lunch for me every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a best friend feels like kid stuff. It feels like something I should have grown out of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nate-and-jason-the-best-of-friends:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;Nate and Jason, the Best of Friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/best-friends1.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Nate Green and Jason Lengstorf&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been friends with &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt; since we were eleven or twelve, when his family moved in down the street and our moms set us up on a play date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did all the stuff boys do: played Mortal Kombat&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:fatalities&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:fatalities&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, shot our little brothers with BB guns, pretended we were the Harlem Globetrotters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate and I were opposites in a lot of ways, but we both felt like outsiders — Nate because he didn&amp;rsquo;t quite meet the criteria of any clique, and me because I was in the midst of several simultaneous identity crises — and that held us together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our opposite tendencies were complementary: I did Nate&amp;rsquo;s homework; Nate convinced the cute girls at the beach to hang out with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As adults, Nate and I are still opposites. We still complement each other well personally, and now we&amp;rsquo;re able to help each other professionally.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:symbiosis&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:symbiosis&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-all-need-a-sounding-board:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;We All Need a Sounding Board&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complementary skill sets aside, Nate and I have helped each other in another, less tangible way: over the course of nearly twenty years of friendship, we&amp;rsquo;ve had hundreds of very frank, very honest conversation. The kind that most people have to pay a psychiatrist for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to discuss the things that scared us — being able to be 100% vulnerable, in other words — has allowed us to work through the source of many of our fears and troubles, which has ultimately led to both of us becoming more aware of our internal motivations and the things that trip us up. We&amp;rsquo;re both better people because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; In July 2015, Nate and I decided to make these conversations public in hopes of sparking similar discussions for anyone willing to listen. We&amp;rsquo;ve created a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2FTAT.com?utm_source=best-friends&amp;amp;utm_medium=site-link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=lengstorf-com&#34;&gt;podcast where we have deep conversations&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;em&gt;Two Friends Talking About Things&lt;/em&gt;. You can listen to the first episode here, on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2ftat.com/episode/00-what-are-we-talking-about/?utm_source=best-friends&amp;amp;utm_medium=episode-link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=lengstorf-com&#34;&gt;the website&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/hear2FTAT&#34;&gt;on iTunes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/127426147&amp;color=eb7f00&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=true&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=false&amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-going-to-get-so-much-shit-for-this:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Going to Get So Much Shit for This&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Nate and I were discussing our most recent challenge to each other: write for at least thirty minutes a day and post whatever comes out on our blogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shared one of Nate&amp;rsquo;s posts yesterday. He mentioned that he was planning to share one as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both got uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was it weird that we were publicly giving each other so much attention? Would people make fun of us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did we both feel that way? Everyone who knows us knows that we&amp;rsquo;re close, and neither of us is ashamed of being friends with the other. So where does this apprehension over talking about our friendship on the Internet come from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hollywood-hates-dude-friends:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;Hollywood Hates Dude Friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Marche argues that pop culture is poisoning the idea of male friendship:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The splendid isolation of masculinity has emerged from so much iconography—the cowboy, the astronaut, the gangster—that almost every hero in the past fifty years has been a figure of loneliness. Current pop culture is even more extreme: It doesn&amp;rsquo;t just celebrate the lonely man; it also despises men in groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marche claims most movies and TV shows show groups of men being idiots. &lt;em&gt;The Hangover&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dumb and Dumber&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;How I Met Your Mother&lt;/em&gt; all paint the idea of male friendship as a way to bring out the least intelligent parts of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it explains why I feel apprehensive talking about having a best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-have-a-best-friend:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;Do You Have a Best Friend?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I had a solution, or even a suggestion for a solution to the problem. I don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do know that — despite being uneasy saying it out loud — having a close male friend has been one of the most beneficial things in my life, both growing up and as an adult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a best friend? Does it feel weird to talk about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a best friend, does it bother you?&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:honest&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:honest&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:fatalities&#34;&gt;What I mean by &amp;ldquo;played&amp;rdquo; is that I would mash buttons while Nate and his little brother would expertly and brutally murder my character because they knew all the special moves and fatalities. &lt;strong&gt;All of them.&lt;/strong&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:fatalities&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:symbiosis&#34;&gt;I work with Nate to help him implement a lot of his projects that have a design or tech component, and Nate helps me with marketing and networking.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:symbiosis&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:honest&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m genuinely curious, not baiting.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:honest&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bright Side</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/bright-side</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 15:28:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/bright-side</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Every time you talk to another person, you&amp;rsquo;re affecting the way they feel. Try not to make them feel like shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re meeting two people for dinner. One sits down with a smile, making eye contact, sitting up straight, looking pretty happy; the other is despondent, flopped in his chair like a sack of laundry, and studying the palms of his hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now ask about their days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paulie-poopypants:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Paulie Poopypants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The schmoopy one says, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough day. I was late getting to work, and as soon as I showed up my boss dropped this giant project in my lap. And then — as if my day wasn&amp;rsquo;t already bad enough — it was raining after work so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t go to the park like I wanted to.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bobbi-brightside:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Bobbi Brightside&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smiley one says, &amp;ldquo;Today was pretty good! I took an extra-long shower, which was great even though I had to rush to work afterward. I just got a new project at work that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a great challenge — I think if I do well, I might get a promotion. And since it was rainy after work I got a chance to write a letter to a friend I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to send.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;they-re-describing-exactly-the-same-day:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re Describing Exactly the Same Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever someone tells a story, they spin it. Their feelings and motives color the narrative, and we feel — to a certain extent, at least — what they feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that. Because it&amp;rsquo;s huge: &lt;strong&gt;you have the ability to control the moods of the people around you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-fun-to-be-around:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Are You Fun to Be Around?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone wants to feel happy. It&amp;rsquo;s why we seek out things like music and love and beauty; it&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href=&#34;http://illegal-art.net/girltalk/&#34;&gt;Girl Talk&lt;/a&gt; causes spontaneous dance parties; it&amp;rsquo;s why I prefer to hear &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/&#34;&gt;stories with happy endings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have the ability to make me feel happy when I ask about your day. What were the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jlengstorf/stop-glossing-over-the-good-stuff-b89e25f7c714&#34;&gt;good things that happened to you&lt;/a&gt;? What&amp;rsquo;s the bright side? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the best thing about today?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you focus on the negative, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to feel great. And I&amp;rsquo;m going to associate that feeling with you. And if it happens frequently, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start avoiding you, because you&amp;rsquo;re a downer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-to-paulie-and-bobbi:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Back to Paulie and Bobbi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s assume you have the option to hang out with either Paulie Poopypants or Bobbi Brightside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a lot more fun hanging out with Bobbi; positivity is contagious, and optimism cures a lot of ills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of all the people you look forward to spending time with. Are any of those people constantly bringing you down with stories about how hard, unfair, or hopeless things are?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-your-silver-lining:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Find Your Silver Lining&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything has a bright side.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s up to you to let the bright side give you hope instead of letting the challenge bring you down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/eeyore.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Eeyore&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself become an emotional black hole.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you see your glass as half-empty or half-full, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s still your glass.&lt;/strong&gt; And you have to deal with that regardless of your attitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; control is how you frame your circumstances in conversation. Bringing a little sunshine to someone else&amp;rsquo;s day means they&amp;rsquo;ll look forward to your company. And you might even find that projecting positivity outward makes you more inwardly positive as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ask yourself: Are you a source of positivity and happiness for other people? Or are you the Eeyore that shits on everyone else&amp;rsquo;s good time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;Okay, okay, not everything. Some things are irredeemable. But if you have time to read a blog like mine, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to bet that you and I are talking better than 95% First World Problems, here. #realtalk
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me Against the World</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/me-against-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 23:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/me-against-the-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The idea of &amp;ldquo;me against the world&amp;rdquo; is strange. It implies that, for whatever reason, I pose a threat to The World and, therefore, must be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World will strike at me with weather and illness; with fairweather friends and canceled flights; with unrequited love and full seasons of &lt;em&gt;Entourage&lt;/em&gt; on demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World is out to get me. The World wants me to fail. The World is an unstoppable current against which I have to battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World is Dr. Doom, hellbent on ruining my happiness and success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/dog-against-the-world.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Dog Against the World&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The World is out to get this dog, too. Look how thoughtful he is.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s how it works. There&amp;rsquo;s no supervillain manifested in The World; there&amp;rsquo;s just the world: at best an indifferent observer, and more likely an inanimate object that doesn&amp;rsquo;t do too much of anything except &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; notice when I succeed, fail, live, or die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-is-not-against-me:545e32d7f89a68970f2c2d20a1ec1a67&#34;&gt;The World Is Not Against Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t even know I&amp;rsquo;m here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, this is terrifying. I&amp;rsquo;m a boat on the ocean, fighting wind and waves, and the storm would swallow me, my hopes, and dreams, all without a thought about me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How insignificant and small I must be, for the world to take no notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world doesn&amp;rsquo;t care if I fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-also-doesn-t-care-if-i-succeed:545e32d7f89a68970f2c2d20a1ec1a67&#34;&gt;The World Also Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Care If I Succeed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can die in my parents&amp;rsquo; basement as a jobless, dreamless nobody, or I can die as the best version of myself I can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world doesn&amp;rsquo;t care either way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the world won&amp;rsquo;t try to hold me back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the game of life, I&amp;rsquo;m playing without an opponent. I can succeed or fail, and the only person who really gives a shit is me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most hopeful, empowering phrase I can think of: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;no one but me cares about this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means I can do what makes me happy. I can put myself first. I can write, or create, try something I&amp;rsquo;m not good at, or change my ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also means I&amp;rsquo;m free to avoid anything hard, scary, uncomfortable, or unfamiliar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or I can charge headlong into this burning building and carry out my dreams before there&amp;rsquo;s nothing left to burn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-ll-go-as-far-as-i-m-willing-to-go:545e32d7f89a68970f2c2d20a1ec1a67&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll Go as Far as I&amp;rsquo;m Willing to Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only have two obstacles in life: willpower and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one will try to stop me from learning enough to gain understanding. So really, understanding is just another test of willpower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So will I dig in, trust myself, and push until I get what I want in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or will I give up, settle in, and tell myself The World is out to get me?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing the Weekend</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/losing-the-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 17:04:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/losing-the-weekend/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When I started Copter Labs, it started a new phase of &amp;ldquo;working from anywhere&amp;rdquo; in my life. It really changed my perception of time, though, and I no longer have a concept of &amp;ldquo;the weekend&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me qualify this statement by saying this is &lt;em&gt;not a complaint&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s just something I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed as the years have gone on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tgim:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;TGIM?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I don&amp;rsquo;t know what day of the week it is. Sometimes I feel like this is a good thing, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been liberated from the shackles of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other times I feel like Norm Macdonald in &lt;em&gt;Billy Madison&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/norm-macdonald.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;What day is it? October?&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What day is it? October?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112508/&#34;&gt;Billy Madison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I get cues about the day of the week from conversations with other people; they say things like, &amp;ldquo;TGIF,&amp;rdquo; and, &amp;ldquo;Must be Monday.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;losing-the-weekend:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;Losing the Weekend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really have a weekend to speak of. Today is Saturday, and I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of migrating a dozen sites to &lt;a href=&#34;http://cptr.me/HP5GYs&#34;&gt;WPEngine&lt;/a&gt; and doing logo concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be fixing a site that got hacked and making improvements to a couple other client sites&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes this bothers me, and I get grumpy and think, &amp;ldquo;Man, I wish I could just take two days a week off.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, actually, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like having weekends back &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekends-imply-weekdays:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Weekends&amp;rdquo; Imply &amp;ldquo;Weekdays&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of having two days a week completely to myself sometimes sneaks into my brain and tricks me into thinking I&amp;rsquo;m missing out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the whole idea that those two days are mine and mine alone &lt;strong&gt;implies that the other five days are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, I have to remind myself occasionally, is the &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; reason that I chose the career path I&amp;rsquo;m currently on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-hard-work-but-it-s-my-work:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Hard Work, but It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;My Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I average a ten-hour workday. I work seven days a week. My clients call and email me at all hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll get asked how that kind of schedule is better than working 40 hours and having the rest of my time to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair question. And, honestly, sometimes I wonder the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where I always land on this issue is that, yes, what I do is &lt;em&gt;really hard work&lt;/em&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s what I love to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day I solve hard problems: I come up with a design that will support a marketing strategy that I need to define, or build a piece of software that solves a complex problem in a way that&amp;rsquo;s simple for my clients to use, or I coordinate the team at Copter Labs to tackle an impossibly large project on an impossibly short timeline to get it launched on time.[footnote]Or, more realistically, get it launched &lt;em&gt;less late&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;more late&lt;/em&gt;.[/footnote]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t think of anything I&amp;rsquo;d rather do with my time. And my track record shows it: when I was working full time at a Kinko&amp;rsquo;s, I would get off work and go home to work on a code project or design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This was my hobby before it was ever a source of income.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I didn&amp;rsquo;t love code and marketing and design as much as I do, my life would probably be a lot different than it is now, and the idea of a 70+ hour workweek would probably make me gag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do, it isn&amp;rsquo;t, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;redistributed-weekends:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;Redistributed Weekends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s also not fair to say that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a weekend at all, though. I do have time off. It&amp;rsquo;s just spread out throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can take a long lunch, or schedule an appointment at 10am. I can shut down at 3:30pm if I know I can stay up a bit later or put in a couple extra hours tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nothing-s-lost-after-all:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;Nothing&amp;rsquo;s Lost After All&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of all this, I guess, is that I should probably just shut up whenever I start to think I&amp;rsquo;m missing out. I need to keep perspective, and realize that my life is exactly the way I want it to be right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things like weekends were never important to me, or I would have made that a part of the structure of Copter Labs. And if, in the future, a weekend becomes something I actually want, I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll figure out how to have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have any &amp;ldquo;grass is greener&amp;rdquo; thoughts bringing you down? Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it: jump to the Facebook discussion and let&amp;rsquo;s air all our First World Problems publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>