<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Planning on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/planning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Planning on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 08:31:20 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Get More Done Faster: Scheduling for Maximum Productivity</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/scheduling-maximum-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 08:31:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/scheduling-maximum-productivity/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you write down everything you have to get done for you to do your job well, what does the list look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like most of us, &lt;strong&gt;your list of duties will have a wide variety of tasks that require different kinds of attention and focus.&lt;/strong&gt; We have to play multiple roles: communicator, planner, creator, administrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these roles requires different skills, and different parts of our brains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when we check email, jump into the work chat, or scan social media, we&amp;rsquo;re working in the context of communication. Research and learning are in the context of information gathering. Design, development, and writing are in the context of creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we spend a little time looking at our list of duties, we&amp;rsquo;ll start to see that &lt;strong&gt;our jobs expect us to work across multiple contexts to get things done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The variety of jobs we&amp;rsquo;re expected to do adds a new challenge for us: we have to shift gears in order to get our work done. And while we all know that constantly shifting gears slows us down in our work — in the same way we &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that we should exercise more, and we &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; seeing the movie based on a book we love will let us down — we don&amp;rsquo;t do much to fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it turns out, trying to do all the different jobs at the same time is a &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-used-to-be-terrible-at-working:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;I Used to Be Terrible at Working&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started freelancing — and worse, when I started hiring subcontractors and employees — I was &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt; at getting things done effectively. I felt tremendous pressure to be everything to everyone: if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t available on Slack, I was holding up my team; if I didn&amp;rsquo;t respond to an email within an hour, my clients would hire someone else; if I didn&amp;rsquo;t finish a project by the deadline, I&amp;rsquo;d lose the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led to a horribly &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult/&#34;&gt;unsustainable working style&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before my eyes are even open I&amp;rsquo;m reaching for my phone. The lock screen is loaded with notifications, and a knot starts to form in my stomach. &lt;em&gt;Oh Christ. Here we go again.&lt;/em&gt; Scan the email for emergencies. Check Twitter. &lt;em&gt;Only 1 new follower. Note to self: suck less as a person.&lt;/em&gt; More email. Mash out typo-riddled responses with my thumbs as I walk to get coffee — &amp;ldquo;Hey, Heidi. Nice day, huh? &amp;hellip; Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m good. You? &amp;hellip; Good to hear. Well, see you later!&amp;rdquo; — and scan calendar invites on the walk back. Open a code editor. Chat beeps. Forget what I was working on. Remember. Email beeps. Forget again. Start working on the issue in the email. Chat beeps. Remember what I was supposed to be working on. Email beeps. Forget. Look at the clock. &lt;em&gt;Goddammit, I forgot to eat again.&lt;/em&gt; Order delivery. Move to the couch. Put on &lt;em&gt;Fringe&lt;/em&gt;. Remember today&amp;rsquo;s deadline. Panic. It&amp;rsquo;s after nine so chat&amp;rsquo;s quiet; &lt;em&gt;finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll get some work done.&lt;/em&gt; Close the computer with four half-finished emails and two of three projects incomplete. Fall asleep checking email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most days, I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; a lot — I just didn&amp;rsquo;t get much *done.&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my time was spent on things that weren&amp;rsquo;t very important, and very little of my effort was spent on what I was &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to guess, about 75% of my working hours were lost to fumbling between tasks and trying to ward off the onslaught of realtime communication with all the sad determination of a cartoon character plugging holes in a sinking boat with his fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My target for each week is to spend fewer than 40 hours on the computer &lt;em&gt;total,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:computertime&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:computertime&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so I needed to be &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; better at this if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to end up jobless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/get-more-done-better-scheduling.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Rethink your schedule and get more done faster.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-productivity-supercharger-separate-tasks-by-context:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;The Productivity Supercharger: Separate Tasks by Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/philcaravaggio&#34;&gt;Phil Caravaggio&lt;/a&gt; is one of those people who optimizes everything. It&amp;rsquo;s necessary for his job — he&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.precisionnutrition.com/about/phil-caravaggio&#34;&gt;CEO of Precision Nutrition&lt;/a&gt;, a multi-million dollar company — if he&amp;rsquo;s going to live a life outside the requirements of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phil introduced me to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.entrepreneurship.org/resource-center/the-entrepreneurial-time-system-t.aspx&#34;&gt;Dan Sullivan&amp;rsquo;s time management ideas&lt;/a&gt;, which center around context. He has a trademarked approach to time management called The Entrepreneurial Time System™ that&amp;rsquo;s worth looking into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phil has implemented this system into his working style with &lt;em&gt;massive&lt;/em&gt; success. Encouraged by Phil&amp;rsquo;s experience, I decided to try out the broad strokes of the system in my own planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In simple terms: &lt;strong&gt;the best way to maximize your productivity is to separate tasks by context.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have three kinds of tasks as entrepreneurs: high-impact tasks that require all of our attention and produce big results; regenerative tasks that allow us to recharge and let our subconscious work on new solutions and ideas; and low-impact tasks that just have to be done in order to allow us to perform the high-impact tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we group these tasks into three kinds of days, we get Meaningful Work Days, Off Days, and Bullshit&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:bullshit&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:bullshit&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Days. (For fun and brevity, we&amp;rsquo;ll call this the MOB System.)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:sullivan&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:sullivan&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;meaningful-work-days-focus-exclusively-on-big-tasks:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;Meaningful Work Days: Focus Exclusively on Big Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meaningful work days are reserved for high-impact work only.&lt;/strong&gt; The act of actually writing, developing, or designing something after all the preparatory work is done. If working is an episode of &lt;em&gt;MTV Cribs&lt;/em&gt;, Meaningful Work Days are the bedroom, because, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vuEdZVV6XHw&amp;amp;t=3m0s&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is where the magic happens.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;off-days-relax-recharge-let-your-mind-wander:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;Off Days: Relax, Recharge, Let Your Mind Wander&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Off days are technology-free.&lt;/strong&gt; Or at least work-free. I aim to have at least one day a week where my computer isn&amp;rsquo;t opened at all, and I use that day to do something adventurous, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jlengstorf/status/588879515067097088&#34;&gt;heading out to a water fight&lt;/a&gt; or taking Thai cooking lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bullshit-days-prep-work-busywork-chores:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;Bullshit Days: Prep Work, Busywork, Chores&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bullshit days are for all the things that are required for us to do our important tasks,&lt;/strong&gt; but that aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily the sexy parts of the job that we look forward to. This can include email, accounting, research, outlining, setting up development environments, or collecting inspiration for a new design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-three-days-are-necessary-for-maximum-productivity:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;All Three Days Are Necessary for Maximum Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be tempting to think, &amp;ldquo;Since all the best results come from Meaningful Work Days, why don&amp;rsquo;t I &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; have Meaningful Work Days?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two problems with this kind of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-all-work-and-no-play-makes-you-suck-at-work:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;1. All Work and No Play Makes You Suck at Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that human brains just aren&amp;rsquo;t all that good at sustained periods of focus. We can cram for a while, but it&amp;rsquo;s a game of diminishing returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If we try to force focus days every day, we&amp;rsquo;ll eventually end up hurting ourselves.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/overtime-hurts-productivity/&#34;&gt;Too much time on the job results in less output at lower quality&lt;/a&gt; than if we&amp;rsquo;d kept a more balanced schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off Days create mental space where &lt;a href=&#34;http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/04/30/want-to-be-more-creative-take-a-walk/&#34;&gt;our subconscious can form new ideas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:walking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:walking&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; They create distance from the job, which allows us to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2009/05/090511180702.htm&#34;&gt;remember what&amp;rsquo;s important to us&lt;/a&gt;. They &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2014/08/schedule-a-15-minute-break-before-you-burn-out/&#34;&gt;keeps us from burning out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-hard-work-without-preparation-is-wasted:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;2. Hard Work Without Preparation Is Wasted&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very few meaningful tasks can happen in a vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To write a good article, there&amp;rsquo;s prior reading to be done, research to be collected, interviews to be conducted, and various other prep tasks that need to be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, to design something for a client, resources need to be collected, the requirements need to be gathered from the client, and marketing content needs to be approved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without doing the prep beforehand, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to do it while trying to complete the task. And there&amp;rsquo;s no better way to end up down a Wikipedia Hole and accomplish nothing than to try to do research for an article as you write it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If we want to be effective on our Meaningful Work Days, we need to have all the bullshit out of the way first.&lt;/strong&gt; Without proper prep work, a Meaningful Work Day becomes a Bullshit Day instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-split-up-your-todo-list:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;How to Split Up Your Todo List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start MOB-bing,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:ha&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:ha&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; you need to go through two critical steps. Schedule these for your first Bullshit Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write down &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; you do for your job.&lt;/strong&gt; If it happens while you&amp;rsquo;re at work, write it down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Separate your tasks into &amp;ldquo;Meaningful&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Bullshit&amp;rdquo; categories.&lt;/strong&gt; What makes a &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; impact in your job? What just needs to be done to get you to the next big task?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;meaningful-tasks:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;Meaningful Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meaningful tasks are the things that make the biggest impact,&lt;/strong&gt; and that take the most concentration. If we&amp;rsquo;re in a job we love — or even a job we just &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt;-like — these are probably the things we enjoy doing the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, meaningful tasks are writing, development, and design. I get a big emotional payoff from these jobs, and they make the biggest impact on my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bullshit-tasks:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;Bullshit Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bullshit tasks are the tasks that have to be taken care of for the meaningful work to have meaning.&lt;/strong&gt; Tasks like these aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily exciting, but they lay the groundwork for the fun stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, bullshit tasks are research, editing, email, billing, and code maintenance. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel particularly enamored with this stuff, but I know that it needs to be done so I can keep the lights on and create more opportunities for my more enjoyable tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-give-yourself-permission-and-space-to-improve-your-scheduling:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;How to Give Yourself Permission and Space to Improve Your Scheduling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The idea of taking full days away from email and chat to focus on the most meaningful work may seem impossible.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Sure, &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; can do that,&amp;rdquo; you may be thinking, &amp;ldquo;but I have [clients/coworkers/managers/customers] to consider. I can&amp;rsquo;t just &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; check email for a full day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:meaningfulmorning&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:meaningfulmorning&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt the same way before I started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, my agency was growing: I had over a hundred clients, a half-dozen employees and contractors, editors, and conference producers, and all of them had questions, problems, and needs that required my attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was &lt;em&gt;absolutely positive&lt;/em&gt; that if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t 100% available, everything would fall apart around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thankfully, my concerns were *absolutely wrong.&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how I was able to make the switch, and how you can, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-start-with-a-plan:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;1. Start with a Plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaningful work days can only happen after you get the bullshit — planning, gathering resources, asking questions — out of the way first. Otherwise, you&amp;rsquo;re dead in the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a Bullshit Day to write out all the tasks on your plate.&lt;/strong&gt; Then break them down into smaller steps and figure out what needs to be done before you can focus on the meat of the task: if you&amp;rsquo;re on the hook for an article, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to research other articles on the topic, find studies that back up your points, and write an outline before you can start writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you try to start without doing the initial prep work, trying to do meaningful work becomes more challenging and — most likely — less productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-let-everyone-know-what-s-happening:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;2. Let Everyone Know What&amp;rsquo;s Happening&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week before I started using the MOB System, I told my team that I was going to start spending three days a week on Meaningful Work Days. &lt;strong&gt;This meant on Monday, Wednesday, and Friday, everyone would be entirely unable to reach me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To prepare my team,&lt;/strong&gt; I set clear expectations that &amp;ldquo;needing my input&amp;rdquo; was not a valid excuse for missed deadlines. If they needed me, they needed to get in touch &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; my Meaningful Work Days.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:empowered&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:empowered&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To prepare my clients,&lt;/strong&gt; I created an autoresponder saying I only checked email on Tuesdays and Thursdays, and that they could route their requests to our general email if the request was urgent.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:bottleneck&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:bottleneck&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By being upfront and very clear with both my team and my clients, no one was blindsided by my changed schedule.&lt;/strong&gt; As a result, no one seemed to be particularly bothered or slowed down. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone noticed most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I hadn&amp;rsquo;t realized it before, but by making myself fully available at all times, I had actually made my team and clients &lt;em&gt;worse&lt;/em&gt; at things.&lt;/strong&gt; I was a crutch. A shortcut. As soon as I made myself less available, they stopped looking to me for approval or help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They remembered their own power and competence, and as a result they &lt;em&gt;got things done.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-remove-all-distractions:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;3. Remove All Distractions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting work done means giving yourself a period of &lt;em&gt;uninterrupted&lt;/em&gt; time during which you can focus exclusively on the task at hand.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your phone is vibrating every few seconds, or the work chat is chiming non-stop, you&amp;rsquo;re not working uninterrupted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &amp;ldquo;Do Not Disturb&amp;rdquo; mode, or turn off your network connection entirely. Turn your phone face down and silence the ringer and vibration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have trouble avoiding distracting sites, use something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rescuetime.com/ref/967986&#34;&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt; to block sites temporarily.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:blockers&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:blockers&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work in an office, find a space where you can avoid coworker interruptions. If all else fails, put on headphones and hang a sign off your back that says, &amp;ldquo;Unless the building is on fire, please don&amp;rsquo;t interrupt me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Or, even better, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/convince-your-boss-remote-work/&#34;&gt;convince your boss to let you work remotely&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However you do it, find a way to buy yourself two blocks of 2–3 hours, at least twice a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your boss has any interest in results, your extra productivity will be noticed quickly, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself being &lt;em&gt;protected&lt;/em&gt; from distractions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-use-a-timer:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;4. Use a Timer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a timer is critical, because without one we&amp;rsquo;re bound to run over our allotted time slots. I use a simple app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pocket-cup-noodle-timer/id423076135?mt=12&#34;&gt;Pocket Cup Noodle Timer&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of my work blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like 90-minute cycles because it&amp;rsquo;s supported by research into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tony-schwartz/work-life-balance-the-90_b_578671.html&#34;&gt;our bodies&amp;rsquo; natural rhythms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another popular approach with shorter working bursts is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique&#34;&gt;Pomodoro Technique&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-follow-a-simple-schedule:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;5. Follow a Simple Schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scheduling is a touchy subject for me. I hate it when people tell me how to spend my own time. So let me be very clear that &lt;strong&gt;this section is just a suggestion&lt;/strong&gt;, based on my own experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing particularly groundbreaking about the way I schedule my days. The difference, really, is in the &lt;em&gt;types of work&lt;/em&gt; being scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The secret for me has been concentrated bursts of work, punctuated with full disconnection for short breaks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the general scheduling template I follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;90-minute timed work block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15-minute technology- and work-free break&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;90-minute timed work block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60-minute lunch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;90-minute timed work block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;75-minute technology- and work-free break&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;90-minute timed work block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is 7.5 total hours of work, with 6 hours of screen time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-take-real-breaks:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;6. Take Real Breaks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/better-productivity-work-less/&#34;&gt;breaks are vital for staying productive&lt;/a&gt; because, according to science, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2014/08/schedule-a-15-minute-break-before-you-burn-out/&#34;&gt;taking breaks keeps us focused&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you use your break to take a walk, you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/04/30/want-to-be-more-creative-take-a-walk/?_r=0&#34;&gt;boost your creativity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/science/6094786/Feeling-stressed-Then-go-mow-the-lawn-claims-research.html&#34;&gt;lower your stress levels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just make sure to leave your technology behind. No phone checks, and leave your laptop closed. Take your breaks like it&amp;rsquo;s 1991 and phones are only used for talking to people far away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-when-you-re-done-be-done:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;7. When You&amp;rsquo;re Done, Be Done&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each day starts with your todo list. Let&amp;rsquo;s say your goals for the day are to clear your inbox, edit a blog post, and fix a bug in the website; when you&amp;rsquo;ve finished the list, write your todo list for tomorrow, then &lt;em&gt;stop working for the day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only need three of the four 90-minute working blocks, be okay with stopping early. &lt;strong&gt;Productivity is measured in results, not how many hours your butt is in a chair.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(More on this: &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/results-based-work/&#34;&gt;How Time-Based Management Kills Motivation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;better-productivity-means-a-little-discipline-now-and-a-lot-of-freedom-later:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;Better Productivity Means a Little Discipline Now and a Lot of Freedom Later&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the role context plays in our work — and its extreme effects on our productivity — is helpful, but it won&amp;rsquo;t make much of a difference if the knowledge isn&amp;rsquo;t applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All the knowledge in the world means jack if we don&amp;rsquo;t change after we know better.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial challenge of guarding our time can seem daunting. Our coworkers have grown used to the way we work &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; — changing that seems like it could cause tension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all fairness, it might. But only at first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a healthy workplace, both management and the workers value results.&lt;/strong&gt; By giving yourself the freedom to work optimally in a flow state, you stand the best chance of producing truly outstanding results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a win for everyone: the company sees better results, your coworkers have clear guidelines for getting in touch for help and information, and you get more done in fewer hours — which gives you the opportunity to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/work-to-live/&#34;&gt;keep your life in balance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re going to do the work either way, so why not find a way that keeps your stress low and your overtime at a minimum?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-next:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me, you’d love to get away from the crazy hours and soul-sucking demands of the &amp;ldquo;always-on&amp;rdquo; lifestyle, but you don’t feel like it’s possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was wrong. I just had to trust myself to take the first step.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t waste time like I did. You can start working less and accomplishing more today. I’ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Get the Free Guide Here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:computertime&#34;&gt;After my &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult/&#34;&gt;brush with stress-induced beardlessness&lt;/a&gt;, it became critically important to me — a literal matter of life and death, in my mind — to spend the majority of my time disconnected from a screen.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:computertime&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:bullshit&#34;&gt;I say bullshit lovingly: &amp;ldquo;I have to deal with this billing bullshit or I won&amp;rsquo;t have any money.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of thing that I someday (soon) plan to delegate entirely — once I&amp;rsquo;ve written out the process in a manner that&amp;rsquo;s bulletproof.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:bullshit&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:sullivan&#34;&gt;This is very similar to Dan Sullivan&amp;rsquo;s Focus/Buffer/Free day approach. He has a whole system built around this which is far more comprehensive than mine — my general approach is to do the least amount of structure required to get good results. If you&amp;rsquo;re better when there&amp;rsquo;s a stricter set of guidelines to follow, I highly recommend looking into Dan Sullivan&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strategiccoach.com/home.html&#34;&gt;Strategic Coach programs&lt;/a&gt;. He&amp;rsquo;s extremely good at what he does.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:sullivan&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:walking&#34;&gt;The referenced study is centered around walking, but the idea is the same: you&amp;rsquo;re away from the task at hand, and your mind doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the immediate distraction in place. As a result, your subconscious can roll the idea around and make connections that may not have happened if you were still actively focused on the task.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:walking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:ha&#34;&gt;Holy shit, that was terrible.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:ha&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:meaningfulmorning&#34;&gt;If a full day is absolutely out of the question, you can switch it to a half day. If your day starts at 9am, set the expectation that your first email check is after lunch. (Or, if you&amp;rsquo;re more effective in the afternoon, don&amp;rsquo;t check email after 2pm.) A three-hour dedicated window for your most important work won&amp;rsquo;t ruffle too many feathers, and it will have a big effect on your productivity.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:meaningfulmorning&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:empowered&#34;&gt;Once I was unavailable, my team was suddenly more empowered. I was, in effect, trusting them to make decisions without my approval or oversight. This made them significantly more efficient.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:empowered&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:bottleneck&#34;&gt;This had an unexpected benefit: clients stopped seeing me as the solution to their problems; instead, they saw the &lt;em&gt;company&lt;/em&gt; as the solution, which removed a bottleneck. When I was 100% available, clients might demand to work with me — &amp;rdquo;the boss&amp;rdquo; — instead of another member of the team; when working with me meant waiting, they were happy to work with whomever could solve the problem.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:bottleneck&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:blockers&#34;&gt;Other options exist to do the same thing, like the Chrome extensions &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/morphine/fbnpehpbojenlldmfcopeajkichnnjpo&#34;&gt;Morphine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/stayfocusd/laankejkbhbdhmipfmgcngdelahlfoji?hl=e&#34;&gt;StayFocusd&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bdf3bb94d9031e8bc4e49d3ce03f359:blockers&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Airbnb Like a Pro: Save Money &amp; Avoid Surprises</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/use-airbnb-like-a-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 07:33:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/use-airbnb-like-a-pro/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.com/c/jlengstorf&#34;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; is near the top of my list of the greatest things to happen to the world in the last ten years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sharing_economy&#34;&gt;sharing economy&lt;/a&gt; has made it incredibly easy to save money by renting other people&amp;rsquo;s unused things. Airbnb and competitors like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vrbo.com/&#34;&gt;VRBO&lt;/a&gt; do this by allowing people to rent out their extra space — from a spare room to an empty home — to other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/how-to-book-airbnb-like-a-pro.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;How to book the best Airbnb listings.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This photo is from a listing I booked in Madrid. (Thanks Enrique!)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/991697&#34;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;airbnb-a-hotel-that-doesn-t-suck:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Airbnb: A Hotel that Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Suck&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding a hotel that doesn&amp;rsquo;t smell like industrial-strength cleaner is expensive. And finding one that&amp;rsquo;s comfortable enough to live in for a long period of time is difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airbnb offers the ability to find a place to stay that feels less like a filing cabinet for tourists and more like a &lt;em&gt;home&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(If you&amp;rsquo;ve never stayed at an Airbnb before, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.com/c/jlengstorf&#34;&gt;get $25 off your first rental using this link&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the most out of Airbnb can be tricky. But it&amp;rsquo;s not hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;define-what-matters:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Define What Matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you start traveling, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to come up with a list of what you need in order to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember: &lt;strong&gt;long-term travel is very different from a weekend stay.&lt;/strong&gt; Something that might not bother you on a quick trip, such as a shaky internet connection, will be a big problem if you&amp;rsquo;re there for a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be honest with yourself about what you need in order to feel at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the list is pretty short:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want an entire place to myself — shared rooms are for very short stays only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wifi needs to be fast and reliable — without it, I can&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bed needs to be comfortable and at least queen-sized&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86:bed&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86:bed&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temperature control for the room is essential — I can&amp;rsquo;t sleep when I&amp;rsquo;m too hot or cold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The location needs to be within walking distance of both good restaurants and coffee shops with wifi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a washing machine in the unit is ideal since I only have 5 days&amp;rsquo; worth of clothing (in a pinch, I can do without this)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything else is negotiable. By figuring out what my non-negotiable items are, I can quickly remove options that would stress me out while I was there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-your-filters-appropriately:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Set Your Filters Appropriately&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airbnb has a very simple search interface, but if you&amp;rsquo;re not paying attention it may look like you&amp;rsquo;re only able to search for a date range and what kind of room you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you click the &amp;ldquo;more filters&amp;rdquo; button, though, &lt;strong&gt;you can filter by amenities&lt;/strong&gt; ranging from wireless internet and air conditioning to a gym or a doorman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/how-to-use-airbnb-filters.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Use Airbnb filters to find the best extended rental.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Airbnb&#39;s amenity filters on desktop (left) and mobile (right) are easy to use.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.com/c/jlengstorf&#34;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you like to cook? Make sure they have an oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traveling with a dog? Check the &amp;ldquo;pets allowed&amp;rdquo; filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using the filters, you can quickly exclude any listings that don&amp;rsquo;t meet your needs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;confirm-the-non-negotiables-with-the-host:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Confirm the Non-Negotiables with the Host&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After filtering down the listings that definitely aren&amp;rsquo;t what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have a few additional items on your list that you need to verify. &lt;strong&gt;Send the host a message to ask any clarifying questions or to verify information about the listing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I always verify wifi speed before committing to a place by asking the host to run a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.speedtest.net/&#34;&gt;speed test&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things aren&amp;rsquo;t selectable by the filters, such as the size of the bed, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need to check with the host about that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-a-feel-for-your-host-before-you-book:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Get a Feel for Your Host Before You Book&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve decided that a place is probably a good fit, Airbnb encourages you to book immediately — don&amp;rsquo;t do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/booking-on-airbnb-contact-host.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Use the contact host button on Airbnb to make sure the listing is good for you.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.com/c/jlengstorf&#34;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, &lt;strong&gt;use the small &amp;ldquo;contact the host&amp;rdquo; link below the &amp;ldquo;About This Listing&amp;rdquo; box to send a message to the host&lt;/strong&gt; — including the dates you want to book — without making a commitment. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to put money down before you&amp;rsquo;re sure the host is responsive and able to answer any questions you have clearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;read-the-reviews:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Read the Reviews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the person renting the space and the person who owns the space are encouraged to review each other after a stay, so you&amp;rsquo;re able to read what fellow travelers thought about the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading reviews can help you spot potential problems before you book.&lt;/strong&gt; Keep an eye out for red flags like issues contacting the host, problems with amenities that you care about, or comments about the general neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of reviews (and cumulative ratings) are also a good indicator of whether you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with someone who frequently has renters or if it&amp;rsquo;s someone who may lack experience in dealing with guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed with both types of people and enjoyed the space, but there&amp;rsquo;s something to be said about the comfort of booking a listing with dozens of five-star reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;find-your-ideal-hotel-to-home-ratio:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Find Your Ideal Hotel-to-Home Ratio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain aspects of the hotel experience that are really pleasant: knowing your room will be cleaned each day, having fresh towels, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you ask for it ahead of time, you can often arrange to have the good parts of a hotel-like experience in your Airbnb rental.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to be aware of is cleaning. A lot of rentals don&amp;rsquo;t have a cleaning service, so if you&amp;rsquo;re staying for longer than a couple weeks, you&amp;rsquo;ll either have to clean it yourself or work out a deal with the owner to provide cleaning services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually ask if there&amp;rsquo;s a cleaning service, and if not, I&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;strong&gt;arrange with the landlord to have the place cleaned every week or two&lt;/strong&gt; while I&amp;rsquo;m staying there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t do this at my first couple locations, and it sucked. I hate mopping floors and changing sheets, so I&amp;rsquo;m more than willing to pay a little extra to have it done for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;speed-things-up-with-a-message-template:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Speed Things Up with a Message Template&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;save time by creating a template for contacting hosts&lt;/strong&gt; that introduces yourself and communicates your non-negotiable items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, here&amp;rsquo;s the message I send to each host before I book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend, Marisa, and I have been looking at your listing, and we love it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are spending all of 2015 traveling around the world, renting Airbnb apartments in the cities we want to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re both so grateful that people like you have opened your homes to travelers, because without you, our adventure wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible. So thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re very interested in renting your apartment, but I wanted to ask a couple questions first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we both work from our computers and will be working while we travel. Since our jobs rely on an internet connection, could you please let us know how fast and reliable the wifi connection is at your apartment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure how fast it is, could you please search Google for &amp;ldquo;speed test by ookla&amp;rdquo; and click the first result? On that site, click the &amp;ldquo;Begin Test&amp;rdquo; button to check the connection&amp;rsquo;s speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, since we&amp;rsquo;re planning to stay for an extended period, we&amp;rsquo;re interested in negotiating additional cleaning fees so we could have the apartment serviced every two weeks. Would that be a possibility?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ ADD A PERSONAL NOTE ABOUT THE AREA AND/OR THE LISTING HERE ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again. We&amp;rsquo;ll look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason &amp;amp; Marisa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;save-more-money:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Save (More) Money&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you pay $1,500/month in rent, that&amp;rsquo;s about $50/night to stay in your own apartment. (This, of course, isn&amp;rsquo;t even the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/cost-of-living-remotely/&#34;&gt;full price you pay to live in your apartment&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hotel, by contrast, is probably going to cost at least $100/night unless it&amp;rsquo;s, well, &lt;em&gt;gross.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airbnb has never failed to find me a place to stay that was cheaper than a hotel room, and I&amp;rsquo;ve nearly always found a place that cost less per night than my rent in Portland.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it turns out you can save even more by being on top of your booking and taking advantage of Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s price breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;longer-stays-cost-less:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Longer Stays Cost Less&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Airbnb shows the cost of a listing per night. For example, at the time of writing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/5234548&#34;&gt;this listing in Atlanta&lt;/a&gt; costs $82/night if you book it for six nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;if you book the same listing for a week, the cost drops&lt;/strong&gt; to $71/night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you book for a month, the cost drops further&lt;/strong&gt; to $51/night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all Airbnb listings have breaks for longer stays, but when you search for longer stays, the ones that offer breaks are easy to spot by their lower prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can stay put for a month, you stand to save a bundle by taking advantage of Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s price breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;book-way-in-advance-for-better-cheap-options:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Book Way in Advance for Better Cheap Options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s only one of each place, so when it&amp;rsquo;s booked, you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nice listings with low prices will be the first to go, so if you&amp;rsquo;re sure of your travel plans way ahead of time, you should &lt;strong&gt;book early to make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve got your pick of the best locations.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;airbnb-is-the-perfect-solution-for-extended-travel:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86&#34;&gt;Airbnb Is the Perfect Solution for Extended Travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one wants to spend all their time living in hotel rooms. Using Airbnb is a great way to live like a local would — after all, you&amp;rsquo;re borrowing a local&amp;rsquo;s home — and avoid the temporary feeling that can lead to homesickness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, in combination with the potential to save &lt;em&gt;a lot of money&lt;/em&gt;, is why I&amp;rsquo;m convinced &lt;strong&gt;Airbnb is the perfect tool for &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/how-to-become-location-independent/&#34;&gt;location-independent&lt;/a&gt; workers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Don&amp;rsquo;t forget: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.com/c/jlengstorf&#34;&gt;sign up for Airbnb with this link get $25 toward your first rental&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86:bed&#34;&gt;I travel with my partner Marisa, and we found out the hard way that one of us — not naming names — is a sleep-puncher.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:91cf14a7277c97ff0685dd4a8db8db86:bed&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Essentials: How to Set Up a Mobile Phone Abroad</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-mobile-phone-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 06:44:03 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-mobile-phone-abroad/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Since having a mobile phone is now more or less a requirement for being a functional member of society, it&amp;rsquo;s important to find a way to get your hands on a phone while abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key benefit to having a working phone is access to wireless data, which is invaluable when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to navigate a new city where the street signs aren&amp;rsquo;t in English, or if you need to quickly look up how to say &amp;ldquo;coconut oil&amp;rdquo; in Thai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the benefits of data, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to receive calls and texts from your friends and family in your home country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a slightly confusing setup — I&amp;rsquo;ll explain thoroughly, I promise — you can keep a local number while abroad, complete with text and picture message, while also setting up a local phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s all &lt;em&gt;way cheaper&lt;/em&gt; than a mobile contract in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/how-to-set-up-a-mobile-phone-abroad.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;How to set up a mobile phone while traveling abroad.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-an-unlocked-phone-with-a-sim-card-slot:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Buy an Unlocked Phone with a SIM Card Slot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you&amp;rsquo;ve got your phone numbers and forwarding worked out, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a phone that works in all the countries you want to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most US mobile carriers subsidize the cost of phones with contracts, the phones they sell are locked — this makes them useless if they&amp;rsquo;re not on that carrier&amp;rsquo;s network and plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To avoid insane roaming fees, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to buy an unlocked phone.&lt;/strong&gt; When you see the cost of an unlocked phone, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably shit your pants — just remember that when you &amp;ldquo;buy&amp;rdquo; a phone with a contract, you&amp;rsquo;re also committing to about $1,200 in phone bills over the next year, so a $600 phone isn&amp;rsquo;t actually that expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure the phone you buy allows you to swap out the SIM card, and that it will work on GSM networks. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what that means, do a search for the phone model you want to buy and whether or not it works in the countries you want to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1GyjrWh&#34;&gt;purchased an unlocked iPhone 6&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s worked in the US, Europe, and Southeast Asia without any issues so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-a-prepaid-sim-card-once-you-land:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Buy a Prepaid SIM Card Once You Land&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I found out how cheap it was to have a prepaid SIM in other countries, I spent a half-hour ranting about how criminal the mobile carrier racket is in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve left the United States, I have spent less than $40/month on prepaid voice/text/data plans.&lt;/strong&gt; Usually much less.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:uk&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:uk&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick search will point you to several discussions about the best SIM for whichever country you&amp;rsquo;re headed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we&amp;rsquo;ve used Three in both Italy and the UK, Yoigo in Spain, and TrueMove H in Thailand. Italy has been the most expensive so far at €35 for a month, and I think that was mainly because I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what the hell I was doing and bought a more expensive package than I actually needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way I&amp;rsquo;ve found to get a SIM is to &lt;strong&gt;go directly to a retail store&lt;/strong&gt; for whichever carrier you choose, then &lt;strong&gt;find the prepaid plan that suits your needs.&lt;/strong&gt; (We&amp;rsquo;ve been able to find brochures in English almost everywhere, as well as people working the counters who are able to speak English well enough to get us set up.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A word of advice: &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t leave the store until you&amp;rsquo;ve verified that you can get online, make a call, and send a text message.&lt;/strong&gt; You probably won&amp;rsquo;t run into any issues, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to find out an hour later that a step was missed — and you &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t want to try and explain what&amp;rsquo;s happened to a different employee whose English is about as good as your Italian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;having-a-local-number-helps:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Having a Local Number Helps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A benefit that I didn&amp;rsquo;t initially consider when getting SIM cards is the bonus of having a local number wherever you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Barcelona, we made friends with some locals, and being able to shoot them texts without anyone spending a fortune was very handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In London, calling local businesses to ask if they had something we needed was an enormous time-saver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It won&amp;rsquo;t come up often, but when it does, it&amp;rsquo;s great to know you&amp;rsquo;ve got that covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-data-plans-are-cheap-if-you-re-reasonable:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;The Data Plans Are Cheap — If You&amp;rsquo;re Reasonable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data usage is usually pretty cheap, and the allowances are reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, &amp;ldquo;normal usage&amp;rdquo; consists of getting directions and looking up places in Google Maps, checking various social networks once or twice a day, sending a few photos to my friends via MMS, and occasionally asking Google to settle debates.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:debates&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:debates&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re live-streaming everything you do through Periscope, your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;staying-connected-to-your-us-based-friends-and-family:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Staying Connected to Your US-Based Friends and Family&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure your loved ones don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay international calling rates to get in touch with you, you can leverage Google and Skype to make sure you can still receive calls — just like you were still in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-a-google-voice-number:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Get a Google Voice Number&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re in the US, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/googlevoice/about.html&#34;&gt;Google Voice&lt;/a&gt; is a simple option to give yourself a US-based number that friends can call or text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a Google Voice number, you can call or text your friends right from the Gmail app, as well as from the Hangouts app. &lt;strong&gt;Your incoming calls and texts can be forwarded to any US-based phone number&lt;/strong&gt; — I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how to work around this a bit later — or to your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re also able to set up voicemail with custom greetings, call blocking, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you use your computer (or the Hangouts app on wifi) &lt;strong&gt;you can make calls and send texts from your Google Voice number for free.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great way to make sure your family and friends don&amp;rsquo;t have to contact you through an app — my parents, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, greatly appreciate not having to learn what the hell a WhatsApp is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-up-a-skype-number-for-call-forwarding:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Set Up a Skype Number for Call Forwarding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To work around Google Voice&amp;rsquo;s US-only call-forwarding restriction, &lt;strong&gt;you can get a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skype.com/en/features/&#34;&gt;Skype number&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for $60/year, which allows you to forward the calls to international numbers in most countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you&amp;rsquo;ve set up the Skype number, &lt;strong&gt;set your Google Voice number to forward to it.&lt;/strong&gt; Turn off any of Skype&amp;rsquo;s extra features, like voicemail, to make sure that the call goes through to your phone and your Google Voice voicemail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this is set up, you just have to remember to set the Skype number to forward to your local number wherever you&amp;rsquo;re staying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;staying-connected-is-easier-and-cheaper-than-you-might-think:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e&#34;&gt;Staying Connected Is Easier (and Cheaper) than You Might Think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was concerned before I left that I&amp;rsquo;d have a really difficult and expensive time trying to stay connected abroad. I was concerned I&amp;rsquo;d need to ration my data usage, tell my friends to stop texting me, and pay a fortune to call home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with a little bit of legwork up front, it turns out that &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll actually &lt;em&gt;save a shitload of money&lt;/em&gt; this year over what I was spending to keep a phone through Verizon in the US.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After seeing the ease of setting it up, and the savings of going prepaid, I&amp;rsquo;m a believer; I&amp;rsquo;ll be a hard sell to ever get a mobile contract again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:uk&#34;&gt;In London I put £15 on a SIM from Three and — after normal use — still had £5 of credit left when I headed to the airport a month later.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:uk&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:debates&#34;&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to stop this. Google ruins &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/funny-stuff/the-fine-art-of-bullshit-c09f7bbb391e&#34;&gt;the art of bullshit&lt;/a&gt;, which is half the reason it&amp;rsquo;s fun to debate things over dinner in the first place.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:05de7e06ea2ff2f01726437f01c6663e:debates&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Essentials: Understanding How Visas Work</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-travel-visas-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 04:54:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-travel-visas-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, travel visas haven&amp;rsquo;t crossed your mind at all as you&amp;rsquo;ve been preparing to leave the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only a month or two out from my flight out of the US — well after I initially booked the ticket — that I realized I needed to worry about visas. Since I&amp;rsquo;d never left the United States for more than a few weeks before, the idea of what travel visas are and why anyone might need a travel visa just hadn&amp;rsquo;t occurred to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article assumes you&amp;rsquo;re in the same boat and have never really given much thought to travel visas. In it, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss &lt;strong&gt;what travel visas are, the methods I&amp;rsquo;m using to travel from country to country on tourist visas, and visa options for travelers who want to stay in a country longer than a few months.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-travel-visas:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d&#34;&gt;What Are Travel Visas?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To hugely simplify the concept, a visa is a kind of permission slip from a foreign government to be in the country. An international hall pass, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you can legally enter a foreign country, you need to obtain a visa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/how-travel-visas-work.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;how travel visas work&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hjl/101443399/&#34;&gt;hjl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, this is easy: when you&amp;rsquo;re getting a tourist visa, for example, an agent from the country your entering will simply ask why you&amp;rsquo;re there — maybe asking a few questions about your reasons for being there and when you&amp;rsquo;re leaving — before stamping your passport with a tourist visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other cases, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty complicated: to get a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exteriores.gob.es/Consulados/MONTREAL/en/InformacionParaExtranjeros/Documents/Visados%20de%20larga%20duracion/Non-lucrative%20residence%20visa.pdf&#34;&gt;non-lucrative residence visa in Spain&lt;/a&gt;, for example, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to submit a criminal history, doctor&amp;rsquo;s note, your fingerprints, a valid passport, and an application form (and fee) — all verified with something called an apostille.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d:apostille&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d:apostille&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visas all carry certain restrictions on what you can and cannot do while in the country. They&amp;rsquo;re all valid for a limited period of time, which varies widely depending on the country; some visas are only valid for a month, while others are valid for a year or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to do some research before each trip to make sure you know what kind of visa you&amp;rsquo;ll need to obtain to make sure you stay out of trouble while traveling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tourist-visas-are-the-way-to-go:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d&#34;&gt;Tourist Visas Are the Way to Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my purposes, tourist visas are the best solution for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am not working &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; the countries I visit.&lt;/strong&gt; I make all my money from US- and Canadian-based companies, who pay into a US-based bank account. My physical location has no bearing on the work I do.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d:prohelp&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d:prohelp&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m in Europe or Asia, I&amp;rsquo;m a tourist.&lt;/strong&gt; I take no money out of the economy, but I do put a fair amount into it by paying for short-term rentals, food, and entertainment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I like to move every 30–90 days.&lt;/strong&gt; After I&amp;rsquo;ve been in a city for a month or two, I find myself slipping into routines instead of exploring — when I hit this point, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on and rekindle my sense of adventure in a new city.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since I rarely want to stay in a country longer than a tourist visa would allow, tourist visas make the most sense for me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also wary of staying in any country long enough to give them a reason to expect me to pay taxes there. I&amp;rsquo;m confused enough by trying to pay one federal government — if I can help it, I&amp;rsquo;d prefer not to add another to my todo list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;not-all-tourist-visas-are-automatic:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d&#34;&gt;Not All Tourist Visas Are Automatic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some countries — Thailand and Vietnam, for example — you can&amp;rsquo;t just show up and get a passport stamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In order to stay in Thailand for over 30 days, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thaiembassy.com/thailand/thailand-tourist-visa.php&#34;&gt;apply for a visa&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This is really easy, though: just find a Thai embassy in whatever country you&amp;rsquo;re in and fill out the tourist visa form. There&amp;rsquo;s a small fee — about $30 — and you have to leave your passport overnight. When I applied, I was in and out within 30 minutes when I applied and when I picked up the visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Vietnam, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to &lt;a href=&#34;http://vietnamembassy-usa.org/consular/visa-application-process&#34;&gt;apply for a visa&lt;/a&gt; ahead of time as well. I haven&amp;rsquo;t done this yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m planning to head to Vietnam once it starts getting cold in Europe. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve read, it&amp;rsquo;s similar to the Thai visa: &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not hard, but you have to jump through a few hoops.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m thinking I&amp;rsquo;ll deal with the hassle of figuring out how to get a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tripadvisor.com/Travel-g293921-c148049/Vietnam:Faq.Visa.On.Arrival.Voa.html&#34;&gt;visa-on-arrival arranged&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-aware-of-the-schengen-area:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d&#34;&gt;Be Aware of the Schengen Area&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another surprise to me when I first left was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schengen_Area&#34;&gt;Schengen Area&lt;/a&gt;, which is a collection of 26 countries in Europe that share one entry visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A tourist visa in the Schengen Area is good for 90 days in a 180-day period.&lt;/strong&gt; This means you can only spend 3 of every 6 months in the Schengen Area before you&amp;rsquo;d have to apply for a longer visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to use a tourist visa in Europe, be &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; sure you&amp;rsquo;re planning to move between countries in a way that won&amp;rsquo;t get you in visa trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had originally thought that I&amp;rsquo;d fly into Italy, stay for a week, head to Spain (new visa), then jump over to France (new visa), and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, Italy, Spain, and France are all part of the Schengen Area, so after I landed in Italy, I had 90 days to spend there before I needed to head for a country outside of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Schengen Area makes European travel tricky, but not impossible. The UK and Ireland, for example, are not part of the Schengen Area, so you could spend 90 days in Rome, then head to Dublin for three months before jumping back to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;options-for-staying-longer:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d&#34;&gt;Options for Staying Longer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in staying longer in one place than a tourist visa allows, there are options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, since I&amp;rsquo;ve never applied for any long-stay visas, I can&amp;rsquo;t speak to the process, cost, or difficulty of obtaining these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over some of the methods I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about and share links to articles by people who have actually gone through the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;teaching-english-as-a-foreign-language:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d&#34;&gt;Teaching English as a Foreign Language&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A common option for native English speakers who want to live in a foreign country is to teach English as a foreign language (TEFL).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know a couple people who are doing this, and it seems to be a great way to go abroad if you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable making a reasonably large time commitment for what is generally a pretty low wage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a large TEFL community on Reddit, and they&amp;rsquo;ve put together a pretty &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/TEFL/wiki/gettingstarted/dummiesguide&#34;&gt;comprehensive guide to getting into TEFL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;becoming-a-student:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d&#34;&gt;Becoming a Student&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Student visas, obviously, are for students.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard rumors of travelers enrolling at &amp;ldquo;schools&amp;rdquo; that are essentially fronts for obtaining student visas semi-legally. That sounds like some shady shit to me, so I never looked into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not actually a student, this visa probably isn&amp;rsquo;t the best idea. If you are a student, look into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://travel.state.gov/content/visas/english/study-exchange/student.html&#34;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt; for getting one in the country you want to study in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-options-for-long-term-visas:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d&#34;&gt;Other Options for Long-Term Visas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not interested in attending classes as a teacher or a student, you still have a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A popular long-term visa I keep hearing about is the &lt;strong&gt;non-lucrative residence visa in Spain&lt;/strong&gt;. This visa is for anyone who can prove they can afford to remain in the country for an extended period of time without working — having at least $30,000 in the bank is a good idea, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard. While I don&amp;rsquo;t personally know anyone who&amp;rsquo;s applied for this visa, I did enjoy reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://bucking-the-trend.com/apply-non-lucrative-residence-visa-spain-us-citizen/&#34;&gt;Jed&amp;rsquo;s retelling of the application process&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this seems like the right option for you, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exteriores.gob.es/Consulados/SANFRANCISCO/en/ConsularServices/Documents/visas/NonLucrative.pdf&#34;&gt;here are the guidelines for submitting your application&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option is the &lt;strong&gt;residence permit for freelance or self-employment in Germany&lt;/strong&gt;. This one requires residence in Germany, so that may be a deal-breaker. If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to live in Germany, however, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://service.berlin.de/dienstleistung/305249/en/&#34;&gt;start the application process&lt;/a&gt;. For a write-up by someone who&amp;rsquo;s gone through the process, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@imcatnoone/how-to-get-your-german-freelance-visa-without-losing-your-sanity-8fa68b39431a&#34;&gt;check out Cat Noone&amp;rsquo;s post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re hoping to stay in the Schengen Area for longer than 90 days, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nomadicmatt.com/travel-blogs/how-to-legally-stay-in-europe-for-more-than-90-days/&#34;&gt;a few loopholes may exist&lt;/a&gt;, but it sounds like general consensus is that it&amp;rsquo;s just easier to use a tourist visa in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-your-own-research:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d&#34;&gt;Do Your Own Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with anything you read on the internet, your results may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure to verify any information you found in this article&lt;/strong&gt; — and any article that&amp;rsquo;s not directly from a visa-issuing authority in the country you want to visit — before making travel plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visas aren&amp;rsquo;t hard, but you need to know what you&amp;rsquo;re getting into.&lt;/strong&gt; Read the official government sites to make sure you know the requirements and time limits, then speak to an expert if you&amp;rsquo;re not 100% sure how to get your visas sorted out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don&amp;rsquo;t let this intimidate you. I was nervous at first, but having gone through the process I can assure you it&amp;rsquo;s less painful than airport security can be in the US. You&amp;rsquo;ll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d:apostille&#34;&gt;When I first heard about this, I pictured walking down a drafty, torch-lined hallway toward a heavy iron door, behind which a man — sitting behind a large desk, writing with a quill that he dipped in a bottle of something frighteningly similar in color to blood, his face hidden beneath the hood of a heavy, dark cloak — would rasp at me in a voice dripping with evil, &amp;ldquo;Who dares disturb the apostille?!&amp;rdquo; The truth, unfortunately, is far less interesting. (It&amp;rsquo;s like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apostille_Convention&#34;&gt;super-notarization&lt;/a&gt;.)
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d:apostille&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d:prohelp&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning that this lifestyle is currently new enough to fall through cracks in the way countries define work, and this leaves a lot of room for interpretation. I&amp;rsquo;m not an accountant, so you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take my word for any of this. Talk to a professional if you&amp;rsquo;re unsure; &amp;ldquo;Jason told me this would work&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t going to hold up in court.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5f56e2b73d91b89eced16bdc0062dd9d:prohelp&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Tell Your Loved Ones You&#39;re Leaving</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-tell-your-loved-ones-youre-leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 02:07:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-tell-your-loved-ones-youre-leaving/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve made up your mind to spend an extended period of time traveling, and figured out how to make your income location-independent, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to face one of the toughest challenges you&amp;rsquo;re likely to come up against: &lt;strong&gt;figuring out how to tell your family and friends you&amp;rsquo;re leaving.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;people-are-resistant-to-things-they-don-t-understand:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8&#34;&gt;People Are Resistant to Things They Don&amp;rsquo;t Understand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common reaction to things we don&amp;rsquo;t understand is fear. And typically, &lt;strong&gt;fear leads us to assume that the thing that scares us is bad.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a very good chance that going nomadic is going to be &lt;em&gt;completely fucking foreign&lt;/em&gt; to nearly everyone you know, and reactions will range from the lukewarm&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:lukewarm&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:lukewarm&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to the outright hostile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom, who has spent the majority of her life in Montana, worried that I&amp;rsquo;d be kidnapped by terrorists, killed by food poisoning, locked up in a foreign prison for being &amp;ldquo;too American&amp;rdquo; — her list of potential calamities was virtually endless.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:realmom&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:realmom&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But really, my mom is excited&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:mom&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:mom&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/how-to-tell-friends-and-family-youre-leaving.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;How to tell friends and family you&amp;amp;#039;re leaving the country.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;educate-whenever-possible:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8&#34;&gt;Educate Whenever Possible&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the people we&amp;rsquo;re closest to, most of the objections are coming from a good — albeit misguided — place. They worry we&amp;rsquo;re putting ourselves at risk in some way, and they&amp;rsquo;re trying to caution us against making mistakes that could haunt us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our loved ones will likely make objections based on their fears about world travel and what other countries are like. To combat this, be ready to present evidence that proves their concerns are unfounded.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they&amp;rsquo;re worried you can&amp;rsquo;t afford to travel, show them how it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/cost-of-living-remotely/&#34;&gt;significantly cheaper to live abroad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they bring up safety, let them know you&amp;rsquo;re about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_intentional_homicide_rate&#34;&gt;60% less likely to get murdered&lt;/a&gt; anywhere in Europe or Asia as you are in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if they talk about stability — well, you&amp;rsquo;re not exactly looking for the kind of stability they&amp;rsquo;re pushing on you, so you&amp;rsquo;ll just have to agree to disagree for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;remind-them-that-nothing-is-forever:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8&#34;&gt;Remind Them that Nothing Is Forever&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because humans are &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_cognitive_biases&#34;&gt;horrible at being rational&lt;/a&gt;, we tend to assume that every decision we make will affect us forever. This, of course, is completely untrue — but we need to remind our family and friends of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m traveling now, and I love it. At the moment I can&amp;rsquo;t see an end to my travels, because my list of places to explore seems to be getting &lt;em&gt;longer&lt;/em&gt; as I go along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I remember a time not that long ago when I believed I&amp;rsquo;d be a touring musician forever. I remember when I told myself I&amp;rsquo;d live in Portland forever.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:portland&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:portland&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in every case, I grew and gained experience, my goals evolved, and I found that what I thought I wanted forever was really just what I wanted for that period in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this period of my life, I want to travel. I fully expect that in the future — whether that&amp;rsquo;s in two weeks or twenty years — I will decide that I&amp;rsquo;m ready to stop traveling and be in once place for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every plan, no matter how permanent it may feel at the time, will evolve over time and — most likely — change entirely as our experience shifts where we place importance in our lives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This decision to travel isn&amp;rsquo;t you saying goodbye to your family and friends forever. It&amp;rsquo;s just you traveling for now, and — if you remind them that nothing is forever — they should support you doing the thing that feels right to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;suggest-get-togethers-in-fun-places:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8&#34;&gt;Suggest Get-Togethers in Fun Places&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t visit my parents often. It&amp;rsquo;s not because I don&amp;rsquo;t love my parents — I do — but rather because my parents live in Whitefish, Montana, which is a small town without much to offer unless you&amp;rsquo;re going fishing, hunting, or skiing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left Montana to get away from the snow and the boredom I was dealing with there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to love when my parents would visit me in Portland, though. I always had a list of things to do that was too long for the few days they&amp;rsquo;d be in town, and I&amp;rsquo;d always look forward to their next visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re traveling, you can easily put yourself in locations that are ideal for spending quality time together with loved ones.&lt;/strong&gt; If you would usually take a week to hang out with your family each year, why not spend that week on a beach in Costa Rica?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;or-plan-to-visit-home:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8&#34;&gt;Or Plan to Visit Home&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to take advantage of the Foreign Earned Income Exclusion for your taxes, you have about a month each year to be home, which is actually more time than I usually spend with my family in an average year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For those of us who don&amp;rsquo;t live in the same town as our parents, it&amp;rsquo;s likely that we could spend &lt;em&gt;exactly the same amount of time together&lt;/em&gt; each year while traveling the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;remember-that-the-world-is-flat:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8&#34;&gt;Remember That the World Is Flat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video calling has changed the world in a way I didn&amp;rsquo;t fully grasp until I was on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apps like Google Hangouts, Skype, Facetime, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://talky.io/&#34;&gt;Talky&lt;/a&gt; have created a world where talking to someone face-to-face is easy no matter where in the world you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the odd phone call to friends and family, I usually jump on a video call with someone I care about once a week or so to catch up. As a result, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel disconnected or lonely — it&amp;rsquo;s strikingly similar to the way I used to meet a friend for coffee when we were in the same city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your loved ones won&amp;rsquo;t miss you &lt;em&gt;nearly&lt;/em&gt; as much if you set up regular video chats.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have people in your life who struggle technically, sit with them before you leave to show them how the calls work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;give-them-a-little-tough-love:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8&#34;&gt;Give Them a Little Tough Love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes — despite all the pushback from those close to you — you just have to do it anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even if it&amp;rsquo;s tough, sometime you&amp;rsquo;ll just have to sit someone down and say, &amp;ldquo;I love you, and I know you&amp;rsquo;re not comfortable with what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, but this is what I believe is the best thing for me. I need to see this through.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trust-yourself-to-know-what-s-best-for-you:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8&#34;&gt;Trust Yourself to Know What&amp;rsquo;s Best for You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life boils down to our pursuit of happiness, and very few people will be truly unhappy to see you doing something you love.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:unhappy&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:unhappy&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know that you want to give the digital nomad lifestyle a try, stick to your guns and be willing to defend it to your family and friends. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to understand completely, or even to fully agree with what you&amp;rsquo;re doing — they just need to know you still want them in your lives and that you&amp;rsquo;re not going to disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they see how happy you are in your new lifestyle, they&amp;rsquo;ll be hard-pressed not to understand your excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hell, I&amp;rsquo;m still holding out hope that my dad will be convinced to leave the United States and visit me in Europe next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if I can get my dad to entertain the idea of a trans-Atlantic flight to a country where smoked brisket isn&amp;rsquo;t readily available, well&amp;hellip;I believe anything is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:lukewarm&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip;great. I always wanted to travel, but, y&amp;rsquo;know, I have &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/&#34;&gt;The Future&lt;/a&gt; to think about.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:lukewarm&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:realmom&#34;&gt;I give my mom a lot of shit because she tends to worry quite a bit. She&amp;rsquo;s got no problem with me traveling the world — just don&amp;rsquo;t tell her I&amp;rsquo;m not wearing the flak jacket she bought me.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:realmom&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:mom&#34;&gt;Jason&amp;rsquo;s mom here. No I&amp;rsquo;m not. Please come home soon.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:mom&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:portland&#34;&gt;This would have been shortly after I first tasted the foie gras bon bons at Le Pigeon, I believe.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:portland&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:unhappy&#34;&gt;And, honestly, if someone is unhappy because you pursued your own happiness, how much value are they really adding to your life?
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5191c1869c72dd371cbec536f4c6bdf8:unhappy&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Have It All: Living for Now AND Later</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 01:01:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of guilt packed into our culture. We hear phrases like &amp;ldquo;hard work and sacrifice&amp;rdquo; tossed around to describe virtuous lifestyles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re trained to feel ashamed of having a good time.&lt;/strong&gt; We can only allowed to enjoy ourselves for an allotted number of vacation days — any further enjoyment is a sure sign that you don&amp;rsquo;t give a fuck about The Future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, would you like to come on this trip to Costa Rica with us?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, I can&amp;rsquo;t. I have The Future to consider, you know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what good is that sacrifice, really? &lt;strong&gt;Does the decision to suffer today for the sake of The Future actually result in a better future?&lt;/strong&gt; Or are we just depriving ourselves because we&amp;rsquo;ve been told it&amp;rsquo;s the right thing to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sacrifices-make-sense-sometimes:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Sacrifices Make Sense — Sometimes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly some sacrifice is a good thing. But how do we tell the difference between a sacrifice that will benefit us and a sacrifice that just makes us miserable for no reason?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ramen.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;ramen&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  #thestruggleisreal

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was building my business, I took a contract that barely covered my living expenses, quit my day job, and bought a pallet of ramen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the decision to sacrifice my short-term comfort for the potential to significantly improve my life in the long run. &lt;strong&gt;I felt comfortable making this sacrifice because there was a concrete goal, a timeline, and a measurable outcome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be self-employed (concrete goal). I had three months (timeline) on the contract to either make a livable wage (measurable outcome) — or decide I would be better off hunting for a new employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By making this sacrifice, I was able to make the jump from moonlighting as a web designer to working as a full-time freelancer — and this has paid me back many times over since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;base-decisions-on-tangible-criteria:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Base Decisions on Tangible Criteria&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should all be aware of what our later years will hold. But we &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; be blindly denying ourselves enjoyment today for the sake of The Future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid making unnecessary sacrifices for The Future — and to avoid making decisions that could negatively affect our &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; future — &lt;strong&gt;we need to define what The Future actually looks like.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a standard of living, an &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/calculator/retirement/retirement-need/&#34;&gt;exact dollar amount&lt;/a&gt;, or whatever you decide your future will require — it just needs to be concrete. Make sure it&amp;rsquo;s not, &amp;ldquo;I want to be able to live comfortably.&amp;rdquo; What does &amp;ldquo;comfortably&amp;rdquo; mean?&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you defined your future as requiring, say, $60,000/year for retirement, and you want to retire at 67, then you&amp;rsquo;d need to put a plan in place to save at least $1.5M between now and your 67th birthday.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By creating a plan, you now have a concrete goal with a timeline and a measurable outcome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-whatever-doesn-t-interfere-with-the-plan:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Do Whatever Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Interfere with the Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a real plan, anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect it is fair game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to go on a trip, see a concert, or blow off work for the afternoon to visit your friends? Do it, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s not to the detriment of your plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we have a clear plan, the guilt and uncertainty associated with The Future goes away. We can now test the things we want now against the things we want later — and I think we&amp;rsquo;ll all be shocked by how rarely the two are opposed to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/crippling-fear-of-uncertainty.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Sorry I couldn&amp;#39;t come with you, but I have my crippling fear of uncertainty to consider, you know.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This is what we&#39;re saying when we turn down the things we want &#34;for The Future&#34;.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keep-the-future-in-context:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Keep the Future in Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Without context, The Future is just a foggy, looming uncertainty.&lt;/strong&gt; It has nothing to do with our comfort or wealth in years to come — it&amp;rsquo;s just a nagging fear that we don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s next, so maybe we should hedge our bets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d be better off calling it The Crippling Fear of Uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, would you like to come on this trip to Costa Rica with us?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, I can&amp;rsquo;t. I have my Crippling Fear of Uncertainty to consider, you know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living the lives we want to live today is certainly a threat to The Future. But &lt;strong&gt;to a well-considered plan for the future, our happiness is no threat at all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have to ask ourselves: are we holding back because this sacrifice will have a measurable impact on our plans for the future? Or are we just scared of The Future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;For me, that might mean a house made out of hammocks where I&amp;rsquo;ll be fed various morsels of imported cheese by an extremely well-trained octopus. Your &amp;ldquo;comfortable&amp;rdquo; living situation may vary.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;This is an incredibly simplified approach to saving money for retirement, and it&amp;rsquo;s most likely wrong. Please do research and talk to a professional about your own retirement plans.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>