<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entertainment on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/entertainment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entertainment on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 10:07:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/entertainment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Completely Alone at a Table of Friends</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/fomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 10:07:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/fomo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So these three statisticians go duck hunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;ve got the shotguns and the duck calls and the waders and the decoys, and they head out into a marsh and wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After a little while, they see some ducks, and the first statistician stands up to take a shot. He shoots — &lt;em&gt;BLAM&lt;/em&gt; — but the duck keeps flying; he&amp;rsquo;s missed high by about a foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The second statistician is ready, and he takes a second shot — &lt;em&gt;BLAM&lt;/em&gt; — but the duck&amp;rsquo;s still flying; the shot missed low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The third statistician jumps up and&amp;hellip; he, uhhh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking at my phone now. My friend&amp;rsquo;s mother just liked one of my photos on Facebook. How anticlimactic. She likes &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; photo I post, so it&amp;rsquo;s kind of like getting a participation trophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I look up, the table is staring at me expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; I ask.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phones-and-toddlers-are-dicks:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;Phones (and Toddlers) Are Dicks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/kids-are-assholes.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Kid being an asshole&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  &#34;Oh, you still needed this? ...yeah, I&#39;m not sorry.&#34;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/gallery/sO1Ok&#34;&gt;chaselye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends are getting to the age where some of them are married and have kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the kids are old enough to talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they do. Frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND:&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at remodeling the basement, but we think we&amp;rsquo;re going to—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY VOICE:&lt;/strong&gt; MOM MOM MOM THERE&amp;rsquo;S A DOG MOM DID YOU MOM DID YOU SEE THE DOG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND:&lt;/strong&gt; Just a minute, honey. We&amp;rsquo;re going to hold off until next—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY VOICE:&lt;/strong&gt; I WANT TO PET THE DOG MOM MOM CAN I PET THE DOG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND:&lt;/strong&gt; Sweetie, I need you to be quiet for a minute. We&amp;rsquo;re holding off until next Spring so we don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with the—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY VOICE:&lt;/strong&gt; MOM MOM CAN I HAVE MY JUICE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[FRIEND digs in cooler for a juicebox. 30 minutes pass. Interruptions continue. TINY VOICE becomes so insistent that FRIEND exits the table briefly. It becomes clear, finally, that FRIEND wants to remodel the basement, but will wait until Spring to avoid extra heating costs since they&amp;rsquo;re planning to replace the insulation. No further discussion is possible because TINY VOICE needs to be put down for a nap. FRIEND goes home.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barbecues aren&amp;rsquo;t that much fun anymore, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these days, neither is the bar. Or dinner. Or other kid-free events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jokes and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/funny-stuff/the-fine-art-of-bullshit-c09f7bbb391e&#34;&gt;silly arguments&lt;/a&gt; and general banter is all different now. Staccato bursts of conversation are all interrupted by flashing lights and three-second bursts of muzak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Two-thirds of a thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY ROBOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND 2:&lt;/strong&gt; New thought started in awkward silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Interruption to finish original thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY ROBOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see a group of friends in a bar isn&amp;rsquo;t much like watching humans who care about each other interact. It&amp;rsquo;s like watching four people sit alone at a communal table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alone-at-a-table-full-of-friends:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;Alone at a Table Full of Friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ignoring-friends-on-phones.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Ignoring friends at dinner on cell phones.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Dinner was great; I finally caught up on my Twitter feed!

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://grooverpr.wordpress.com/2014/03/29/topic-of-the-week-cell-phones-conversations/&#34;&gt;grooverpr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a true story: I was in Chiang Mai a few months back, and Marisa and I made a game of timing how long it took for various tables of 3+ college students to actually speak to each other. The game was boring; they almost never spoke to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one table — two guys and two girls — who never spoke at all. One of the girls didn&amp;rsquo;t even look at her friends; she spent the whole meal taking selfies at severe downward angles. The other girl photojournaled the entire meal and presumably starved to death because she never got around to eating anything. The guys buried their heads in an iPad game and Snapchat.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-let-em-get-the-hooks-in:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;We Let &amp;lsquo;Em Get the Hooks In&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change was slow for most of us. Almost imperceptible. Sometime in 2009 we became abruptly aware of a dozen unread notifications in our pockets and our stomachs went through the taffy puller because &lt;em&gt;things were happening&lt;/em&gt; and we were missing them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way someone&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; came up with the term FoMO and it started getting tossed around as a psychological disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And — like magic — being a total dick to your friends became a psychological disorder, in the same way that bringing a rooster&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; onto a plane somehow became medically valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;This is things that have gone to far: A rooster on a plane, in a pink tutu, as an &amp;ldquo;emotional support&amp;rdquo; animal. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/PLpuf4EH5Z&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/PLpuf4EH5Z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sue Strachan (@SueStrachan504) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SueStrachan504/status/511540289769844737&#34;&gt;September 15, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-want-to-be-everywhere:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;We Want to Be Everywhere&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren&amp;rsquo;t more things happening in the world now than there were thirty years ago. We&amp;rsquo;re just able to see more of it happening in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a practical demonstration of &amp;ldquo;ignorance is bliss&amp;rdquo;, our parents and grandparents never tasted the bitter anguish of realizing that nerds from the U.S. just &lt;a href=&#34;http://twistedsifter.com/videos/usa-challenges-japan-to-giant-robot-duel/&#34;&gt;challenged Japan to a mech-suit battle&lt;/a&gt; last week &lt;em&gt;and you didn&amp;rsquo;t hear about it until today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we unfortunate residents of The Future™ weren&amp;rsquo;t so lucky. Fate, with a mirthless grin and malevolently glittering eyes, thrust us into a world where Periscope and Facebook and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theonion.com/article/media-landscape-redefined-by-24-second-news-cycle-2213&#34;&gt;24-second news cycle&lt;/a&gt; exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our only weapon in this struggle against cultural irrelevance is a constant IV-drip of information, fed through our eyeballs and fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armed with the latest smart_______, we doggedly pursue Total Awareness. Legends are told of an elite few who know all things &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; they start trending on Facebook. These multi-screen samurai pursue 100% coverage of global occurrences with Neeson-esque determination.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-where-are-we-exactly:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;So Where Are We, Exactly?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the corners of our vision, just beyond the edge of what we can identify without turning our heads, another world is dimly lit with blue light, collecting dust and falling into disrepair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that world doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter now. We &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that world; it&amp;rsquo;s the other things that we need to keep tabs on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; our friends, and their stories.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We already &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; all our family&amp;rsquo;s dirty secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s exciting about the things we already know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing. &lt;em&gt;Nothing&lt;/em&gt; is exciting about the things we know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; exciting? Kid Rock acting like an ignorant hillbilly. &lt;em&gt;What drama and intrigue!&lt;/em&gt; And you know what else? Donald Trump on an escalator. If that&amp;rsquo;s not a memory that will bring you some small comfort in the final hours of your life, you&amp;rsquo;re probably dead inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Grandma can just hold her damn horses if she wants to spend the day with us; we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with matters of critical import, here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/fomo.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;FoMO: Fear of Missing Out&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  #thestruggleisreal

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-things-that-matter:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;The Things That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work endlessly — thanklessly — to keep drinking from the information firehose spraying from this pitiless world we live in. No one will sing songs of our dedication and perseverance. The history books won&amp;rsquo;t mention our names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;rsquo;ll know what we&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our old age, we want to look fondly back on a lifetime of accomplishment and contentment. Happy memories of happy days, where we did things that truly mattered to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom&amp;rsquo;s kinda-dry turkey dinner just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make that cut. Sorry, Mom, but there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;real struggle&lt;/em&gt; happening here. You&amp;rsquo;re just too old to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that we don&amp;rsquo;t love our friends and family — we do. Dearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just that we aren&amp;rsquo;t 100% sure there&amp;rsquo;s not something out there that we might love &lt;em&gt;more.&lt;/em&gt; So we have to keep our options open&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and stay diligent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise we&amp;rsquo;re just cheating ourselves, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may not be able to communicate our feelings without emoticons. We may not have spoken to our parents in weeks. Our friends may only know us as That Guy Who Plays on His Phone Through Lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we saw &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tvsV6nlLe1g&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; the day it came out. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VLEfrulUEcs&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, our sacrifice was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;The third statistician jumps up and starts fist-pumping and yelling, &amp;ldquo;Yeah! We got him, boys! We got him!&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;He was looking at snaps of beautiful women doing nothing: talking to the camera, pointing their cameras at what they were eating, waving and laughing. The two girls he was with were incredibly good-looking. They had food they could show him. They had (perhaps most importantly) agreed to hang out with him in person. I wanted to shake him: &amp;ldquo;Son, do you even understand what you&amp;rsquo;re doing wrong, here?&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bostonmagazine.com/news/article/2014/07/29/fomo-history/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boston Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, credit for FoMO (&amp;ldquo;Fear of Missing Out&amp;rdquo;) goes to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danherman.com/The-Fear-of-Missing-Out-(FOMO)-by-Dan-Herman.html&#34;&gt;Dan Herman&lt;/a&gt;, though it was really popularized by Patrick McGinnis in a 2004 op-ed on the subject. This will be on the quiz.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;Or pig, or mini-horse, or peacock. It&amp;rsquo;s so absurd that you have to wonder if it&amp;rsquo;s an attempt at satirizing rich white women with tiny dogs to help with their depression, or this subversion of cloying airline policy is being carried out by a subset of hipsters who decided mustaches weren&amp;rsquo;t ironic enough.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;Of course, no one can prove that the fabled Ultrainformed exist. They&amp;rsquo;ve never been spotted in the wild, and only surface for mere moments at a time under the guise of various throwaway Reddit accounts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The hopeful among Millennials (a.k.a. the Informationally Forsaken) speak of the Ultrainformed as possible saviors from our ignorance; the cynical write them off as the Illuminati; my grandpa says we should just close the fucking computer and go outside already.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;For the last time, Dave: we&amp;rsquo;ve all heard your goddamn Mariah-Carey-in-the-elevator story.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Nobody cares.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, yeah, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hang out, but I can&amp;rsquo;t actually commit to anything. There&amp;rsquo;s a possibility that something better than your shitty party will come up, and I want to keep my options open. I&amp;rsquo;ll show up if I show up.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Make Time; Find Time</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/find-time</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 10:47:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/find-time</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I love listening to a good podcast. Something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radiolab.org/&#34;&gt;Radiolab&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://hearstartup.com/&#34;&gt;StartUp&lt;/a&gt; — things that make me think, teach me something new, spin me off on a philosophical tangent for a half hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-don-t-have-time-for-that:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Have Time for That&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a constant backlog at work. I have friends I want to visit. I like to go outside when I&amp;rsquo;m not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting quietly for 45 minutes to listen to the latest Radiolab? Sorry, but it&amp;rsquo;s not high on my list of things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The time spent listening to a podcast is too easy for me to reallocate to things that I deem &amp;ldquo;productive&amp;rdquo;, and therefore I rarely listen to podcasts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only times I ever listen to podcasts are A) when a friend hears a particularly good one and goes out of his way to listen to it again while we&amp;rsquo;re hanging out, B) on a road trip&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:road-trip&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:road-trip&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or C) when I&amp;rsquo;m sick/hung over/burned out and can&amp;rsquo;t imagine doing anything other than passively listening to something while draped over my couch like a threadbare blanket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-should-make-time:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You Should Make Time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s important to you, you should make time for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I hear that, I get a twinge of guilt. &lt;em&gt;I should. I&amp;rsquo;m such a slacker. Why don&amp;rsquo;t I just make time to do this if it&amp;rsquo;s important to me?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m making a lot of time for a lot of important things already.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently making time to write this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I will make time to go to the gym for an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evenings this week I&amp;rsquo;ll be making time to meet with friends for dinners and drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I keep &amp;ldquo;making time&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m going to run out of hours&lt;/strong&gt; for work, sleep, and showers.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:showers&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:showers&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; And if I prioritize the things I&amp;rsquo;m willing to make time for, podcasts definitely fall after writing, my health, and my social life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So does that mean I should just give up on podcasts and write them off altogether?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/find-time1.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Don&amp;#39;t make time; find time.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-the-time:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545&#34;&gt;Find the Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent conversation, I brought all this up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/best-friends/&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d love to listen to podcasts, but there just aren&amp;rsquo;t enough hours in the day, you know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a particularly avid podcast listener, Nate didn&amp;rsquo;t understand. &amp;ldquo;You can always find time to listen to a podcast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate fits his podcast listening into the spaces where nothing otherwise engaging is happening. While cooking dinner, he&amp;rsquo;ll throw on the latest &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thisamericanlife.org/&#34;&gt;This American Life&lt;/a&gt; instead of background music. Or while cleaning, or folding laundry, or some other menial task that is otherwise less-than-engaging, but unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How many minutes of your day are full of little spaces where you zone out? Where you&amp;rsquo;re taking care of something, but your brain is completely off?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to listen to more podcasts, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to &lt;em&gt;make time&lt;/em&gt; at all. &lt;strong&gt;I needed to use the time I already had more efficiently.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-the-time-in-my-day-to-day:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545&#34;&gt;Finding the Time in My Day-to-Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t own a car. It&amp;rsquo;s a benefit of living somewhere like Portland — I&amp;rsquo;m close enough to pretty much everything that I can walk there.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:options&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:options&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can walk a mile in about 15–20 minutes. I don&amp;rsquo;t like to talk on the phone while I walk, and I find it really annoying when people walk and text, so I try to keep my phone in my pocket. This means my walks are typically spent daydreaming or thinking about stuff that I can&amp;rsquo;t deal with until I get wherever I&amp;rsquo;m going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, now that I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in terms of finding time, &lt;em&gt;my walks are one or two podcast episodes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wateravenuecoffee.com/&#34;&gt;Water Avenue Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, which is just under two miles from my apartment. It took me about 35 minutes to walk here, and on the walk I listened to episode 3 of StartUp. On the walk home I&amp;rsquo;ll listen to the latest episode of Radiolab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll have spent no additional time that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t already going to spend, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have listened to two podcasts that I really enjoy.&lt;/strong&gt; That&amp;rsquo;s two more podcasts than I listened to in the previous two weeks because I was &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/too-busy/&#34;&gt;too busy&lt;/a&gt; and couldn&amp;rsquo;t make time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else do I put off or skip altogether because I can&amp;rsquo;t (or won&amp;rsquo;t) make time? And where could I find the time to &lt;em&gt;fit it into my existing commitments?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure yet, but I certainly plan to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:road-trip&#34;&gt;Road trips are a very rare thing for me nowadays; I no longer own a car and I usually travel solo, which makes airfare a cheaper, faster option in most cases.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:road-trip&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:showers&#34;&gt;I include showers here because I&amp;rsquo;ve tried the work-is-more-important-than-showers approach. &lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not.&lt;/em&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:showers&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:options&#34;&gt;Or bike, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.car2go.com/en/portland/&#34;&gt;car2go&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:options&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enough with the Sad Stories</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 13:34:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I watched Robert Redford die &amp;ndash; slowly and tortuously &amp;ndash; for two hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was watching his new movie, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2017038/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;All Is Lost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is &lt;strong&gt;killing it&lt;/strong&gt; on Rotten Tomatoes (currently rocking a 94% rating). I left the theater feeling heavy, sad, despondent. It was rough. I didn&amp;rsquo;t much care for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/75824994?color=e26700&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;422&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say &lt;em&gt;All Is Lost&lt;/em&gt; is a bad movie. It&amp;rsquo;s well-made, and Robert Redford is a solid actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Jesus! what a draining way to spend an afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-nineteen-year-old-self-is-so-ashamed-right-now:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;My Nineteen-Year-Old Self Is So Ashamed Right Now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;rsquo;m saying all this as Present Tense Jason, who is very different from Jason of Yore; in fact, the latter would spit right in my face for what I&amp;rsquo;m about to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten (somewhat) older and seen (a bit) more of the world, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost interest in the movies that used to top my list. Gone are the days of repeated viewings of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1g5XH57&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Clockwork Orange&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; no longer do I want to sit down and really &lt;strong&gt;experience&lt;/strong&gt; a film like &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzt.to/1crskxC&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Requiem for a Dream&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still think they&amp;rsquo;re good movies &amp;ndash; great ones, even &amp;ndash; but god&lt;em&gt;damn&lt;/em&gt; are they depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid it was important to me that my movie choices felt authentic, and didn&amp;rsquo;t cloud the story with fluffy Hollywood nonsense. I wanted heroes who could die, and stories that twisted and turned and gave you hope before killing the main character &amp;ndash; y&amp;rsquo;know, because life is like that sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;art-imitating-life:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;Art Imitating Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year I read about some movie that raises the bar for authenticity. Some &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1hlY1Rb&#34;&gt;movie about Osama Bin Laden&lt;/a&gt; put all the actors through real military training, or some French filmmaker had his actors &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1dgPXu0&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; have sex during the love scenes&lt;/a&gt;. Even the superhero movies are coming up with as-plausible-as-you-can-make-a-superhero-backstory origin stories &amp;ndash; apparently so we can all avoid the burden of suspending our disbelief for 105 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all pushing toward a true-to-life experience. And a good portion of it is terribly hard to watch because it&amp;rsquo;s so depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-em-laugh:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;Make &amp;lsquo;Em Laugh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take away my cinephile card if you want, but these days, I just want to be entertained, not bashed in the skull repeatedly with an emotional sledgehammer. I&amp;rsquo;m sick of feeling bad when the credits start rolling, or after finishing a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to hear a great story about characters that make me want to be better, filled with heroes who win by being smarter and more determined than the villains; about couples who believe so deeply in true love that even insurmountable obstacles can be surmounted; about wizened old mentors who teach just the right lesson at just the right moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I want things to work out in the end.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know life is hard, and that not everything ends well. There are little reminders of life&amp;rsquo;s hardships and inconveniences all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, then, would I want additional reminders while I&amp;rsquo;m trying to relax and take my mind &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; the world&amp;rsquo;s ills?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-be-awesome:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;Just Be Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I want nothing but romantic comedies. I just want more stories involving people being awesome, and that leave me feeling better than when I started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t show me &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1crujSA&#34;&gt;Paul Giamatti slowly self-destructing&lt;/a&gt; in a moody downward spiral. Instead, show me Cary Elwes &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1a6pCBD&#34;&gt;outsmarting Sicilians and besting giants&lt;/a&gt; to rescue his true love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your favorite feel-good movies and books?&lt;/strong&gt; Let me know in the Facebook discussion!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>