<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gtd on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/gtd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gtd on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 13:28:23 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/gtd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The No-Distractions Productivity Experiment</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 13:28:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-experiment/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I sat down and designed, developed, and wrote content for this new site. If you work on the web, or if you&amp;rsquo;ve hired a web designer before, you know this is crazy talk. But &lt;em&gt;it happened.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All things considered, I spent about ten hours on it, broken up by a trip to the gym, lunch, and dinner. This is a very simple site, too, which definitely played a big part in the quick turnaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t like admitting that I set a New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution, because I&amp;rsquo;m painfully aware of how many January 1 promises I&amp;rsquo;ve made and immediately broken. However, this site has been on my back burner for months now, and between the time off for the holiday, my back-logged desire to work on it, and the general &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s do &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; energy that accompanies a perceived fresh start, I finally built up enough momentum to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a web project from concept to launch in one day is very, &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; rare, so I kind of surprised myself by pulling it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loaded the new files up on the server and flipped the switch with a kind of fuck-yeah-I&amp;rsquo;m-unstoppable feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It got me thinking about how I&amp;rsquo;ve historically handled momentum, and how it usually starts an upswing in productivity, followed by frustration when I can&amp;rsquo;t keep up the heroic pace I&amp;rsquo;ve set for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-distractions:5928468cb35d47a9f4c4fc0008e12966&#34;&gt;No Distractions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the reason I was able to finish this site in such a short time frame is that I shut off all distractions: no email, no phone calls, no chat; just headphones, coffee, and good ol&amp;rsquo; blood-and-sawdust resolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t my usual state of affairs. In fact, I only pulled it off because it was a holiday and I should have been taking time off in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a normal day, tuning out distractions would mean grumpy clients, stalled contractors, lost leads, and an ever-growing todo list &amp;ndash; all of which add up to outweigh the benefits of how much work gets done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-a-balance:5928468cb35d47a9f4c4fc0008e12966&#34;&gt;Finding a Balance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Routine is hard for me. I instinctively buck authority, even if the rules are self-imposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My default mode is very freeform; I drive Ali nuts by constantly improvising and telling her, &amp;ldquo;Relax. &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/jazz/&#34;&gt;Life is jazz.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, seeing how much I was able to accomplish with all the distractions turned off, I wonder how effective I could be if I allocated one or two days a week as &amp;ldquo;no distractions&amp;rdquo; days, during which I would cut off communications and just get a big chunk of work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve toyed with the idea before, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never fully implemented it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-experiment:5928468cb35d47a9f4c4fc0008e12966&#34;&gt;The Experiment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Tuesday, I&amp;rsquo;m going to have a distraction-free day. It&amp;rsquo;s going on my calendar. My team will be notified. An autoresponder will be set on my email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serious business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the experiment works, I should be able to focus on and &amp;ndash; hopefully &amp;ndash; complete one or two large tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should also have the added benefit of making me feel less guilty if I spend the days before and after buried in email or on the phone, which is a common source of stress for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you tried this split style of working before?&lt;/strong&gt; Any tips to help me get it right the first time? Let me know in the Facebook discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; The experiment went well, and I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-results/&#34;&gt;posted the results&lt;/a&gt; for review. Short version: this is something I&amp;rsquo;m going to try and integrate into my workflow once a week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>