<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsters on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/monsters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monsters on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 10:58:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/monsters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away Its Power</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/name-your-fear</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 10:58:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/name-your-fear</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At a sleepover in second grade, my friends put on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0094761/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Blob&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — a horror film about space jelly that kills anyone it touches. I was so scared I started crying and my mom had to pick me up to take me home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another night I snuck out of my bedroom while my parents watched TV, and I saw the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OPdDdC4go6c&#34;&gt;sewer scene from &lt;em&gt;It&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. My dad had to remove everything that even &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt; resembled a clown from the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-wasn-t-scared-of-the-story:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;I Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Scared of the Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both cases, I actually barely saw any of the movie that frightened me. I saw that the movie was a scary movie, I knew that scary movies terrified me, and I knew that watching a scary movie would scare me too badly to be able to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize, however, was my fear of horror films — and the fear I felt when I imagined what terrors those films might contain — was all it took to ruin my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was scared of the movies themselves.&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of the movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was so bad that I only had to see the cover of &lt;em&gt;Child&amp;rsquo;s Play&lt;/em&gt; in a video store to end up petrified and sleepless for a few nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-out-how-it-ends:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Find Out How It Ends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an adult, I still don&amp;rsquo;t care for horror films. But if I start watching one, I now force myself to finish the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I see a scene from a horror film — just like I did when I was a kid — I build a vague, terrifying beast out of my fear of the movie, and this unknowable shape is more monstrous than anything I&amp;rsquo;ll see in a movie. I don&amp;rsquo;t care how good the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer-generated_imagery&#34;&gt;CGI&lt;/a&gt; is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to see the end. I need to know what happens. What &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; goes on in this movie?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no way the actual outcome will be scarier than what I can dream up in my ignorance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By seeing the full movie, I learn the reality of the story, and that takes away the paralyzing power of my ignorance and fear.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-away-its-power:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Take Away Its Power&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our fears are imaginary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t know what comes next, so we make projections about the future. And in our imaginations, the potential for catastrophe is alarmingly high.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;rsquo;re not actually scared of the experience. We&amp;rsquo;re scared of the unknown: the vague, monster-shaped outline in our imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By facing that fear, we replace the monster with a memory. And even if the memory is uncomfortable or humiliating, it&amp;rsquo;s very unlikely that it will be as horrifying as the make-believe nightmare scenario we dreamed up before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shining-a-light-into-monster-shaped-shadows:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Shining a Light into Monster-Shaped Shadows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To take power away from your fear, give it a name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an effort to limit the number of monsters occupying my headspace, I try to push my fears into reality and name them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I feeling anxious about a client who seems unhappy with my work? Call them and clear the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there an unresolved tension between me and a family member? Let&amp;rsquo;s sit down and get to the bottom of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is my laundry room haunted? Let&amp;rsquo;s go stand in there and find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I notice a situation that scares me, I try to jump in earlier rather than later, because the end result is always the same: I face the fear and realize the difference between what I &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; was wrong, and what was &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; wrong is staggering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I thought may have been a relationship-ending issue with the client turned out to be a few small adjustments and ten minutes of screensharing to show them how to use a tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a beer with the family member, we realized we were both working toward the same goal even though our methods were clashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My laundry room is creepy as shit. But it&amp;rsquo;s not haunted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a fear is dragged into reality and exposed to a little daylight, the giant monster-shaped shadow in my imagination shrivels to a small, silly bit of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;name-your-fears:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Name Your Fears&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What monsters are lurking in your imagination right now? How many of them can you drag into reality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/uaeincredible/217849066/&#34;&gt;Capture Queen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;Sure, &lt;em&gt;The Ring&lt;/em&gt; still scared the shit out of me, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t lose any sleep afterward. I can guarantee the things my brain will dream up out of a storyline involving a dead girl who haunts your TV are &lt;em&gt;far worse&lt;/em&gt; than what happens in the movie.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;For an easy example, imagine asking someone out on a date that you think is &amp;ldquo;out of your league.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I get anxious imagining it: I see her across the room, obviously more successful, socially adept, and better-looking than me. She&amp;rsquo;s smiling, sharply dressed, surrounded by people who are laughing at the devilishly clever observation she just made about current events of which I&amp;rsquo;m appallingly ignorant.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And here I come — trying to look confident but probably smiling like a crazy person, food caught in my beard, smudges on my glasses — to interrupt her conversation. I tell a joke that doesn&amp;rsquo;t land, laugh loudly at my own joke out of discomfort, turn tomato-red in self-conscious embarrassment, and stammer my way through awkward compliments that are just making her more uncomfortable.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I never even get to the part about asking her out.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;She laughs in my face. The people around her laugh in my face. Everyone in the room perks up, and she grabs the microphone from the party&amp;rsquo;s emcee.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ladies and gentlemen, a special announcement: Jason Lengstorf is a useless idiot who lacks the charm of a papercut and smells like he&amp;rsquo;s been eating nothing but cheese for the last eight weeks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The story makes the news later that night, and I&amp;rsquo;m forced to flee the country in shame. I live out the rest of my days in Bulgaria harvesting sugar beets in exile.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The reality, however, is that — while &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d probably still blow it&lt;/a&gt; — the actual situation would be far less ridiculous. I&amp;rsquo;d say hello, she&amp;rsquo;d say hello, I&amp;rsquo;d try to make conversation, and when we didn&amp;rsquo;t hit it off I&amp;rsquo;d make an exit. This isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a storybook ending, but it&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near the worst-case scenario my imagination cooks up.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>