<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creating on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/creating/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creating on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 08:42:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/creating/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Shitty First Draft</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/shitty-first-draft</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 08:42:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/shitty-first-draft</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://precisionnutrition.com/&#34;&gt;Precision Nutrition&lt;/a&gt;, the first iteration of any project is called a &lt;strong&gt;Shitty First Draft&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:lamott&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:lamott&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t done to make the people producing the work feel bad about themselves; exactly the opposite, in fact: &lt;strong&gt;the goal of the Shitty First Draft is to remove the need for polish in favor of making progress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/shitty-first-draft-hemingway.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;The first draft of anything is shit. – Ernest Hemingway&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-power-of-getting-started:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499&#34;&gt;The Power of Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blank canvas is intimidating. You have a vague idea of what you need to create. You have a deadline. You know you have the skill to pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly right? What if people judge your work too harshly? What if this idea isn&amp;rsquo;t as good as you thought?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small worries like these can lead to procrastination and unnecessary stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Shitty First Draft is specifically designed to remove these barriers, making it much easier to just get started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Shitty First Draft is not intended to be perfect.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s intentionally imperfect and unpolished.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Shitty First Draft isn&amp;rsquo;t reviewed for launch-readiness.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s intended to give everyone a starting point to provide real, concrete feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Shitty First Draft gets the ideas on paper and out of your head.&lt;/strong&gt; This makes it much easier to see the value of the idea &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; spending too much time on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shitty First Draft is fast, and intended only to move the project from a vague, project-shaped idea to a tangible, tweakable, &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving a project from &amp;ldquo;an idea we need to start working on&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;a project that&amp;rsquo;s started but needs to be finished&amp;rdquo; has a huge psychological benefit: &lt;strong&gt;forward progress generates momentum,&lt;/strong&gt; and there&amp;rsquo;s no question that projects with momentum get finished faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-something-simple-to-get-a-real-working-concept:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499&#34;&gt;Create Something Simple to Get a &amp;ldquo;Real&amp;rdquo; Working Concept&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having something tangible to look at allows the whole team to see a real-world application of the idea. This is far easier to tweak than a collectively assembled mental model and/or flowchart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a Shitty First Draft, the time it takes to get something tangible is much lower. The project spends far less time as a concept in the minds of the &amp;ldquo;idea people&amp;rdquo;, and far more time being shaped into a final product by the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/quick-and-dirty-prototypes.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;keep prototypes quick and dirty&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The wireframes for our app bordered on stick figures. That&#39;s all we needed.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I&amp;rsquo;m currently building a new application that&amp;rsquo;s trying to take certain in-person interactions and — as best as possible — scale those globally. We spent hours talking about how this could work and how to measure success, but because nothing like this app currently exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wrap our heads around how it worked, because it was only a concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We needed something real — something bound by the limits of reality — so that we could start to find and fix issues with our approach.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of trying to code anything, I started by building a Shitty First Draft: low-quality wireframes of different screens in the app, plugged together in a Google Presentation that we used to storyboard what a real session would look like using the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lo-fi storyboard only took a few days to put together, and having &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; screens to look at while walking through a real use case allowed us to find issues that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have caught otherwise — issues that would have required a good deal of work done over again had we jumped straight to building a &amp;ldquo;production-ready&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:productionready&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:productionready&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;remove-guesswork-from-new-projects:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499&#34;&gt;Remove Guesswork from New Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/underpants-gnomes-planning.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Underpants Gnomes South Park&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  A Shitty First Draft helps avoid the Underpants Gnome problem.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://southpark.cc.com/clips/151040/the-underpants-business&#34;&gt;South Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shitty First Draft also takes a lot of the guesswork out of the subsequent efforts: my first crack at coding up the app felt more like a paint-by-numbers than a blank canvas, and that allowed me to get into a &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/EY6UKJ&#34;&gt;flow state&lt;/a&gt; quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shitty First Draft paved the way for the real product by smoothing out all the usual bumps that would take me out of building the app to work on its strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shitty First Draft has been used effectively at Precision Nutrition for everything from web apps to coaching programs to full-length books. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what kind of work you&amp;rsquo;re doing: &lt;strong&gt;start with a Shitty First Draft, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a higher-quality product sooner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;give-yourself-permission-to-start-shitty:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499&#34;&gt;Give Yourself Permission to Start Shitty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shudder to think of now many hours I&amp;rsquo;ve wasted trying to write something perfect on the first try.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:highschool&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:highschool&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; How many lines of code I&amp;rsquo;ve deleted after I built out a fully-functional feature that it turned out wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessary at all. How many designs I&amp;rsquo;ve scrapped because I started with the aesthetic before I had all the details of how something would be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt pressure to be perfect. Most of it was internal pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to admit I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get things perfect on the first try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasted days of my life. Probably &lt;em&gt;months.&lt;/em&gt; All because I was worried that if every word, every line of code, every pixel of a design — if &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; I produced wasn&amp;rsquo;t my absolute best work, I was failing myself, my clients, my business, my fucking &lt;em&gt;ancestors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ernest-hemingway-shitty-first-draft.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Ernest Hemingway shitty first draft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Smart guy, that Hemingway fella.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I came to accept that Hemingway was right, and that the first draft is always shitty, I started working more quickly, and the work I put out into the world was better quality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article started as a list of productivity tips, which was expanded to a series of articles including a piece on planning, which was then simplified into just this concept. From there, it went through several rounds of edits from myself and people I trust before it came out as the post you&amp;rsquo;re reading now.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:anxiety&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:anxiety&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything about my creative process improved when I started implementing the Shitty First Draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will you create when you give yourself permission to start shitty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:lamott&#34;&gt;I did a search for &amp;ldquo;shitty first draft&amp;rdquo; after I started writing this article and came across an excerpt from Anne Lamott&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Bird by Bird&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://wrd.as.uky.edu/sites/default/files/1-Shitty%20First%20Drafts.pdf&#34;&gt;on shitty first drafts.&lt;/a&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s worth a read — especially if you&amp;rsquo;re a writer.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:lamott&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:productionready&#34;&gt;I quote this because it still would have been a Shitty First Draft; it just would have cost far more to produce.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:productionready&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:highschool&#34;&gt;In high school, I was so hellbent on this I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t edit my writing assignments at all. Hell, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; them after I finished writing. I&amp;rsquo;d sit down, write the whole thing in one sitting — it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take long to fill two pages, double-spaced, after all — print it, and never look at it again. I remember saying something impossibly pretentious, like, &amp;ldquo;My writing is born whole. If I have to edit it, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth writing in the first place.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:highschool&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:anxiety&#34;&gt;The anxious part of my brain just started screaming, &amp;ldquo;No! Delete that! What if this isn&amp;rsquo;t an amazing article and people say, &amp;lsquo;This is your &lt;em&gt;edited&lt;/em&gt; stuff?&amp;lsquo;&amp;rdquo; Yes. This is my edited stuff.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:validation&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:validation&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; That little anxious voice can suck it.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ccdb412110a12cc6d10d548842a4499:anxiety&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocketships and Bicycles</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/rocketships-bicycles</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 13:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/rocketships-bicycles</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time with my head in the clouds. To me, the best ideas are the ones unhindered by trifles like logistics. Or reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question I always start with is: &lt;em&gt;If I had unlimited time, capital, and resources, what would I build?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s impractical, sure, but to me it removes a critical barrier in my planning process. Instead of asking, &amp;ldquo;What am I capable of?&amp;rdquo; I ask, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s possible?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/rocketship-goal-setting-lg.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;aim high when setting goals&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Dream big.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-with-what-s-possible-not-what-s-practical:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;Start with What&amp;rsquo;s Possible, Not What&amp;rsquo;s Practical&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want to get from Point A to Point B, I have a problem to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I start designing a solution, I&amp;rsquo;m not thinking about what I&amp;rsquo;ve built before, or what I think I might be able to build with my current level of knowledge; I&amp;rsquo;m only thinking of what — given unlimited resources in a perfect world — I would &lt;em&gt;ideally&lt;/em&gt; like to see built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To travel from Point A to Point B, &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to build a rocketship.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the actual process of planning the rocketship build gets underway, I&amp;rsquo;ll start worrying about practicalities. Features will be stripped away until the solution becomes feasible, and often times my rocketship will become nothing more than a simple bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-real-life-example-of-setting-ideal-outcomes:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;A Real-Life Example of Setting Ideal Outcomes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently kicked off an experiment in permanent travel and digital nomadism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a number of theories about productivity, work-life balance, and overall happiness that fundamentally changed the way I look at the world. Ultimately, these theories led to me &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;selling off my possessions and wandering off to see the world&lt;/a&gt;, bringing only what I could fit in a carry-on suitcase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 25px auto; max-width:500px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/p/xTidrIzK7-/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Jason Lengstorf (@jlengstorf)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2015-01-01T08:52:03+00:00&#34;&gt;Jan 1, 2015 at 12:52am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think these theories can be helpful to people other than myself, and I want to share them. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have a big audience, or any favors to call in with big influencers. So how do I get the word out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the problem I need to solve.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignoring time restraints, lack of connections, and my ignorance with respect to how to actually make any of this &lt;em&gt;happen,&lt;/em&gt; I defined my rocketship:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a book on the subject, and get it picked up by a major publisher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch a media onslaught by publishing guest articles &lt;em&gt;everywhere.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak at conferences around the world to share my theories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue to publish on my blog and grow my newsletter list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This combined effort will put my theories in front of millions of people, and — with a little luck — help improve lives around the world. &lt;strong&gt;This is my &amp;ldquo;perfect world&amp;rdquo; outcome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I put the work in and figure out what&amp;rsquo;s possible and practical, the goals will get progressively more and more modest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end, it may turn out that what I &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do is more along these lines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read all the research I can to back up my theories with hard data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I write one or two articles on my blog sharing the data in a useful way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few hundred people read what I wrote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One person uses the information as a catalyst for real, positive change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be my bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will it change the world? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But did it accomplish my original goal: to communicate what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in a clear and well-researched fashion to as many people as possible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Even if &amp;ldquo;as many people as possible&amp;rdquo; turns out to be a smaller number than I&amp;rsquo;d hoped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/goal-setting-bicycle.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;setting goals: a bicycle is almost as good as a rocketship&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  A bicycle may not be a perfect solution, but progress is progress.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect the bicycle outcome to result in a biopic about me, I also wouldn&amp;rsquo;t consider it in any way a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bicycle is not a rocketship. But a bicycle &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-are-you-defining-failure:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;How Are You Defining Failure?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But if I designed a rocketship and only built a bicycle, haven&amp;rsquo;t I missed my goal and failed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If failure to you is &amp;ldquo;any outcome that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly match the initial plan&amp;rdquo;, then sure, the bicycle is a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, however, isn&amp;rsquo;t with the plan or the design; the problem is an inaccurate definition of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rocketship isn&amp;rsquo;t the goal.&lt;/strong&gt; The rocketship is &lt;em&gt;a proposed solution.&lt;/em&gt; The &lt;em&gt;goal&lt;/em&gt; is to get from Point A to Point B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this perspective, any progress is progress. By thinking big and editing along the way, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably still get further than you would have been if you aim low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you design a rocketship and end up with a bicycle, you came up short of your ideal solution — but you have a viable, practical means of getting from Point A to Point B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, &lt;em&gt;even though you didn&amp;rsquo;t build the rocketship, you still accomplished the original goal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/unicycle-goal-setting.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;unicycle&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Hedging bets can lead to impractical solutions.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/the1andonlycary/&#34;&gt;Cary Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you hedge your bets and design a bicycle, you don&amp;rsquo;t have any wiggle room in your proposed solution. If you end up with a unicycle (or maybe just a wheel), you either have an impractical means of getting yourself around — unicycles are difficult to learn to ride, after all — or, worse, a concept that &lt;em&gt;theoretically&lt;/em&gt; moves you from Point A to Point B, but lacks some of the required equipment to make it usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-the-definition-of-failure-works-in-reality:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;How the Definition of Failure Works in Reality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have choices when I think about sharing my experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, I could look at the goal as &amp;ldquo;get a book published&amp;rdquo; — this is a lofty goal, and very specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also only part of what I was originally setting out to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I could look at the goal as &amp;ldquo;tell as many people as possible about my ideas for improving our quality of life&amp;rdquo; — this is what I originally wanted to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I do the work and manage to get a book published, &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made an enormous amount of progress&lt;/strong&gt; toward sharing my findings with as many people as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if I do everything else on my rocketship list &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; publishing a book — guest posts, speaking gigs, and all — but I&amp;rsquo;m looking at the rocketship as the &lt;em&gt;goal&lt;/em&gt; and not the &lt;em&gt;means to that goal&lt;/em&gt;, I would still feel like a failure because the book didn&amp;rsquo;t get published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a counterproductive way to look at things, because if I can do four of the five things on my rocketship list, a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; amount of people will be exposed to my ideas. Just because I didn&amp;rsquo;t tick all the boxes shouldn&amp;rsquo;t — and doesn&amp;rsquo;t — mean all of my efforts were in vain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I lose sight of &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m trying to do in favor of &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m going to do it, I risk setting an impossible standard and feeling like a failure, despite otherwise making good progress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/upgraded-car.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;drifting car&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Start simple and upgrade over time.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/xavier33300/&#34;&gt;SuperCar-RoadTrip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-constant-improvement-to-start-fast-and-steadily-get-faster:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;Use Constant Improvement to Start Fast and Steadily Get Faster&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparatively, a rocketship will complete the goal &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; faster than a bicycle, so it can feel hopeless to only have a bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, if the bicycle you&amp;rsquo;ve built is reliable, it ceases to be something you have to worry about. You no longer need to design the solution; you only need to spend time on maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves you free to build improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing that progress — albeit slow — is being made, you can add new features. A motor. Chassis. Wings. Autopilot. Espresso machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A bicycle doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to &lt;em&gt;remain&lt;/em&gt; a bicycle. And in many cases, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, the bicycle can become a motorcycle, which can become a race car, then a plane, and — eventually — a goddamn rocketship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these solutions is better than the one from which it evolved: a motorcycle is fast; a plane is faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be tempting to say, &amp;ldquo;Well, fine: I can&amp;rsquo;t build a rocketship. But I will build a race car, because I know I can do that, and altogether skip the part where I have that slow bicycle!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The catch is that a bicycle might take a month to build, where a race car may take a year. How much would the slow progress of the bicycle add up in the eleven months between?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how much of a delay would it cause to start with a bicycle, then improve it to become a race car?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting with a simple solution creates a Progress Snowball.&lt;/strong&gt; The solution allows you to quickly start making slow progress, and each subsequent improvement improves the speed, bit by bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/progress-snowball-goal-setting.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;progress snowball in goal setting&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The Progress Snowball: At first it feels painfully slow, and then — suddenly — everything changes.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-practical-example-of-steady-improvement:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;A Practical Example of Steady Improvement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I initially started planning for my experiment, I wanted to do it all at once: launch a huge number of guest posts simultaneously, push a ton of content out on my blog, kick off a targeted social media campaign, hit the conference circuits hard as a speaker, and send off my book manuscript to publishers while the online buzz was in full swing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would have been, if not a rocketship, at least a race car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I looked at it objectively, it was too much for me to take on. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t abandon my blog for months to work on this material, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spread myself thin by committing to writing for my blog &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; keeping up with my day job &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; writing a book-length work plus additional articles. After all, my whole message is to &lt;em&gt;avoid&lt;/em&gt; working long hours, and I want to make sure I&amp;rsquo;m able to succeed while practicing what I intend to preach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My race car design also would have required convincing a bunch of sites who don&amp;rsquo;t know me at all to both publish a guest post from me &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; to run it on a timeframe that was to my benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I&amp;rsquo;d be unhappy if I lost momentum on my blog, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I&amp;rsquo;d be able to get all — or any — of the guest blogs accepted if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have at least a little bit of supporting material up beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I chose a bicycle: regular posts on my own blog, a few things on Medium, and a concentrated effort to keep up my social media accounts in a way that was engaging and mostly on-message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This created the slow progress that I&amp;rsquo;m seeing now, while I work on researching and creating material for the book, for guest posts, and for speaking engagements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since creating the bicycle, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to book a few speaking gigs on the topic, and opened up conversations with a few of the sites I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to guest blog for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still not a race car, but it might pass for a moped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m a long way from done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-your-rocketship:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Your Rocketship?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at your current goals, how are you planning to achieve them? Are you paralyzed, feeling that the goal is beyond your grasp? Are you tentative, making modest plans that feel safe? Are you feeling hopeless, creating impossible standards for yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust yourself, and to keep working on a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan as if anything is possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that any progress is good progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never stop thinking of ways to improve your progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may find yourself on a bicycle to start, but before long you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself further along than you ever thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Shoot for the moon. Even if you miss, you&amp;rsquo;ll land among the stars.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Norman Vincent Peale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Something</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/create-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 17:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/create-something/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I feel restless or unhappy, it usually means I&amp;rsquo;m not creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always feel better when I&amp;rsquo;m creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/create-something.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;create something&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of what I create comes in the form of pixels and code for my clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I do a personal website project — like this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other times I&amp;rsquo;ll draw little characters on bar napkins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while I&amp;rsquo;ll pick up my guitar and strum, or I&amp;rsquo;ll meet up with an old friend and we&amp;rsquo;ll record &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/bearbak/trouble&#34;&gt;Taylor Swift covers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll work out a new cocktail recipe that I can make at home. Or make pizza from scratch. Or whatever. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I always feel better when I&amp;rsquo;m creating.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creation is the intersection of learning and doing.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s the application and proofing of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creation is a way of stating that — &lt;em&gt;hey, everyone!&lt;/em&gt; — there are things that I value, and that I&amp;rsquo;m willing to work for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creation is chasing ideas that inspire us, intrigue us, make us wonder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing I can imagine is to live without wonder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because when I wonder, I want to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I want to know, I learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I learn, I want to test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I test, I create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; feel better when I&amp;rsquo;m creating.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>