<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mentorship on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/mentorship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mentorship on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 09:35:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/mentorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizards and Assholes</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/wizards-and-assholes</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 09:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/wizards-and-assholes</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One of my early jobs was at a local publishing house, where I did typesetting and rudimentary layout work for field guides. There was a guy there — we&amp;rsquo;ll call him Carl — who handled the still-new digital aspect of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had built a website or two at this point. My work was total amateur hour, but I could tell that this kind of work was something I enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl was the first person I&amp;rsquo;d met who worked on websites for a living.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; At the time, he represented all of the things I wanted in my career. So I looked up to him as a mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, Carl, can I ask you a question? How can I get to where you are? What should I do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl looked at me, sizing me up. He had a smirk on his face. His condescending gaze was amused, like, &amp;ldquo;Who the fuck does this kid think he is?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ron-swanson-condescending.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Ron Swanson condescending&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  I want to make sure you feel like a complete idiot.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1266020/&#34;&gt;Parks and Recreation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt ashamed. I wanted to take my question back. I wanted to hide under the desk until Carl left for the day so I could slink home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked at me for a long time. I shriveled under his stare, questioning everything about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can you tell me the difference between cell padding and cell spacing?&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty sure I knew the answer. I thought maybe it was a trick question. I second-guessed myself. I hesitated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He chuckled and shook his head, disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re not ready to handle the kinds of work I do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-was-an-asshole:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;Carl Was an Asshole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl was forty-something years old, working a job that — in retrospect — was entry-level at best. His skill level was nothing to brag about; he could get the job done, but no one was going to knock any doors down to hire him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Carl was a big fish in a small pond. There was no competition for his job, because no one in Montana at the time was taking digital media very seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/the-wizard.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;The Wizard of Oz&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Pay no attention to the dickhead lording his junior-level skill set over your head.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1JF0EdZ&#34;&gt;The Wizard of Oz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made Carl a lot like the Wizard of Oz: he was mysterious and powerful, dealing in forces that few people really understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I was Dorothy, lost on this brand new career path, looking for someone to guide me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was an eager student. Carl was in a position to help me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, he chose to be an elitist asshole and made me feel stupid for not knowing the things I&amp;rsquo;d just asked him for help with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-of-becoming-irrelevant:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;Fear of Becoming Irrelevant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to think that Carl just didn&amp;rsquo;t like me. He thought I was some dumb kid who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t amount to much and who was probably just on his hobby of the week. Why waste time on the likes of me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think something else may have been at play: Carl might have seen me as a threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not directly. Carl wasn&amp;rsquo;t thinking, &amp;ldquo;Oh no! This kid&amp;rsquo;s about to take my job!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On some level, though, I think Carl may have seen my questions as a threat to his job security. After all, if enough people learned this stuff, it&amp;rsquo;d be a lot more difficult for him to remain the big fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl wanted to be indispensable. He wanted to be the lynchpin in the organization, without which everything would go off the rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That meant treating his knowledge like a trade secret, and boxing out anyone who might weaken his grip on this job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it didn&amp;rsquo;t excuse humiliating a teenager for showing interest in his field of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-be-like-carl:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Be Like Carl&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I was in Boston speaking at an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one of the evenings there was a cocktail mixer at a bar called Lucky&amp;rsquo;s, a basement bar in South Boston. It was the sort of dimly lit, brick-walled dive where you imagine finding disreputable people discussing unsavory acts, but actually find disinterested twenty-somethings discussing undiscovered bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jake-pruitt.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jake Pruitt&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the night wound down, the group I was standing with was approached by this kid, &lt;a href=&#34;http://javascriptjake.com/&#34;&gt;Jake&lt;/a&gt;, who looked like he was about 12 years old. He was 20, in college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment, I was dismissive. &lt;em&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s probably out of his depth,&lt;/em&gt; I thought. &lt;em&gt;I hope he doesn&amp;rsquo;t start asking a bunch of dumb questions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I was angry with myself for letting thoughts like that into my head. I remembered how it felt when I asked Carl for advice, and how humiliated I was when he talked down to me and made me feel like I was too dumb to play on his level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be like Carl,&lt;/em&gt; I reminded myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake was outgoing, curious, personable. He asked a ton of questions, and the whole group joined in to answer them as best we could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point I started giving him shit because he kept pulling his phone out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m taking notes on what you&amp;rsquo;re saying,&amp;rdquo; he told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was both flattering and terrifying. &lt;em&gt;This kid is listening to me? Is that&amp;hellip; Should he be doing that?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it felt good. Here was this kid: excited to learn, passionate about building a career, and looking to me for a little guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake was an eager student. I was in a position to help him out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have been an elitist asshole. I could have done my best to assert my superiority and make him feel dumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it felt way better to help him out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Jake felt good about things, too; later that evening, I got a note from him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Really great chatting with you, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jlengstorf&#34;&gt;@jlengstorf&lt;/a&gt;. Super great life tips, I hope to be like you when I grow up!
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Jake Pruitt (@thejakepruitt)&lt;/small&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thejakepruitt/status/527644976113803265&#34;&gt;October 30, 2014&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;there-s-room-for-all-of-us:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s Room for All of Us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake will end up being pretty successful. He&amp;rsquo;s smart, ambitious, and he&amp;rsquo;s got a head start on his career. He&amp;rsquo;s years ahead of where I was at his age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So should I worry about Jake replacing me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe. But at least now I can remind him that I was a helping hand on his way up, and hope that he&amp;rsquo;ll give me a job when he does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;During the early 2000s in Montana, there were approximately seven people who knew what the internet was.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;For the non-nerds in the room, let me try to put this question into perspective. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re curious to know more about engines, and you ask a mechanic how what you should do to learn more about cars. In response, he says to you, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between using a horse to pull your carriage, or using a donkey?&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>