<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fashion on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/fashion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fashion on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 06:40:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/fashion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Essentials: The Uniform</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/travel-essentials-uniform</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 06:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/travel-essentials-uniform</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One of the toughest challenges of &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;my experiment in long-term remote living and travel&lt;/a&gt; was figuring out how I was going to dress myself out of a carry-on suitcase for an entire year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/exofficio-shirt.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Exofficio shirt&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  I don&#39;t captain a boat, so this look really isn&#39;t for me.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exofficio.com/products/details/mens-air-strip-long-sleeve-shirt&#34;&gt;Exofficio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never considered myself to be fashionable,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:fashion&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:fashion&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so my first instinct was to cop out and buy everything from a &amp;ldquo;world traveler&amp;rdquo; type of company like Exofficio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screw it: I&amp;rsquo;d look like a retired-comptroller-turned-sailing-enthusiast, and uppity fashion snobs who would scoff at my cargo pockets and armpit air vents could kiss my ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with going sailboat captain, though, is that in recent years &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve really started to enjoy building my own style.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of help from my friends with good fashion sense, and over the last couple of years I&amp;rsquo;ve built up a semi-respectable wardrobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wearing an outfit that&amp;rsquo;s stylish makes me feel like an adult. I have a sense of being put together, and that helps me move through my day-to-day life with a little more confidence. It&amp;rsquo;s a small detail, but one that makes a noticeable difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to forfeit my fashion sense while I travel&lt;/strong&gt; — this means copping out wasn&amp;rsquo;t (and isn&amp;rsquo;t) an acceptable option for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I took a look at what some of the men in the fashion industry were doing, and I saw something interesting: &lt;em&gt;a lot of these fashionable men wear the same thing every day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/men-wearing-a-uniform.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;men wearing uniforms: Barack Obama, Tom Ford, Michael Kors, and Steve Jobs&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  In their uniforms (left to right): Barack Obama, Tom Ford, Michael Kors, and Steve Jobs.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Ford and Michael Kors wear almost the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; same outfit every day. Their uniform is a kind of trademark for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I noticed the uniform on fashion designers, I started to notice it on other well-known people, such as Barack Obama and Steve Jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that a lot of fashionable women, including Vera Wang, do the same thing. But I&amp;rsquo;m not going to pretend to have an opinion on what the ladies should pack for long-term travel, so I&amp;rsquo;m only focusing on men&amp;rsquo;s clothing. My travel partner Marisa Morby has written a post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marisamorby.com/blog/2015/1/12/dressing-for-a-year&#34;&gt;how she&amp;rsquo;s dressing for a year of travel&lt;/a&gt;; I&amp;rsquo;d recommend her post over mine for the ladies.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This uniform thing looked promising. I could wear the same thing every day and still look fashionable? Yes, please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-a-uniform-is-a-good-idea:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Why a Uniform Is a Good Idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I carry everything I own in a bag at least once every couple months.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;excellent&lt;/em&gt; motivation to pack light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing to wear a uniform &lt;em&gt;eliminates options&lt;/em&gt;, which reduces the number of items needed to put outfits together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the simplicity removes a decision from my morning.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:decisions&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:decisions&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; And while I&amp;rsquo;m not making hundreds of critical decisions every day, I do want to cut down on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/08/21/magazine/do-you-suffer-from-decision-fatigue.html?pagewanted=all&#34;&gt;decision fatigue&lt;/a&gt; as much as possible to leave that mental space available for the decisions I actually care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-choose-a-uniform:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;How to Choose a Uniform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it came down to actually &lt;em&gt;choosing&lt;/em&gt; the uniform, I struggled a bit. This is what I&amp;rsquo;ll wear every day, so it should be a really stellar outfit, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should I try to make a statement and rock a huge bowtie like Alber Elbaz? Suit-shorts like Thom Browne?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/alber-elbaz-thom-browne.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Alber Elbaz and Thom Browne&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This might be more than I&#39;m willing to commit to.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should go for the ultra-casual look Steve Jobs and Mark Zuckerberg are known for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I briefly entertained the idea of becoming The Guy In Brightly-Colored Chinos. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;d always wear ostrich boots. Or I could give &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=Craig+Sager&#34;&gt;Craig Sager&lt;/a&gt; a run for his money with my brightly-colored getups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, I started to feel like maybe this was all too much work and something that only the famous and ultra-chic can pull off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-it-simple:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Keep It Simple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a brief existential meltdown — &lt;em&gt;what does fashion even mean, anyways?&lt;/em&gt; — I realized I was horribly overcomplicating the concept. &lt;strong&gt;The entire goal of a uniform is to &lt;em&gt;simplify&lt;/em&gt; your wardrobe,&lt;/strong&gt; not add a bunch of extra work to it. I should be looking at what I &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; wear most of the time, and putting my uniform together from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at my closet and considered how each article of clothing was worn through different seasons. What did I wear year round? What did I only wear for a particular season (and was there a way to replace those items with something less seasonal)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I started thinking along the lines of simplicity, the process became far less overwhelming, and my uniform started coming together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-it-flexible:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Keep It Flexible&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I won&amp;rsquo;t be traveling with a full closet, &lt;strong&gt;my uniform needs to be appropriate for &lt;em&gt;any situation&lt;/em&gt; I find myself in.&lt;/strong&gt; Can I wear it to a fancy steak dinner at an upscale restaurant? A dive bar? A business meeting?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/overdressed.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;overdressed&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Not exactly a practical outfit.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of looking sharp, but packing a tuxedo requires an awful lot of space in my suitcase for a very small number of situations. I needed to look at more moderate options — something that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get me barred from an upscale venue, but that I could also wear in casual situations without looking severely overdressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, I looked at my wardrobe and tried to think of ways that I could take my basic uniform and dress it up or down with a few simple (and easy to carry) accessories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-uniform:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;My Uniform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, my uniform consists of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A solid-colored t-shirt (usually black)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeans or dark chinos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boots or sneakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my base. It&amp;rsquo;s casual on its own, which feels comfortable and easy to manage. (And — truth be told — I&amp;rsquo;m pretending it makes me look like Ryan Gosling.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-ryan-gosling.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf and Ryan Gosling&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Hey girl, do I look like Ryan Gosling in my t-shirt and jeans?

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel comfortable wearing this outfit to nearly any event or meeting I can imagine myself being invited to, and it&amp;rsquo;s very low maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a touch of &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a Grown Up&amp;rdquo; to the outfit, I always wear a reasonably nice watch.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:watch&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:watch&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not one for a lot of accessories, so a watch is usually as far as I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dressing-up-a-uniform:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Dressing Up a Uniform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-blazer.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf wearing a blazer&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  I&#39;m ready to teach that class on postmodern economics now.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tylerdylan.com&#34;&gt;Tyler Dylan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On occasions where I need to look a little fancier, I pack one tweed blazer. Over my jeans, it&amp;rsquo;s only a little dressy; over the chinos it looks almost fancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a blazer isn&amp;rsquo;t right, I also have two sweaters; these dress up the outfit a little bit without looking too dressy. (They also serve a dual purpose, which I&amp;rsquo;ll touch on a bit later.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I&amp;rsquo;d planned to bring a pair of nice (ish) shoes, but I opted to just wear my work boots instead; they &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; look like dress shoes, and I wanted to avoid taking up the extra space in my bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adapting-a-uniform-to-warm-weather:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Adapting a Uniform to Warm Weather&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For warm weather, I have a pair of linen shorts and a pair of board shorts that doubles as a swimming suit. Both are small, so I can roll them up and tuck them into a small crevice in my bag. A t-shirt and shorts is a simple casual outfit, and in warm weather there&amp;rsquo;s not much else I&amp;rsquo;d want to wear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pack a pair of flip flops for warm days and beaches, which also come in handy for shared bathrooms and showers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adapting-a-uniform-to-colder-weather:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Adapting a Uniform to Colder Weather&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/p/xZkDCoIj64/&#34; style=&#34; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;Trying to stay warm&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Marisa (@marisamorby) on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2015-01-03T17:01:20+00:00&#34;&gt;Jan 3, 2015 at 9:01am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that — assuming you&amp;rsquo;re traveling for an extended period of time and you have some control over your schedule — you can usually control the weather for your trip by choosing locations that fall within a range you deem comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal while traveling is to avoid any climate where the temperature drops below 40°F/5°C. This eliminates the need to pack &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; heavy winter gear and simplifies my packing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently pack a light cotton jacket and a slightly heavier overcoat. On their own, these are both great fall weather jackets, and since I tend to be too hot before I&amp;rsquo;m too cold, they&amp;rsquo;re usually more than enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;take-advantage-of-layers:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Take Advantage of Layers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The secret to staying warm with a uniform is layering.&lt;/strong&gt; Those sweaters I mentioned earlier go a long way toward adding some warmth, and fit nicely under my lighter-weight jackets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-cold-weather.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf cold weather options&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  A layered cardigan, a scarf, or both — as warm as you need to be.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tylerdylan.com&#34;&gt;Tyler Dylan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also pack a scarf that looks nice under my lightweight jacket or my overcoat and — using a sweater as a makeshift liner — makes both coats nice and warm as long as the temperature doesn&amp;rsquo;t dip below freezing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I &lt;em&gt;haven&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; packed — and we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I regret it later — is a hat or gloves.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:milan&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:milan&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m usually just fine with my hands in my pockets, and my ears don&amp;rsquo;t get too chilly when the temperature is above freezing.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:bear&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:bear&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-uniform-should-make-sense-for-you:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Your Uniform Should Make Sense for You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My uniform makes perfect sense for my taste: I prefer weather that stays in the sort-of-cool to warm range, where I can wear jeans and a light jacket, so I&amp;rsquo;ve built a uniform around that look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re into winter sports and expect to be in cold climates, your uniform will probably look a little different&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:coldweather&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:coldweather&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from mine. Likewise if all of your travel takes you to tropical climes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you start putting together your uniform, consider three factors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I actually feel comfortable wearing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What type(s) of weather should I be expecting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kind(s) of events, venues, and situations will I find myself in?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answers to those questions help eliminate unnecessary items until you can assemble a uniform that meets all your different needs and maximizes the space in your suitcase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remember-this-is-not-final:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Remember: This Is Not Final&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t bring something and you end up needing it, you can always purchase that item while you&amp;rsquo;re traveling.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:shoppingabroad&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:shoppingabroad&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; If you can&amp;rsquo;t think of a realistic, &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; scenario where you&amp;rsquo;ll use an item, &lt;em&gt;leave it behind.&lt;/em&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t carry around crampons and a pickaxe because you &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; go rock climbing if you meet someone on your travels who is also a rock climber and you&amp;rsquo;re invited; leave that shit behind and rent equipment for the one or two days you&amp;rsquo;ll use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because it fits in your bag doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you need it. And just because you didn&amp;rsquo;t pack it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you can&amp;rsquo;t get it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plans will change. &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/jazz/&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably not going to go exactly the way you&amp;rsquo;re picturing it.&lt;/a&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it: you can adjust as you go along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-wear-a-uniform:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413&#34;&gt;Do You Wear a Uniform?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you consider wearing the same outfit every day? Or does that sound horrible to you? Jump over to the discussion and let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the finer points of fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:fashion&#34;&gt;In high school I was the polar opposite of fashionable: I once wore a form-fitting, ribbed, stretchy, white shirt under a tan fisherman-style vest that would have looked great on a boy band, with grey vinyl pants covered in reflectors (with 45&amp;rdquo; leg openings) and glow-in-the-dark shoes. I wish I was making this shit up.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:fashion&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:decisions&#34;&gt;This was one of the most common reasons the famous folks cited when asked about their uniforms. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pare down decisions. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make decisions about what I&amp;rsquo;m eating or wearing, because I have too many other decisions to make,&amp;rdquo; President Obama told &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vanityfair.com/politics/2012/10/michael-lewis-profile-barack-obama&#34;&gt;Vanity Fair&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:decisions&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:watch&#34;&gt;I would love to graduate to the fancy watches, but that Panerai isn&amp;rsquo;t quite within my reach yet.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:watch&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:milan&#34;&gt;After a week in Milan, I decided it was the right decision not to bring gloves. It was around freezing the whole time, and while gloves wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have hurt, I was also plenty warm with my hands in my pockets.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:milan&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:bear&#34;&gt;The fact that I&amp;rsquo;m about 25% bear doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt; I&amp;rsquo;m more likely to be too warm than too cold.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:bear&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:coldweather&#34;&gt;Probably not too terribly different, though. With long underwear, a winter hat, and warmer socks, I could probably handle fairly cold weather without being too miserable.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:coldweather&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:shoppingabroad&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not traveling in any developing countries — my job required reliable wifi — so I&amp;rsquo;m almost always a short walk away from a clothing store.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:13b359e258b39e3624df2abb8e079413:shoppingabroad&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>