<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Friends on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/friends/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Friends on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 09:54:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/friends/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Men Have Best Friends?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/best-friends</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 09:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/best-friends</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have a best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To say that feels weird. I&amp;rsquo;m almost thirty; thirty-year-old men don&amp;rsquo;t have &amp;ldquo;best friends&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have drinking/golfing/hunting buddies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have their wives&amp;rsquo; friends&amp;rsquo; husbands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they certainly &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; have a Bee Eff Eff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I read Stephen Marche&amp;rsquo;s article for &lt;em&gt;Esquire&lt;/em&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.esquire.com/blogs/culture/on-bro-0914&#34;&gt;the abuse of the word &amp;ldquo;bro&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. I thought it was going to be a silly piece about pop culture, but then I ran into this line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mature as a female person is to mature into female friendships. To mature as a male person is to mature out of male friendships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a sort of shyness I&amp;rsquo;ve felt about telling anyone that I have a best friend. It feels roughly equivalent to admitting I still sleep with a nightlight or that my mom still packs a lunch for me every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a best friend feels like kid stuff. It feels like something I should have grown out of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nate-and-jason-the-best-of-friends:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;Nate and Jason, the Best of Friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/best-friends1.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Nate Green and Jason Lengstorf&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been friends with &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt; since we were eleven or twelve, when his family moved in down the street and our moms set us up on a play date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did all the stuff boys do: played Mortal Kombat&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:fatalities&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:fatalities&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, shot our little brothers with BB guns, pretended we were the Harlem Globetrotters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate and I were opposites in a lot of ways, but we both felt like outsiders — Nate because he didn&amp;rsquo;t quite meet the criteria of any clique, and me because I was in the midst of several simultaneous identity crises — and that held us together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our opposite tendencies were complementary: I did Nate&amp;rsquo;s homework; Nate convinced the cute girls at the beach to hang out with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As adults, Nate and I are still opposites. We still complement each other well personally, and now we&amp;rsquo;re able to help each other professionally.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:symbiosis&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:symbiosis&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-all-need-a-sounding-board:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;We All Need a Sounding Board&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complementary skill sets aside, Nate and I have helped each other in another, less tangible way: over the course of nearly twenty years of friendship, we&amp;rsquo;ve had hundreds of very frank, very honest conversation. The kind that most people have to pay a psychiatrist for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to discuss the things that scared us — being able to be 100% vulnerable, in other words — has allowed us to work through the source of many of our fears and troubles, which has ultimately led to both of us becoming more aware of our internal motivations and the things that trip us up. We&amp;rsquo;re both better people because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; In July 2015, Nate and I decided to make these conversations public in hopes of sparking similar discussions for anyone willing to listen. We&amp;rsquo;ve created a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2FTAT.com?utm_source=best-friends&amp;amp;utm_medium=site-link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=lengstorf-com&#34;&gt;podcast where we have deep conversations&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;em&gt;Two Friends Talking About Things&lt;/em&gt;. You can listen to the first episode here, on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2ftat.com/episode/00-what-are-we-talking-about/?utm_source=best-friends&amp;amp;utm_medium=episode-link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=lengstorf-com&#34;&gt;the website&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/hear2FTAT&#34;&gt;on iTunes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/127426147&amp;color=eb7f00&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=true&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=false&amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-going-to-get-so-much-shit-for-this:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Going to Get So Much Shit for This&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Nate and I were discussing our most recent challenge to each other: write for at least thirty minutes a day and post whatever comes out on our blogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shared one of Nate&amp;rsquo;s posts yesterday. He mentioned that he was planning to share one as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both got uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was it weird that we were publicly giving each other so much attention? Would people make fun of us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did we both feel that way? Everyone who knows us knows that we&amp;rsquo;re close, and neither of us is ashamed of being friends with the other. So where does this apprehension over talking about our friendship on the Internet come from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hollywood-hates-dude-friends:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;Hollywood Hates Dude Friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Marche argues that pop culture is poisoning the idea of male friendship:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The splendid isolation of masculinity has emerged from so much iconography—the cowboy, the astronaut, the gangster—that almost every hero in the past fifty years has been a figure of loneliness. Current pop culture is even more extreme: It doesn&amp;rsquo;t just celebrate the lonely man; it also despises men in groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marche claims most movies and TV shows show groups of men being idiots. &lt;em&gt;The Hangover&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dumb and Dumber&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;How I Met Your Mother&lt;/em&gt; all paint the idea of male friendship as a way to bring out the least intelligent parts of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it explains why I feel apprehensive talking about having a best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-have-a-best-friend:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f&#34;&gt;Do You Have a Best Friend?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I had a solution, or even a suggestion for a solution to the problem. I don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do know that — despite being uneasy saying it out loud — having a close male friend has been one of the most beneficial things in my life, both growing up and as an adult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a best friend? Does it feel weird to talk about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a best friend, does it bother you?&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:honest&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:honest&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:fatalities&#34;&gt;What I mean by &amp;ldquo;played&amp;rdquo; is that I would mash buttons while Nate and his little brother would expertly and brutally murder my character because they knew all the special moves and fatalities. &lt;strong&gt;All of them.&lt;/strong&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:fatalities&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:symbiosis&#34;&gt;I work with Nate to help him implement a lot of his projects that have a design or tech component, and Nate helps me with marketing and networking.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:symbiosis&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:honest&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m genuinely curious, not baiting.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:227e3135c93458ae939fb4f454b60b9f:honest&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bright Side</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/bright-side</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 15:28:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/bright-side</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Every time you talk to another person, you&amp;rsquo;re affecting the way they feel. Try not to make them feel like shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re meeting two people for dinner. One sits down with a smile, making eye contact, sitting up straight, looking pretty happy; the other is despondent, flopped in his chair like a sack of laundry, and studying the palms of his hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now ask about their days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paulie-poopypants:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Paulie Poopypants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The schmoopy one says, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough day. I was late getting to work, and as soon as I showed up my boss dropped this giant project in my lap. And then — as if my day wasn&amp;rsquo;t already bad enough — it was raining after work so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t go to the park like I wanted to.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bobbi-brightside:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Bobbi Brightside&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smiley one says, &amp;ldquo;Today was pretty good! I took an extra-long shower, which was great even though I had to rush to work afterward. I just got a new project at work that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a great challenge — I think if I do well, I might get a promotion. And since it was rainy after work I got a chance to write a letter to a friend I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to send.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;they-re-describing-exactly-the-same-day:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re Describing Exactly the Same Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever someone tells a story, they spin it. Their feelings and motives color the narrative, and we feel — to a certain extent, at least — what they feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that. Because it&amp;rsquo;s huge: &lt;strong&gt;you have the ability to control the moods of the people around you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-fun-to-be-around:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Are You Fun to Be Around?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone wants to feel happy. It&amp;rsquo;s why we seek out things like music and love and beauty; it&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href=&#34;http://illegal-art.net/girltalk/&#34;&gt;Girl Talk&lt;/a&gt; causes spontaneous dance parties; it&amp;rsquo;s why I prefer to hear &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/&#34;&gt;stories with happy endings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have the ability to make me feel happy when I ask about your day. What were the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jlengstorf/stop-glossing-over-the-good-stuff-b89e25f7c714&#34;&gt;good things that happened to you&lt;/a&gt;? What&amp;rsquo;s the bright side? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the best thing about today?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you focus on the negative, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to feel great. And I&amp;rsquo;m going to associate that feeling with you. And if it happens frequently, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start avoiding you, because you&amp;rsquo;re a downer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-to-paulie-and-bobbi:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Back to Paulie and Bobbi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s assume you have the option to hang out with either Paulie Poopypants or Bobbi Brightside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a lot more fun hanging out with Bobbi; positivity is contagious, and optimism cures a lot of ills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of all the people you look forward to spending time with. Are any of those people constantly bringing you down with stories about how hard, unfair, or hopeless things are?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-your-silver-lining:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Find Your Silver Lining&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything has a bright side.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s up to you to let the bright side give you hope instead of letting the challenge bring you down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/eeyore.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Eeyore&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself become an emotional black hole.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you see your glass as half-empty or half-full, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s still your glass.&lt;/strong&gt; And you have to deal with that regardless of your attitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; control is how you frame your circumstances in conversation. Bringing a little sunshine to someone else&amp;rsquo;s day means they&amp;rsquo;ll look forward to your company. And you might even find that projecting positivity outward makes you more inwardly positive as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ask yourself: Are you a source of positivity and happiness for other people? Or are you the Eeyore that shits on everyone else&amp;rsquo;s good time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;Okay, okay, not everything. Some things are irredeemable. But if you have time to read a blog like mine, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to bet that you and I are talking better than 95% First World Problems, here. #realtalk
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Busy for Fun</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/too-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 22:32:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/too-busy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Ali and I got invited to go bouldering with our friends Nate and Chris today. I like Nate, I like Chris, and I like bouldering, but I almost turned them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t up to it, but because I had &amp;ldquo;too much to do&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-too-busy-for-fun:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Too Busy for Fun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Wednesday, I fly to Miami. (My Christmas gift to Ali is a week in warmer weather, though the weather report says we may be headed directly into a thunderstorm.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No later than Friday, I&amp;rsquo;m on the hook for two different logos, a home page design, and two front end builds, plus a bunch of maintenance tasks and revisions on in-progress designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And somewhere in between all that I still have to do the general day-to-day work stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not exactly an easy week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing this, my instinct is to go &lt;em&gt;Full Metal Hermit&lt;/em&gt; and decline any and all social invitations, opting instead for sixteen-hour coding binges fueled by espresso and pizza delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just crank until it&amp;rsquo;s done, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rush-binge-repeat:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798&#34;&gt;Rush, Binge, Repeat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I would have done. I would have buried myself in my todo list — at the expense of my physical and emotional health — for the sake of my getting everything on my list knocked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list would get done, but I&amp;rsquo;d be burned out, and &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d spend a week recovering from the marathon.&lt;/strong&gt; Meanwhile, my todo list would keep growing, and I&amp;rsquo;d find myself fully recovered just in time for the next marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something was broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;less-time-to-work-inspires-higher-quality-work:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798&#34;&gt;Less Time to Work Inspires Higher-Quality Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of one of these binges, I made the decision to try something different the next time: instead of cutting off my social life, &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d accept every invitation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798:within-reason&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798:within-reason&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and try to actually enjoy my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started going to happy hours, and watching football games, and lots of other things that were fun for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weird part, though, was that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t falling behind. In fact, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was getting more done.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-work-and-no-play:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798&#34;&gt;All Work and No Play&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t officially measured this, but I think the reasons being more social led me to get more done are twofold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was a finite window of time in which I could get work done, which prevented me from screwing around &lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was taking breaks, which prevented the burnout that work binges would cause&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-it-s-important-make-time:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798&#34;&gt;If It&amp;rsquo;s Important, Make Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-rock-climbing.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf rock climbing at the Circuit Bouldering Gym in Portland, OR.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I put on a tough act, but I&amp;rsquo;m only about 10&amp;rdquo; off the ground in this photo.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today, I went bouldering. I had breakfast with my friends afterward. And you know what? &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll still get my list finished.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m even hopeful that, with my upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-experiment/&#34;&gt;No Distractions Experiment&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, I might actually catch up for one fleeting, glorious afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Building a work-life balance has helped me strengthen my social life &lt;strong&gt;and boosted my productivity&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; but if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t questioned my instinct, I might still be lonely and burned out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How&amp;rsquo;s your work:life balance? Let me know on the popular social networking site known as Bookface.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798:office&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798:office&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/21460573@N08/6594353823/&#34;&gt;Mark J P&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798:within-reason&#34;&gt;Within reason. If I had two or three invitations on the same day, I would sometimes pass.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798:within-reason&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798:office&#34;&gt;Quote lifted without a hint of shame from &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2dbe17c7cd00fe0c776a6f2c7b70c798:office&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>