<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Failure on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/failure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Failure on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 13:09:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/failure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocketships and Bicycles</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/rocketships-bicycles</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 13:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/rocketships-bicycles</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time with my head in the clouds. To me, the best ideas are the ones unhindered by trifles like logistics. Or reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question I always start with is: &lt;em&gt;If I had unlimited time, capital, and resources, what would I build?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s impractical, sure, but to me it removes a critical barrier in my planning process. Instead of asking, &amp;ldquo;What am I capable of?&amp;rdquo; I ask, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s possible?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/rocketship-goal-setting-lg.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;aim high when setting goals&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Dream big.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-with-what-s-possible-not-what-s-practical:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;Start with What&amp;rsquo;s Possible, Not What&amp;rsquo;s Practical&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want to get from Point A to Point B, I have a problem to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I start designing a solution, I&amp;rsquo;m not thinking about what I&amp;rsquo;ve built before, or what I think I might be able to build with my current level of knowledge; I&amp;rsquo;m only thinking of what — given unlimited resources in a perfect world — I would &lt;em&gt;ideally&lt;/em&gt; like to see built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To travel from Point A to Point B, &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to build a rocketship.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the actual process of planning the rocketship build gets underway, I&amp;rsquo;ll start worrying about practicalities. Features will be stripped away until the solution becomes feasible, and often times my rocketship will become nothing more than a simple bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-real-life-example-of-setting-ideal-outcomes:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;A Real-Life Example of Setting Ideal Outcomes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently kicked off an experiment in permanent travel and digital nomadism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a number of theories about productivity, work-life balance, and overall happiness that fundamentally changed the way I look at the world. Ultimately, these theories led to me &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;selling off my possessions and wandering off to see the world&lt;/a&gt;, bringing only what I could fit in a carry-on suitcase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 25px auto; max-width:500px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/p/xTidrIzK7-/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Jason Lengstorf (@jlengstorf)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2015-01-01T08:52:03+00:00&#34;&gt;Jan 1, 2015 at 12:52am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think these theories can be helpful to people other than myself, and I want to share them. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have a big audience, or any favors to call in with big influencers. So how do I get the word out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the problem I need to solve.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignoring time restraints, lack of connections, and my ignorance with respect to how to actually make any of this &lt;em&gt;happen,&lt;/em&gt; I defined my rocketship:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a book on the subject, and get it picked up by a major publisher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch a media onslaught by publishing guest articles &lt;em&gt;everywhere.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak at conferences around the world to share my theories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue to publish on my blog and grow my newsletter list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This combined effort will put my theories in front of millions of people, and — with a little luck — help improve lives around the world. &lt;strong&gt;This is my &amp;ldquo;perfect world&amp;rdquo; outcome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I put the work in and figure out what&amp;rsquo;s possible and practical, the goals will get progressively more and more modest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end, it may turn out that what I &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do is more along these lines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read all the research I can to back up my theories with hard data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I write one or two articles on my blog sharing the data in a useful way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few hundred people read what I wrote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One person uses the information as a catalyst for real, positive change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be my bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will it change the world? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But did it accomplish my original goal: to communicate what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in a clear and well-researched fashion to as many people as possible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Even if &amp;ldquo;as many people as possible&amp;rdquo; turns out to be a smaller number than I&amp;rsquo;d hoped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/goal-setting-bicycle.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;setting goals: a bicycle is almost as good as a rocketship&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  A bicycle may not be a perfect solution, but progress is progress.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect the bicycle outcome to result in a biopic about me, I also wouldn&amp;rsquo;t consider it in any way a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bicycle is not a rocketship. But a bicycle &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-are-you-defining-failure:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;How Are You Defining Failure?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But if I designed a rocketship and only built a bicycle, haven&amp;rsquo;t I missed my goal and failed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If failure to you is &amp;ldquo;any outcome that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly match the initial plan&amp;rdquo;, then sure, the bicycle is a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, however, isn&amp;rsquo;t with the plan or the design; the problem is an inaccurate definition of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rocketship isn&amp;rsquo;t the goal.&lt;/strong&gt; The rocketship is &lt;em&gt;a proposed solution.&lt;/em&gt; The &lt;em&gt;goal&lt;/em&gt; is to get from Point A to Point B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this perspective, any progress is progress. By thinking big and editing along the way, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably still get further than you would have been if you aim low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you design a rocketship and end up with a bicycle, you came up short of your ideal solution — but you have a viable, practical means of getting from Point A to Point B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, &lt;em&gt;even though you didn&amp;rsquo;t build the rocketship, you still accomplished the original goal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/unicycle-goal-setting.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;unicycle&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Hedging bets can lead to impractical solutions.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/the1andonlycary/&#34;&gt;Cary Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you hedge your bets and design a bicycle, you don&amp;rsquo;t have any wiggle room in your proposed solution. If you end up with a unicycle (or maybe just a wheel), you either have an impractical means of getting yourself around — unicycles are difficult to learn to ride, after all — or, worse, a concept that &lt;em&gt;theoretically&lt;/em&gt; moves you from Point A to Point B, but lacks some of the required equipment to make it usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-the-definition-of-failure-works-in-reality:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;How the Definition of Failure Works in Reality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have choices when I think about sharing my experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, I could look at the goal as &amp;ldquo;get a book published&amp;rdquo; — this is a lofty goal, and very specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also only part of what I was originally setting out to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I could look at the goal as &amp;ldquo;tell as many people as possible about my ideas for improving our quality of life&amp;rdquo; — this is what I originally wanted to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I do the work and manage to get a book published, &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made an enormous amount of progress&lt;/strong&gt; toward sharing my findings with as many people as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if I do everything else on my rocketship list &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; publishing a book — guest posts, speaking gigs, and all — but I&amp;rsquo;m looking at the rocketship as the &lt;em&gt;goal&lt;/em&gt; and not the &lt;em&gt;means to that goal&lt;/em&gt;, I would still feel like a failure because the book didn&amp;rsquo;t get published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a counterproductive way to look at things, because if I can do four of the five things on my rocketship list, a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; amount of people will be exposed to my ideas. Just because I didn&amp;rsquo;t tick all the boxes shouldn&amp;rsquo;t — and doesn&amp;rsquo;t — mean all of my efforts were in vain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I lose sight of &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m trying to do in favor of &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m going to do it, I risk setting an impossible standard and feeling like a failure, despite otherwise making good progress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/upgraded-car.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;drifting car&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Start simple and upgrade over time.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/xavier33300/&#34;&gt;SuperCar-RoadTrip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-constant-improvement-to-start-fast-and-steadily-get-faster:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;Use Constant Improvement to Start Fast and Steadily Get Faster&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparatively, a rocketship will complete the goal &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; faster than a bicycle, so it can feel hopeless to only have a bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, if the bicycle you&amp;rsquo;ve built is reliable, it ceases to be something you have to worry about. You no longer need to design the solution; you only need to spend time on maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves you free to build improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing that progress — albeit slow — is being made, you can add new features. A motor. Chassis. Wings. Autopilot. Espresso machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A bicycle doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to &lt;em&gt;remain&lt;/em&gt; a bicycle. And in many cases, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, the bicycle can become a motorcycle, which can become a race car, then a plane, and — eventually — a goddamn rocketship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these solutions is better than the one from which it evolved: a motorcycle is fast; a plane is faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be tempting to say, &amp;ldquo;Well, fine: I can&amp;rsquo;t build a rocketship. But I will build a race car, because I know I can do that, and altogether skip the part where I have that slow bicycle!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The catch is that a bicycle might take a month to build, where a race car may take a year. How much would the slow progress of the bicycle add up in the eleven months between?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how much of a delay would it cause to start with a bicycle, then improve it to become a race car?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting with a simple solution creates a Progress Snowball.&lt;/strong&gt; The solution allows you to quickly start making slow progress, and each subsequent improvement improves the speed, bit by bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/progress-snowball-goal-setting.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;progress snowball in goal setting&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The Progress Snowball: At first it feels painfully slow, and then — suddenly — everything changes.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-practical-example-of-steady-improvement:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;A Practical Example of Steady Improvement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I initially started planning for my experiment, I wanted to do it all at once: launch a huge number of guest posts simultaneously, push a ton of content out on my blog, kick off a targeted social media campaign, hit the conference circuits hard as a speaker, and send off my book manuscript to publishers while the online buzz was in full swing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would have been, if not a rocketship, at least a race car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I looked at it objectively, it was too much for me to take on. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t abandon my blog for months to work on this material, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spread myself thin by committing to writing for my blog &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; keeping up with my day job &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; writing a book-length work plus additional articles. After all, my whole message is to &lt;em&gt;avoid&lt;/em&gt; working long hours, and I want to make sure I&amp;rsquo;m able to succeed while practicing what I intend to preach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My race car design also would have required convincing a bunch of sites who don&amp;rsquo;t know me at all to both publish a guest post from me &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; to run it on a timeframe that was to my benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I&amp;rsquo;d be unhappy if I lost momentum on my blog, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I&amp;rsquo;d be able to get all — or any — of the guest blogs accepted if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have at least a little bit of supporting material up beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I chose a bicycle: regular posts on my own blog, a few things on Medium, and a concentrated effort to keep up my social media accounts in a way that was engaging and mostly on-message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This created the slow progress that I&amp;rsquo;m seeing now, while I work on researching and creating material for the book, for guest posts, and for speaking engagements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since creating the bicycle, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to book a few speaking gigs on the topic, and opened up conversations with a few of the sites I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to guest blog for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still not a race car, but it might pass for a moped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m a long way from done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-your-rocketship:5247d43ddad16f7933cab145f363f1b7&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Your Rocketship?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at your current goals, how are you planning to achieve them? Are you paralyzed, feeling that the goal is beyond your grasp? Are you tentative, making modest plans that feel safe? Are you feeling hopeless, creating impossible standards for yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust yourself, and to keep working on a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan as if anything is possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that any progress is good progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never stop thinking of ways to improve your progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may find yourself on a bicycle to start, but before long you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself further along than you ever thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Shoot for the moon. Even if you miss, you&amp;rsquo;ll land among the stars.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Norman Vincent Peale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Yourself on Fire</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 08:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I use the term &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;set yourself on fire&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; frequently. To me, it means a sink-or-swim moment: &lt;strong&gt;you&amp;rsquo;ll either find a way to put this fire out, or you&amp;rsquo;re toast.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It removes the option to fail just a little bit. You now either make this work, or you go down hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, and for most people I know, this is both horribly frightening and incredibly motivating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-drawing-garfield-to-marketing-a-band:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;From Drawing Garfield to Marketing a Band&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/minusmythoughts.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;MinusMyThoughts&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tysonvick.com&#34;&gt;Tyson Vick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a musician&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, we had no income. On tour, we were lucky to get paid $100 for a show, and sometimes we could pull together $50 in sales from the merch table. It barely covered gas to get to the next city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no budget whatsoever, so things like &amp;ldquo;marketing budgets&amp;rdquo; were never even discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was a need for marketing: tour posters, merchandise, album art, web banners, MySpace customizations, a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no one to do the work. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to hire help, and none of us knew anything about that stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured, &amp;ldquo;I drew pictures of Garfield and the Ninja Turtles when I was a kid; I can figure out a tour poster.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no experience, and no idea what I was doing. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any reason that I would fail. So &lt;strong&gt;I set myself on fire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The posters weren&amp;rsquo;t great. But they also weren&amp;rsquo;t terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MySpace page went through several iterations, all of which were — let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, here — pretty MySpacey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first website I built &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20040718012243/http://minusmythoughts.com/&#34;&gt;was horrible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It was a table-based layout with no CSS, and it used iframes for content. But goddammit, if you clicked our &amp;ldquo;shows&amp;rdquo; link, you saw a list of shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it sucked. But it worked. &lt;strong&gt;And I fucking &lt;em&gt;built&lt;/em&gt; that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-a-dude-in-a-band-to-a-web-designer:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;From a Dude in a Band to a Web Designer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the few years that my band was touring, I rebuilt that website over a dozen times. At first because I could see the horrible mistakes I was making, but then it just became a fun thing for me to do in the downtime between soundcheck and going onstage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the band broke up, my friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;Nate Green&lt;/a&gt; asked me if I&amp;rsquo;d help him build a website for his new personal brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how to build a website someone else could manage, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any reason that I would fail. &lt;strong&gt;I set myself on fire again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate&amp;rsquo;s website &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20070910075625/http://www.thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t ground-breaking&lt;/a&gt;, but it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate&amp;rsquo;s business grew, and I was suddenly a web designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-life-slightly-singed:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;My Life, Slightly Singed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenges over the years have changed, but I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to keep my response consistent: I can handle that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I look at a challenge and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t put anyone in danger — I&amp;rsquo;m not going to volunteer to build a rocket or perform open-heart surgery, here — I&amp;rsquo;ll take it on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can back that trailer into the boat slip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can cook a turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each of these scenarios (all of which are real moments in my life), I had never done the thing I had just told someone I was able to do. But I trusted myself to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I set myself on fire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every case, I figured it out. I moved slowly, I did a &lt;em&gt;shitload&lt;/em&gt; of Googling, and in the end I delivered a result that was good enough to make everyone involved happy. And with practice, I&amp;rsquo;ll get to the point that it&amp;rsquo;s just a thing I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-yourself-on-fire:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21&#34;&gt;Set Yourself on Fire&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you trying to learn right now? Have you been putting it off? How can you remove your safety net so you &lt;em&gt;have to learn it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you set yourself on fire in the past? Or been set on fire by someone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit the discussion link and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;I use the term &amp;ldquo;musician&amp;rdquo; loosely, here.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:musician&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t actually the &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; first site. The Wayback Machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a copy of it, unfortunately.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9431170ccd992ac112bba84aebb91c21:wayback&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See the Tree Coming</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When I fail, I&amp;rsquo;m presented with a choice: do I learn nothing, learn one thing, or learn a life lesson?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that sounds ridiculous. Of &lt;em&gt;course&lt;/em&gt; I should learn a life lesson, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for me, at least, learning something valuable from failure hasn&amp;rsquo;t always been easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-treadmill-treadmill:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The Treadmill Treadmill&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me try to explain with a story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled for years to stay consistent with my trips to the gym. I would get inspired, find a workout program, pick a diet plan, write a detailed daily fitness agenda, and start planning how I&amp;rsquo;d handle the dozens of beautiful women who would undoubtedly be throwing themselves at me in the coming weeks.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, despite my initial optimism, I&amp;rsquo;d find myself feeling discouraged, making excuses, and eventually abandoning the whole idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was failing. And I was being presented with a choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-five-times-i-failed-in-exactly-the-same-way:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The First Five Times I Failed In Exactly the Same Way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I made the choice to learn nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made excuses. I blamed external circumstances. I tried to convince myself that I was just better off ignoring my health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d brush it off, the memory would fade, and eventually I&amp;rsquo;d start the cycle over again &amp;ndash; only to fail in exactly the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was learning nothing, and it showed in my embarrassing lack of progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-next-five-times-i-failed-creatively:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The Next Five Times I Failed Creatively&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I recognized that I was stuck in a loop, I started choosing to learn one thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I learned that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good at working out first thing in the morning. Then I learned I couldn&amp;rsquo;t always make the afternoons work. After that I discovered that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sustain a chicken-and-steamed-broccoli diet like my bodybuilder friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time I failed again, I was learning one thing &amp;ndash; one precise set of circumstances &amp;ndash; that led to my failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-last-time-i-failed-i-learned:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The Last Time I Failed, I Learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After repeating this cycle maybe a dozen times, I finally took a step back and thought about my situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I was, trying to stay consistent with a plan to make myself healthier &amp;ndash; what better motivation is there? &amp;ndash; and somehow &lt;em&gt;I was failing every time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d learned lots of &amp;ldquo;one thing&amp;rdquo; lessons, but I&amp;rsquo;d never taken the time to examine the root of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was treating the symptoms instead of the disease.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I analyzed, and I ultimately came to the conclusion that the common thread in all my failures was that I gave up after I started to fail: if I missed a workout or had some ice cream, I felt like I&amp;rsquo;d ruined everything and just gave up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an &amp;ldquo;all or nothing&amp;rdquo; type. So when I made a plan, I had to execute it flawlessly or I was wasting my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I learned a life lesson: &lt;strong&gt;I need to set my bar low enough that I can always hit my goal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans started out as, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to do this huge workout and eat exactly these things.&amp;rdquo; The simple lowering of that bar to, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to do something active every day and make sure I eat vegetables with every meal,&amp;rdquo; has made it possible for me to always hit my goal, and as a result I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed consistent for nearly a year now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To clarify, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that I set low expectations that allow me to skate by. I&amp;rsquo;m just adjusting the definition of &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; so that I can sustainably hit my goals. If my goal is &amp;ldquo;just get to the gym, even if you show up, turn around, and go back home,&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve set the bar really low. However, while I&amp;rsquo;ve been to the gym and done a less-than-stellar workout, I&amp;rsquo;ve never showed up to the gym and done &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no picture of perfect human health or anything, but I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; climb stairs without wheezing and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any aches or pains &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s all I really need to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m taking care of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-working-out.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf working out&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One of my &amp;ldquo;get moving&amp;rdquo; activities: conditioning class at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elementalfitnesslab.com/&#34;&gt;Elemental Fitness Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-the-source:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;Finding the Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the obvious benefit to my physical well-being, dealing with my failures taught me one of the most useful life skills I&amp;rsquo;ve come across yet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you fail, try to understand &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you failed instead of just learning how to avoid repeating this one mistake.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I run into a tree, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t just glare at the tree and then go about my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t just make a note of where the tree is so I can avoid it next time I pass this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I should try to understand why I didn&amp;rsquo;t see the tree coming in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-practice:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond my fitness goals, this approach to failure has helped me in every area of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s helped me understand that when I lose clients, it&amp;rsquo;s not because that client is beyond help or because I worded something incorrectly; it&amp;rsquo;s because I violated their expectations, which put them on edge and started a downward spiral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s helped me understand that when I end up fighting with my girlfriend, it&amp;rsquo;s not because she&amp;rsquo;s irrational or because I&amp;rsquo;m too detached; it&amp;rsquo;s because I made her feel attacked, or unimportant, or a similarly unsavory emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This applies to dozens of other examples that I could have brushed past as one-off incidents (or worse, forgotten entirely). Each failure gives me a little window into how I&amp;rsquo;m perceived by others, or how I&amp;rsquo;m wired, and it allows me to &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; my personality &amp;ndash; I can see certain trees coming and avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll hit hundreds more trees &amp;ndash; thousands even &amp;ndash; as I continue to grow and learn and fail, but if I&amp;rsquo;m doing this right, they won&amp;rsquo;t be the same trees all that often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/27139502@N00/460096222/&#34;&gt;Andy Cox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;I had this all worked out: there would be a reality show where these women would showcase their intelligence, strength, and wit through a Billy Madison-esque decathlon featuring such events as &amp;ldquo;Carry Me Up the Stairs as if I&amp;rsquo;ve Been Injured&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Write Me a Haiku About Bears&amp;rdquo;. There would be laughter, tears, strategy, and a Final Challenge that probably involved the Nerf guns from &lt;em&gt;American Gladiators&lt;/em&gt;. The series would be met with lackluster reviews, but a strong cult following.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;The big difference here is &lt;em&gt;framing&lt;/em&gt;. Before, when I was failing, doing a quick workout because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling 100% would constitute a failure; now, I look at &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; workout being better than no workout. Get it?
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>