<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storytelling on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/category/storytelling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storytelling on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 10:03:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/category/storytelling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stories We Tell Ourselves</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/stories</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 10:03:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/stories</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t regret anything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done that I saw through to the end. I only regret things I left unfinished, or never started at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-journey-is-the-story:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;The Journey Is the Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I tell you that a guy named Billy Ray Valentine was a successful investor and made a killing in the commodities market, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t bat an eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever, right? Lots of people are good at their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I tell you that Mr. Valentine came from the gutter and &lt;em&gt;got his job on a bet&lt;/em&gt;, things get a little more interesting.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/stories1.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;stories&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-good-story-isn-t-about-the-ending:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;A Good Story Isn&amp;rsquo;t About the Ending&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all love a good story. &lt;em&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s too easy to mistake the ending for the whole story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The journey is what makes a story good.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s the details. The twists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, stories don&amp;rsquo;t have to end well. Heroes can lose. Main characters can die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll allow any ending, as long as the story is good.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-lives-are-a-collection-of-short-stories:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;Our Lives Are a Collection of Short Stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we don&amp;rsquo;t sit around at dinner telling tales, &lt;strong&gt;our lives exist as a series of stories.&lt;/strong&gt; We tell these stories to ourselves, to our friends, to potential employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/bright-side/&#34;&gt;spin our stories&lt;/a&gt; and use them to create little vignettes of who we are and what we value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strangers use them to make us real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our stories become the only part of us that anyone else really touches.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-good-story-has-a-follow-through:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;Every Good Story Has a Follow-Through&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, even though the guts of a story lie in the journey, every story still needs to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it needs to &lt;em&gt;really end.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the plot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/WTy0QP&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cool Runnings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was the story of that time Derice Bannock was accidentally tripped by an opponent in the 1988 Summer Olympics qualifier before giving up on his Olympic dreams, the story would have felt incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Derice took his failure and pushed onward — and ultimately &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=31M_MdSVxV8&#34;&gt;failed again, sort of&lt;/a&gt; — and it makes for a great story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-up-to-us-to-make-our-stories-good:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Up to Us to Make Our Stories Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a choice with every story we begin: &amp;ldquo;Am I going to see this through to the end, or am I going to give up and leave the story unfinished?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When things get difficult, we can always bail and walk away. And sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s how a story needs to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for every story we leave unfinished, we&amp;rsquo;re building a narrative around ourselves. Are we leaving more stories unfinished than we&amp;rsquo;re seeing through to the end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-your-stories-say-about-you:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;What Do Your Stories Say About You?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you play back your stories in your head, do you feel good about them?&lt;/strong&gt; Or do they feel like a collection of half-finished anecdotes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that — regardless of how your stories read so far — you&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of a few stories right now. And you&amp;rsquo;ll start new stories in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to make them good ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;If you want to know Billy Ray&amp;rsquo;s full story, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/X7sjiL&#34;&gt;watch the documentary&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Montana</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 17:46:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Years back, before I moved to Portland, I used to haunt a bar called Al&amp;rsquo;s and Vic&amp;rsquo;s in Missoula, Montana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of those dives where it was too loud to hear yourself think and the floor was &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; sticky, but they sold a bucket of PBR for four dollars, and a Montana Happy Meal&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a night where I&amp;rsquo;d been called in as wingman for Scott, we met with his date and — for the span of a beer — I did my best not to make him sound like a degenerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His date, whose name I don&amp;rsquo;t remember but whose face looked like a Bernadette, told us her friends were arriving and would we mind standing at the bar with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette introduced us to her friends, Mandy and Kate. Mandy, it turns out, was a friend of Scott&amp;rsquo;s, and the two of them pulled Bernadette into conversation, leaving Kate and I to fend for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate was beautiful. Like, &lt;em&gt;holy shit&lt;/em&gt; good-looking — the kind of attractive that usually requires about a grand&amp;rsquo;s worth of Photoshop cleanup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, on the other hand, was wearing a cowboy shirt with pearl snaps, sporting an extra twenty pounds or so, and unshaven in the not-sexy way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, despite my homeless desperado ensemble, we hit it off immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was funny, sharp-witted. I was scrambling to keep up, but she was laughing. The hoarse mating calls of a hundred college kids were muffled under the sound of her voice, like bourbon over fine-grit sandpaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The faces around us blurred and faded; it was just me and Kate and my beer and her whisky diet and this moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain was leaking that special cocktail of chemicals that only happens the first time you make a connection with someone. In that moment I understood how people can meet and fall in love and end up making long-term promises to each other in front of an Elvis impersonator — all in the span of one intense night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spark between us had magnetized the air; my heart was trying to pull out of my chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette reappeared over Kate&amp;rsquo;s shoulder, and the room snapped back into focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandy was with her, and Scott returned a moment later with a fresh bucket of beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott gave me a &lt;em&gt;how&amp;rsquo;d it go for you&lt;/em&gt; look. I tried not to look upset about the interruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls did their secret eye contact telepathy thing, and Bernadette started preparing her exit. Mandy and Kate took her cue and started gathering their purses and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate caught my eye as she swung her coat around her shoulders, and my heart went all squishy and weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I formed the words in my brain — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number&lt;/em&gt; — opened my mouth to speak — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number, you idiot!&lt;/em&gt; — and I said, &amp;ldquo;It was really nice meeting you. Have a great night.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She might have hesitated. I was too disgusted with myself to notice. The next thing I knew I was watching her hair bounce in the red bar-glow as she walked away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of running after her, telling her I couldn&amp;rsquo;t let her get away without knowing I could see her again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s romantic? Probably creepy. Better not.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of asking Scott for Bernadette&amp;rsquo;s number so I could call her and ask for Kate&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s even worse. Stop it. All of your ideas are bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did nothing. I watched the door close behind her. My mouth was probably hanging open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Scotty — never one to pass up a kidney punch — said, &amp;ldquo;Blew that one, huh?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the beer he offered and did a poor job of acting nonchalant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You know who she is, right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shook my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a special kind of schadenfreude that only men experience. It occurs when we watch a friend — hitting it off with a woman who is clearly out of his league — suddenly and spectacularly self-destruct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a teeball benchwarmer. Kate was one good season away from the big show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scotty was so darkly gleeful he should have been stroking a Persian cat as he said, &amp;ldquo;She was Miss Montana last year.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goddammit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot with Miss Montana, and I let her walk out of the bar. After fifteen minutes of great conversation and good chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replayed the moments before she left in my head. I met her eyes. &lt;em&gt;She was waiting for you to ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot. I did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-wasted-second-chance:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;The (Wasted) Second Chance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks later, I was out with Scotty again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was late, and we had slunk into the bar everyone despised. The sign on the door said &amp;ldquo;Bodega&amp;rdquo;, but it may has well have been called You&amp;rsquo;re Hammered Again &amp;amp; None of the Girls Will Talk to You, Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out front, I bummed a cigarette off a stranger and wobbled gently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jason?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wheeled and found myself facing Kate. I immediately stamped out my cigarette. I could feel the air starting to magnetize again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate smiled. And then she hugged me. Her hair smelled like vanilla-scented heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smelled like an ashtray full of whiskey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So how are you?&amp;rdquo; I managed to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Great! Oh, by the way, these are my brothers, Jeff and Mark,&amp;rdquo; she said, motioning to the two frighteningly large men who flanked her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded. They nodded back, then pretended not to pay attention while this drunken asshole in front of The Saddest Bar in Missoula tried to flirt with their sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow we just fell back into it. She teased me about my smoking, I poked fun at the shoes she was carrying, and we both laughed. My heart did the squishy-weird thing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it was time to make the move. Her brothers weren&amp;rsquo;t going to stand there all night, and I needed to head back inside before Scott ordered me any more drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried scraping every last bit of courage off the walls of my rib cage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just ask. Ask for her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to think of a line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a line, dickhead: &amp;ldquo;Can I get your number and call you sometime?&amp;rdquo; Just. Ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I caught eyes with the larger of her two brothers. And then I wondered if I&amp;rsquo;d misread the whole situation and she was just being nice to me. And then I froze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, hey, it was great seeing you again. I should probably get back inside.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idiot. Idiot. Idiot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flushed. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even make eye contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As suddenly as she&amp;rsquo;d appeared, Kate — Miss Montana — the gorgeous, funny girl I love-at-first-sighted (twice) was gone into the night. For good this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lost-in-the-woulds:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;Lost in the Woulds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would have been a great couple. She would have had a secret family recipe for waffles and a mean Scrabble game. Maybe her disturbingly attractive genes would compensate for my hairiness and we&amp;rsquo;d make the world&amp;rsquo;s hottest babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She would have shot me down. We&amp;rsquo;d have only had another thirty seconds of good conversation left in us. She would have had a boyfriend. I would have hated her guts after two weeks of hanging out. Or, more likely, she&amp;rsquo;d have hated mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand wonderful memories, starting with the one where I asked if I could call and she said yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand mistakes and alienated myself from the Montana Beautiful Women&amp;rsquo;s Club&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any of those outcomes would have been fine. Even bad experiences are still &lt;em&gt;experiences&lt;/em&gt;, you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;em&gt;wondering!&lt;/em&gt; The wondering is murder. There&amp;rsquo;s no lesson to learn in &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s just the nagging of an unanswered question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, I&amp;rsquo;m not the guy who took a long shot with a beauty queen and succeeded against the odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also not the guy who took a shot and missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just a guy who had a shot and stood there looking foolish while the clock ran out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;A shot of Jameson with a PBR back.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;Totally a thing.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enough with the Sad Stories</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 13:34:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I watched Robert Redford die &amp;ndash; slowly and tortuously &amp;ndash; for two hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was watching his new movie, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2017038/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;All Is Lost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is &lt;strong&gt;killing it&lt;/strong&gt; on Rotten Tomatoes (currently rocking a 94% rating). I left the theater feeling heavy, sad, despondent. It was rough. I didn&amp;rsquo;t much care for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/75824994?color=e26700&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;422&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say &lt;em&gt;All Is Lost&lt;/em&gt; is a bad movie. It&amp;rsquo;s well-made, and Robert Redford is a solid actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Jesus! what a draining way to spend an afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-nineteen-year-old-self-is-so-ashamed-right-now:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;My Nineteen-Year-Old Self Is So Ashamed Right Now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;rsquo;m saying all this as Present Tense Jason, who is very different from Jason of Yore; in fact, the latter would spit right in my face for what I&amp;rsquo;m about to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten (somewhat) older and seen (a bit) more of the world, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost interest in the movies that used to top my list. Gone are the days of repeated viewings of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1g5XH57&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Clockwork Orange&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; no longer do I want to sit down and really &lt;strong&gt;experience&lt;/strong&gt; a film like &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzt.to/1crskxC&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Requiem for a Dream&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still think they&amp;rsquo;re good movies &amp;ndash; great ones, even &amp;ndash; but god&lt;em&gt;damn&lt;/em&gt; are they depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid it was important to me that my movie choices felt authentic, and didn&amp;rsquo;t cloud the story with fluffy Hollywood nonsense. I wanted heroes who could die, and stories that twisted and turned and gave you hope before killing the main character &amp;ndash; y&amp;rsquo;know, because life is like that sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;art-imitating-life:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;Art Imitating Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year I read about some movie that raises the bar for authenticity. Some &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1hlY1Rb&#34;&gt;movie about Osama Bin Laden&lt;/a&gt; put all the actors through real military training, or some French filmmaker had his actors &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1dgPXu0&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; have sex during the love scenes&lt;/a&gt;. Even the superhero movies are coming up with as-plausible-as-you-can-make-a-superhero-backstory origin stories &amp;ndash; apparently so we can all avoid the burden of suspending our disbelief for 105 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all pushing toward a true-to-life experience. And a good portion of it is terribly hard to watch because it&amp;rsquo;s so depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-em-laugh:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;Make &amp;lsquo;Em Laugh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take away my cinephile card if you want, but these days, I just want to be entertained, not bashed in the skull repeatedly with an emotional sledgehammer. I&amp;rsquo;m sick of feeling bad when the credits start rolling, or after finishing a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to hear a great story about characters that make me want to be better, filled with heroes who win by being smarter and more determined than the villains; about couples who believe so deeply in true love that even insurmountable obstacles can be surmounted; about wizened old mentors who teach just the right lesson at just the right moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I want things to work out in the end.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know life is hard, and that not everything ends well. There are little reminders of life&amp;rsquo;s hardships and inconveniences all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, then, would I want additional reminders while I&amp;rsquo;m trying to relax and take my mind &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; the world&amp;rsquo;s ills?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-be-awesome:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;Just Be Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I want nothing but romantic comedies. I just want more stories involving people being awesome, and that leave me feeling better than when I started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t show me &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1crujSA&#34;&gt;Paul Giamatti slowly self-destructing&lt;/a&gt; in a moody downward spiral. Instead, show me Cary Elwes &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1a6pCBD&#34;&gt;outsmarting Sicilians and besting giants&lt;/a&gt; to rescue his true love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your favorite feel-good movies and books?&lt;/strong&gt; Let me know in the Facebook discussion!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>