<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Worklifebalance on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/worklifebalance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Worklifebalance on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 04:10:02 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/worklifebalance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Work: Are We Just Working for Work&#39;s Sake?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/work-to-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 04:10:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/work-to-live/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to remember that we don&amp;rsquo;t live to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultural pressure is high to have a good job, and to work hard in that job to get a better job. To make more money so we can buy more stuff. To work the hardest and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/&#34;&gt;sacrifice&lt;/a&gt; the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stigmatize leisure as the mark of someone who won&amp;rsquo;t get far in life. We furrow our brows disapprovingly at the high school graduate who wants to take a year or two off before deciding what to study in college (or whether they should go at all). We look down on the smart kid who works a part-time job because he&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;not living up to his potential.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does all that really mean? Do leisure time, taking a break to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/growing-up-vs-growing-older/&#34;&gt;find yourself&lt;/a&gt;, and working just hard enough to get by really signify a problem? Or are we uncomfortable with the idea of valuing something else over work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can feel a lot like the latter in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t live to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We work to live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/dont-live-to-work-work-to-live.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;we don&amp;#39;t live to work; we work to live&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  What are you working for?

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-work-to-have-freedom:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;We Work to Have Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was eleven, I wanted a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nintendo_64&#34;&gt;Nintendo 64&lt;/a&gt; in the worst way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at $200, my chances were slim. I got a weekly allowance of $10, so by my estimation it would be a thousand years before I&amp;rsquo;d saved up enough to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to beg my parents and promise that they&amp;rsquo;d never have to buy me anything ever again&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in order to get one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 14 I got my first job washing dishes at a local restaurant. My first paycheck blew me away: I&amp;rsquo;d made over $160&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in just two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the next gaming console rolled out, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to beg anyone for it — I could buy it with my own money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The freedom that I felt when I made my first big purchase with money I&amp;rsquo;d earned at my job was intoxicating.&lt;/strong&gt; I knew I never wanted to be stuck begging for the things I wanted again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-shouldn-t-rob-us-of-freedom:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;Work Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Rob Us of Freedom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work to remove the limitations that exist when we can&amp;rsquo;t afford to do the things we want and need. &lt;strong&gt;Income gives us the ability to choose what&amp;rsquo;s best for ourselves, rather than being beholden to someone in a position of power over us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult/&#34;&gt;let work become the dominant force&lt;/a&gt; in our lives, we start to give away that same freedom we&amp;rsquo;ve worked to gain. Only this time it&amp;rsquo;s not a shortage of income that shackles us, but a shortage of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we&amp;rsquo;re trading our freedom for higher wages, or for career advancement, or for anything at all, really, we&amp;rsquo;re actively undermining one of the core principles of work: &lt;strong&gt;we work so we have the freedom to choose.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-work-to-have-purpose:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;We Work to Have Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently visited the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elephantnaturepark.org/&#34;&gt;Elephant Nature Park&lt;/a&gt;, run by Lek Chailert, a tiny woman from a rural part of Thailand with deep reverence for elephants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an adult, she works hard to rescue abused, disabled, and unwanted domesticated elephants and raise awareness about the rapidly disappearing elephant population and mistreatment of elephants as livestock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s found purpose in her work — or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s better to say she found work in her purpose. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that she finds her work incredibly important and fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even if our work isn&amp;rsquo;t our main purpose, it provides a means to pursue that purpose.&lt;/strong&gt; To quote the words of modern-day philosopher Jay-Z:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t help the poor if I&amp;rsquo;m one of them So I got rich and gave back, to me that&amp;rsquo;s the win/win&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jay-Z, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genius.com/9545/Jay-z-moment-of-clarity/Since-i-know-what-im-up-against-we-as-rappers-must-decide-whats-most-important-and-i-cant-help-the-poor-if-im-one-of-them-so-i-got-rich-and-gave-back-to-me-thats-the-win-win&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moment of Clarity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-shouldn-t-rob-us-of-purpose:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;Work Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Rob Us of Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By working, we create the opportunity for ourselves to apply time, money, and effort on the things that we think are most important in life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we let work spill over into our personal lives, the means to pursue our passions begins to diminish. We don&amp;rsquo;t have the energy to go after the things that we used to consider most important — we&amp;rsquo;re too exhausted from working, too preoccupied with meaningless metrics, or too worried about moving up the corporate ladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we let our work displace our purpose, we start to lose steam, and the results can be disastrous: midlife crises, depression, a sense of purposelessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-is-a-tool-not-a-burden:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0&#34;&gt;Work Is a Tool, Not a Burden&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work because we want to live better lives, and to do that we need to have a way to make an income. For most of us, that means a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is a tool that gives us access to meet our needs and fulfill our various wants. And when it&amp;rsquo;s treated like a tool, we&amp;rsquo;re able to control our efforts in a way that creates a better life for ourselves and our loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if we lose sight of what&amp;rsquo;s important to us, work can become the sole focus in our lives — it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a tool, it&amp;rsquo;s a burden that prevents us from doing what we want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to remember that we weren&amp;rsquo;t put on this planet to punch a clock and die on a pile of money; &lt;strong&gt;we were put here to live.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So repeat after me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t live to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We work to live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You never have to buy me anything, ever again!&amp;rdquo; was recently ranked #14 on the &lt;em&gt;Top 100 Phrases Children Don&amp;rsquo;t Fully Understand&lt;/em&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:begging&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;Suck it, allowance!
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:0fa0efe45766655fa7987bd9bede04c0:suckit&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overtime: How to Lose Your Employees and Kill Your Business</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/overtime-hurts-productivity</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/overtime-hurts-productivity</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The way many businesses approach pressing deadlines is terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also, ironically, one of the least effective ways to meet deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current mandatory hours are 9am to 10pm &amp;ndash; seven days a week &amp;ndash; with the occasional Saturday evening off for good behavior (at 6:30pm). – &lt;a href=&#34;http://ea-spouse.livejournal.com/274.html&#34;&gt;ea_spouse: &lt;em&gt;The Human Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post from ea_spouse caused a huge stir in 2004, citing the slow creep of mandatory overtime into company culture at EA Sports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EA&amp;rsquo;s reasoning, according to the post, was that engineering needed to go into &amp;ldquo;crunch mode&amp;rdquo; to boost output and meet looming deadlines. After all, an engineer working damn-near 90 hours a week should be at &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; twice as productive as the same engineer working 40 hours a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;productivity-is-not-linear:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Productivity Is Not Linear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thinking behind why managers believe twice the hours results in twice the output is short-sighted and toxic. Companies who regularly enter &amp;ldquo;crunch mode&amp;rdquo; forget to consider that their employees are humans — susceptible to fatigue, burnout, resentment, unhappiness — and not robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a programmer starts working, her output will follow a pattern along these lines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/daily-productivity-graph.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;productivity over the course of an average day&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If she&amp;rsquo;s asked to work extra hours, she &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; produce extra output. But since she&amp;rsquo;s already pretty beat after 8 hours, the extra output will be pretty low, and at a high cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-more-produces-less:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Working More Produces Less&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an alarmingly short period of time — just a month in some cases — &amp;rdquo;crunch mode&amp;rdquo; productivity will drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And not just a little drop. Output drops so much that it would have been more productive to work a standard 40 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me repeat that, because this is huge: &lt;strong&gt;an employee working 60 hours a week for two months will produce &lt;em&gt;less overall&lt;/em&gt; than the same employee working 40 hours a week for the same time period.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But how?&lt;/em&gt; How can doing 150% of the work result in less than 100% of the output?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-does-productivity-tank-during-crunch-mode:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Why Does Productivity Tank During Crunch Mode?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you work a standard 40-hour week, broken into five 8-hour shifts. And, since it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine our minds as a muscle, let&amp;rsquo;s pretend that your job is to unload heavy shit from a truck and move it into a warehouse all day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-40-hour-week-is-sustainable:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;A 40-Hour Week Is Sustainable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On an average day, you start out fresh, hit your stride an hour or two in, and start to feel fatigue set in after about six hours. At the end of eight hours, you&amp;rsquo;re beat, but not exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard work, but after you go home for the day&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d:done&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d:done&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; you have time to eat a nice dinner, relax with your friends and family, watch an episode of &lt;em&gt;Orange Is the New Black&lt;/em&gt;, and read a chapter of your book before sleeping a solid eight hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the weekends you take care of errands, spend time with friends and family, and sleep in a bit to make up for when you didn&amp;rsquo;t stop at just one chapter of your book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time your workweek starts again, you&amp;rsquo;re fully refreshed — mentally and physically — and ready to get back to work. You could happily keep up this pace for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;crunch-mode-starts-strong:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Crunch Mode Starts Strong&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, when mandatory overtime is assigned, you work a 60-hour week, broken into 6 10-hour shifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On day one, you start fresh, but by the end of 10 hours you&amp;rsquo;re feeling &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; worn out — two extra hours of carrying heavy objects takes a toll — but you &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; unload an extra truck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-it-takes-a-huge-toll:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;but It Takes a Huge Toll&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve also lost two hours of free time to the longer shift, so you have to skip meeting up with friends — and even with the cancellation, you only get seven hours of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On your only day off, you can&amp;rsquo;t sleep in because you have to rush through your errands early — you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to meet your friends for a barbecue at 4pm, and it&amp;rsquo;s your only chance to see them this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your next shift starts with you still feeling fatigued from last week. &lt;strong&gt;No matter how hard you try, you&amp;rsquo;re just too tired to keep up the same pace from last week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-it-gets-worse-over-time:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;and It Gets Worse Over Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the weeks drag on, your lack of sleep is combining with the stress of your increasingly-hurried personal life and you&amp;rsquo;re feeling ragged. The fatigue is showing in your output: &lt;strong&gt;each week is a little less productive than the one before it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/overtime-negative-productivity.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;overtime hurts productivity&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  After as little as 4 weeks of overtime, productivity can go negative.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite starting strong — during week one of crunch mode your output was noticeably higher than a standard week — over the following weeks your output dipped a little at a time, until you ended up doing &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; work over ten hours than you would over eight hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For 150% of the effort, you&amp;rsquo;re now getting less than 100% of the results.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-overtime-is-less-productive-why-do-so-many-businesses-rely-on-it:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;If Overtime Is Less Productive, Why Do So Many Businesses Rely on It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why — despite 100 years&amp;rsquo; worth of solid research, stating definitively that the 5-day, 8-hour workweek is the most sustainably productive arrangement — are so many businesses still implementing extended, mandatory overtime?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lack-of-effective-measurement:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Lack of Effective Measurement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most likely culprit is a lack of measured results. &lt;strong&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t measure output, then your only tool for gauging productivity is time and perceived effort:&lt;/strong&gt; the team has been putting in lots of extra time, and it sure &lt;em&gt;looks&lt;/em&gt; like they&amp;rsquo;re working hard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;misunderstanding-of-time-vs-output:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Misunderstanding of Time vs. Output&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high school, if you finished your assignments early, you weren&amp;rsquo;t let out of class to do whatever you wanted with the extra time. In fact, you were often given extra assignments — things like extra credit — which were, in effect, a &lt;em&gt;punishment&lt;/em&gt; for being efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some businesses operate with the same mindset and pay for time instead of output — you may have heard this called &amp;ldquo;butts in chairs&amp;rdquo; management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By valuing time over output, businesses unwittingly punish their most productive employees and reward the slackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;poor-project-management:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Poor Project Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a project isn&amp;rsquo;t properly planned, companies can find themselves trying to fit a six-week project into a four-week timeline. If managers aren&amp;rsquo;t actively working on controlling timelines, overtime may seem like the only viable option to meet unrealistic deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is usually made worse by the fact that the manager doesn&amp;rsquo;t pay for poor management nearly as much as the employees stuck working overtime will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-companies-fix-the-problem-of-overtime:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;How Can Companies Fix the Problem of Overtime?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s no easy answer to this question. Each company will have its own blend of dogmatic faith in overtime, cultural dependence on long hours, managerial incompetence/inexperience, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult/&#34;&gt;buy-in to the Overkill Cult&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few things that are worth auditing, however, that can at least help point out if there are some major, easily-fixable problems at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;output-should-be-measured:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Output Should Be Measured&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every company needs to be measuring output.&lt;/strong&gt; Where knowledge work is concerned, employee output is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; most important factor in determining whether or not the company is doing better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some companies, employee output is easy (&amp;ldquo;how many trucks did Terry unload?&amp;rdquo;) whereas others face more challenging metrics (&amp;ldquo;how much managing did Pat do this week?&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before a company can see the detrimental effects on productivity, it needs to be able to &lt;strong&gt;define what &amp;ldquo;productive&amp;rdquo; means with hard data&lt;/strong&gt; — otherwise they&amp;rsquo;re just guessing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reward-the-behavior-you-d-like-to-encourage:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Reward the Behavior You&amp;rsquo;d Like to Encourage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On any project, each team member should be given their fair share of goals to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, set &amp;lsquo;em loose. If someone finished her tasks today and they&amp;rsquo;re not due until next Friday, she can leave and not show up again until the review meeting — &lt;strong&gt;as long as what she&amp;rsquo;s turned in is quality, *it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how long she took to build it.&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t punish the stars on your team. Make sure they&amp;rsquo;re challenged, but be okay with results-oriented management — incentivizing your team (&amp;ldquo;finish ahead of schedule and you can do whatever you want until the meeting next week!&amp;rdquo;) instead of punishing them (&amp;ldquo;finish ahead of schedule and we&amp;rsquo;ll load you up with busywork!&amp;rdquo;) goes a long way toward encouraging the behavior you want to see in employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;plan-projects-effectively:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Plan Projects Effectively&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a new project is in its planning stages, &lt;strong&gt;make sure to include people in the decision-making process who will be able to provide reliable time estimates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A system of checks and balances should be put in place before a client ever receives a timeline to make sure the proposed deadlines are achievable without the need to go into crunch mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses shouldn&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the value of &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/effective-project-planning/&#34;&gt;properly planned projects&lt;/a&gt;; with a solid plan, projects get done faster and with fewer unpleasant surprises — like overtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-part-of-the-solution:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d&#34;&gt;Be Part of the Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s tempting to pretend that we&amp;rsquo;re the exception to this kind of data. Don&amp;rsquo;t fool yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working effectively — and in a way that makes us &lt;em&gt;happy&lt;/em&gt; with all aspects of our lives — is a marathon, not a sprint. We&amp;rsquo;ll feel like we have gas left in the tank. Like we&amp;rsquo;re not giving 100%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s exactly the point.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving a little in the tank is vital for sustained performance. When there&amp;rsquo;s a little gas left in the tank, we&amp;rsquo;re still excited to work. We&amp;rsquo;re not too exhausted to spend time with our family and friends. We still have time to pick up hobbies and relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And none of that should be undervalued — it&amp;rsquo;s the secret to &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; being successful and productive in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d:done&#34;&gt;And remember, you&amp;rsquo;re doing manual labor in this scenario. You can&amp;rsquo;t just move a couple boxes real quick from your phone during dinner, or make a call to rearrange that shelf you forgot to deal with today. When you&amp;rsquo;re done for the day, &lt;em&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re done for the day.&lt;/em&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9e087de5bf18f113c674bf17b69b2f2d:done&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Know If You&#39;ve Joined a Cult</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 01:07:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/overkill-cult</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You didn&amp;rsquo;t mean to end up here. You didn&amp;rsquo;t even see it coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with a chance to earn a living doing something you loved. Your dream job. Creating things instead of rotting in a cubicle. You weren&amp;rsquo;t just going to make a living — &lt;em&gt;you were going to leave your mark on the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, you loved the work; it was challenging and fast-paced. Everyone around you was crazy smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You brainstormed in your off time. Took projects home with you. Put in extra hours on weekends. It never felt like overworking because it never felt like work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You put in way more than 40 hours a week, but who was counting? This was &lt;em&gt;fun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But weeks passed into months and somehow you ended up here: Working 60 hours a week minimum, usually more. You greet your coworkers, bleary-eyed, half-joking about needing coffee to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work is still fun, but you don&amp;rsquo;t feel the same passion anymore. Whole days slip by sometimes and you have no idea what happened; you certainly don&amp;rsquo;t have much to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goals outside of work are on hold. You&amp;rsquo;d love to find out if the Belgians have anything to be cocky about waffle-wise, but you don&amp;rsquo;t have time for a big trip right now. You know you need to get into an exercise routine, but something always comes up and you skip the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Later,&amp;rdquo; you promise yourself, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to it soon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not exactly &lt;em&gt;un*happy, but something&amp;rsquo;s off. You can&amp;rsquo;t put your finger on it. You&amp;rsquo;ve just always felt that there would be &amp;hellip; *more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/a-clockwork-orange.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Cultural pressure to work long hours creates false obligation.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  You&#39;re being force-fed an &#34;ideal&#34; work ethic that&#39;s actually toxic for everyone involved.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1VqP36g&#34;&gt;A Clockwork Orange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-ve-been-absorbed:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve Been Absorbed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re no longer a free member of society. You&amp;rsquo;ve been lured into the &lt;strong&gt;Overkill Cult&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Overkill Cult is a cultural delusion that working 60+ hour weeks at the expense of everything else in our lives is not only a necessary part of success, but that doing so is somehow *honorable.&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The insidious thing about the Overkill Cult is that it masquerades as all the things we like most about ourselves: dedication, ambition, follow-through, responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It tells us to push harder, stay later, sleep when we&amp;rsquo;re dead. It tells us we&amp;rsquo;re never going to get ahead if we don&amp;rsquo;t show up first and go home last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleverly, wickedly, the Overkill Cult persuades us to hang ourselves with our own strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if we don&amp;rsquo;t break free, we&amp;rsquo;re all going to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-overkill-cult-will-kill-you-like-it-tried-to-kill-me:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;The Overkill Cult Will Kill You (Like It Tried to Kill Me)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance is the first thing to go once the Overkill Cult has us in its grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it started with my health. I skipped the gym — &lt;em&gt;too busy&lt;/em&gt;, I thought. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to cook — &lt;em&gt;too busy&lt;/em&gt; — so I ordered delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hobbies went next. Everything that wasn&amp;rsquo;t work fell away — &lt;em&gt;too busy, too busy&lt;/em&gt; — until I was on the computer constantly, working.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;strong&gt;In 2012, I was working 70–90 hours a week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I lost my social life. Friends knew I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t show up — &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t; too busy&lt;/em&gt; — so they stopped calling. Some days my only human interaction was ordering coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then — and this, sadly, is where I finally realized there was a problem — I lost my beard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-canary-in-the-coal-mine-or-how-i-killed-my-beard:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;The Canary in the Coal Mine, or How I Killed My Beard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2012, I landed the biggest project of my career at that point: a Black Friday sales site for a Fortune 100 company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thrilled and terrified. A project like this had the potential to move my company to the next level, and I decided to do whatever it took to make this project the best I&amp;rsquo;d ever built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The designers had great ideas, and I sat with them to make sure they were possible on our timeline. We came up with a slick, modern idea built on cutting-edge technology. The client loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then bureaucracy came into play. The legal department made changes. Brand adherence contradicted legal. Design went over schedule. &lt;em&gt;Way&lt;/em&gt; over schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time the design was approved, I had a third of the time we&amp;rsquo;d scheduled. And — since this was a Black Friday site — we couldn&amp;rsquo;t push back the release date. It either launched on time or I was a failure. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to be defeated, I powered through four straight days leading up to Black Friday, sleeping &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; six hours total. On Thanksgiving Day I skipped family get-togethers in favor of making the final push.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was exhausted. Delirious. But, goddammit, &lt;em&gt;I finished the project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client was thrilled. The site won a couple Addy Awards. I assume they made a metric fuckton in holiday sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few months, patches of my beard started to turn white. The whiskers became ultra-fine. Then they fell out altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/overwork-stress-unhealthy.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;effect of overwork on the body&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  May, 2013 — about six months after my Black Friday fiasco.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly afterward, I lost my ability to grow a beard entirely — I was left with the unsavory choice between a clean-shaven &amp;ldquo;giant fat baby&amp;rdquo; look and a creepy mustache.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had stressed myself out so badly that my body had forgotten how to grow a beard. And for what? So I could work 19-hour days and skip family holidays to meet crazy deadlines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was exhausted. My body was failing. I was overwhelmed and unhappy and isolated. &lt;em&gt;I had a mustache, for chrissakes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been guzzling the Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s Kool-Aid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something had to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-tell-if-you-re-in-a-cult:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;How to Tell If You&amp;rsquo;re in a Cult&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telltale signs we&amp;rsquo;ve fallen prey to the Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s influence are subtle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequently working more than 40 hours a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequently sleeping less than 6 hours a night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feeling guilty about any time away from work— even if that time is with family and friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t join overnight — this is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality&#34;&gt;death by a thousand cuts&lt;/a&gt; — and once we&amp;rsquo;ve joined, we&amp;rsquo;ll probably deny it.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;rsquo;ve joined. By the thousands, we&amp;rsquo;ve joined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lies-of-the-overkill-cult:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;The Lies of the Overkill Cult&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s siren song seems like a healthy sense of ambition. &amp;ldquo;We have to work hard to get ahead.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s something we&amp;rsquo;ve been told our entire lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re doing what we think is best for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Overkill Cult doesn&amp;rsquo;t plan for survivors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the symptoms of the Overkill Cult grow from good intentions, they&amp;rsquo;re short-sighted habits that ultimately do more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of the Overkill Cult&amp;rsquo;s telltale signs, and how each of them is a long-term detriment disguised as a healthy work ethic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-working-more-than-40-hours-a-week:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Frequently Working More than 40 Hours a Week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long hours often feel mandatory — it&amp;rsquo;s just part of the culture. We think, &amp;ldquo;My boss/coworkers/cat will judge me if I&amp;rsquo;m not working the same long hours as everyone else. I&amp;rsquo;ll never get ahead if I don&amp;rsquo;t go above and beyond.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just what it takes to make it, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrong.&lt;/strong&gt; Incredibly, terribly, &lt;em&gt;spectacularly&lt;/em&gt; wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research has proven over and over again that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to be productive for more than 40 hours a week.&lt;/strong&gt; At least not for sustained periods of time. Henry Ford introduced the 40-hour work week in 1914 because he saw — through research — that workers on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salon.com/2012/03/14/bring_back_the_40_hour_work_week/&#34;&gt;five eight-hour shifts kept up the highest sustained levels of productivity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite over 100 years of research supporting shorter work weeks, many companies still push for long hours, under the claims of a &amp;ldquo;sprint&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;crunch time&amp;rdquo; period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/overwork-hurts-productivity.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;overtime causes negative productivity after a short time&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This diagram is loosely based on one included in Sidney J. Chapman&#39;s *Hours of Labor*.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony comes in when we look at productivity over time. After just two months of 60-hour weeks, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enginesofmischief.com/makers/evan/pubs/crunch.html&#34;&gt;productivity goes &lt;em&gt;negative&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; compared to what a 40 hour week would have produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you catch that? &lt;strong&gt;By working 150% of the hours, you accomplish &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; in the long run.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-sleeping-less-than-6-hours-a-night:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Frequently Sleeping Less than 6 Hours a Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, sleeplessness has become a strange badge of honor. We swap &amp;ldquo;war stories&amp;rdquo; of sleeping two hours a night with an odd, martyred pride shining dimly in our bloodshot eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I never sleep because &lt;a href=&#34;http://genius.com/3012/Nas-ny-state-of-mind/I-never-sleep-cause-sleep-is-the-cousin-of-death&#34;&gt;sleep is the cousin of death&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; we murmur drowsily. So many projects, so little time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this belief that burning the midnight oil somehow gets us ahead is utterly, tragically wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1739867/pdf/v057p00649.pdf&#34;&gt;cognitive equivalent of a drunk driver&lt;/a&gt; after being awake about 18 hours. But the problem compounds: if you don&amp;rsquo;t get enough sleep, that level of impairment comes faster the next day. After a few days of too little sleep, you&amp;rsquo;re a drunken zombie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go to work drunk, so why the hell do we go to work on four hours&amp;rsquo; sleep, when we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; impaired than if we were hammered?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, sleeping less than six hours a night &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/8660373.stm&#34;&gt;may lead to an early death&lt;/a&gt;. The Overkill Cult is &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; killing you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;feeling-guilty-about-any-time-away-from-work-even-time-with-family-and-friends:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Feeling Guilty About Any Time Away from Work — Even Time with Family and Friends &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we&amp;rsquo;re in the clutches of the Overkill Cult, we feel a stab of guilt when we&amp;rsquo;re not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d love to go to this holiday party, but I really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t; this project won&amp;rsquo;t finish itself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fear that any time not spent working is wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony is — yet again — science tells us &lt;em&gt;exactly the opposite&lt;/em&gt; is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overworking leads to higher stress levels and burnout, which have been linked to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.3200/BMED.31.1.18-32#.VP2vuYGsWlI&#34;&gt;increased health risks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, time away from work is proven to &lt;a href=&#34;http://depts.washington.edu/hhwb/Thm_Mental.html&#34;&gt;relieve stress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2014-14435-001/&#34;&gt;boost creativity&lt;/a&gt;, among numerous other benefits.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, if we accept that the ideal is to sleep 8 hours a night and work 8 hours a day, that leaves us with 8 hours&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for non-work activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking time away from work gives us time to recharge. It puts distance between us and our projects, giving us time to remember why we like doing what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-our-escape:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Making Our Escape&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we may have been duped into joining the Overkill Cult, it&amp;rsquo;s not too late to escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been conned using our own best qualities to develop habits that — even though it &lt;em&gt;seems&lt;/em&gt; like they&amp;rsquo;d make us better — make us worse at our jobs, less satisfied with our work, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; less happy in our day-to-day lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leveraging the same strengths the Overkill Cult exploits, we can break free of its clutches and take back our happiness and passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my beard died, I felt the full weight of burnout. &lt;em&gt;I was burnt to a fucking crisp.&lt;/em&gt; I realized I could either leave my career altogether, or make some fundamental changes to my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, here are the promises I made to myself that helped me break away from the Overkill Cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-work-as-much-as-i-can-but-not-more:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;I Work as Much as I Can — But Not More&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before anything else, I had to accept that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s only possible to do 6–8 hours of quality work each day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to work longer hours will not make me more productive. In fact, working longer hours actually results in me getting less done as time drags on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose the latter, and implemented some radical (to me) &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/no-distractions-experiment/&#34;&gt;strategies for controlling my time&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;I cut from an average of 70–90 hours a week in 2013 to an average 38 hours per week over the last year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected to see less professional success in favor of better overall balance in my life — a sacrifice I was willing to make — instead I saw &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; productivity at work: my turn-around times went down&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and I was more consistently hitting my deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was floored at the time, but in retrospect I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-make-sleep-a-top-priority:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;I Make Sleep a Top Priority&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting enough sleep is beneficial on every level. Yet it&amp;rsquo;s always the first thing I would sacrifice when life got busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too little sleep wreaks havoc on my ability to think clearly, and that hurts me at work in a big, bad way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I cut my hours down, I started sleeping without an alarm.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Since I&amp;rsquo;m not working crazy hours, I close my computer by six or seven in the evening, and by eleven I&amp;rsquo;m usually in bed, where I read for a bit before falling asleep. I wake up naturally between seven and eight-thirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has changed my life. No bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waking up to an alarm before I&amp;rsquo;m fully rested starts the day in a groggy, stressful way. Waking up naturally after getting as much sleep as my body needs leaves me much happier to be awake, and far more ready to start my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-dedicate-a-reasonable-amount-of-time-to-not-working:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;I Dedicate a Reasonable Amount of Time to NOT Working&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was — and still is — the biggest challenge I faced in breaking away from the Overkill Cult. I love what I do, and I want to get my projects finished. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to rationalize working more hours and skipping activities that keep me from working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I know that taking breaks makes me more productive: time away from work lets my passion and excitement for the work renew itself; taking my mind off of a project allows my subconscious to roll around abstract ideas that result in better solutions; breaks from the job lower my stress levels and boost my creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I make sure to do it, even if my gut (incorrectly) tells me it&amp;rsquo;s a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take walks. I leave my phone in my pocket when I&amp;rsquo;m out with friends or eating my meals. I spend a fair amount of time on my hobbies, like writing and hunting for the world&amp;rsquo;s best cheeseburger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happier today than I can ever remember being in my life. I feel excited to work on my projects, to pursue my hobbies, and to spend time with people I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to be alive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leaving-the-overkill-cult-saved-my-life:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Leaving the Overkill Cult Saved My Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When my beard died in 2013, I feared it was only the first sign of an impending decline in my health that would ultimately kill me.&lt;/strong&gt; It was a glimpse into my future, and I was terrified that if I didn&amp;rsquo;t change, I was in for a life of isolation, ulcers, alopecia, and an eventual heart attack or stress-induced brain tumor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By changing my lifestyle, I was able to turn things around. After just a year of balancing my work with the rest of my life, my beard grew back. I lost 30 pounds because I was actually going outside and making it to the gym. I felt more awake, and I &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jlengstorf/stop-glossing-over-the-good-stuff-b89e25f7c714&#34;&gt;became more positive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I left the Overkill Cult, &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; in my life improved. Not one single thing got worse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-costa-rica.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf in front of a volcano in Costa Rica after fixing his work-life balance&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Doing a superhero pose in front of a volcano in Costa Rica. (Notice my beard.)

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://marisamorby.com&#34;&gt;Marisa Morby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-ready-to-make-your-escape:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0&#34;&gt;Are You Ready to Make Your Escape?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been sucked into the Overkill Cult, know that you&amp;rsquo;re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be facing cultural pressure to keep this crazy pace. You may be struggling with your identity as &amp;ldquo;a hard worker&amp;rdquo; and feeling that scaling back somehow makes you lazy or useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I promise you — despite the doubts the Overkill Cult will force into your mind — there&amp;rsquo;s a better way. Better for your career. Better for your health. Better for your relationships. Better for your happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ended up in the Overkill Cult because you&amp;rsquo;re smart, ambitious, and dedicated. But you were misled by your good qualities and turned them into bad habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a better way, and you&amp;rsquo;re smart enough to pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dump your Kool-Aid in the sink. Take back your freedom. Find the happiness and success you were looking for when you started this career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Close your computer. Go outside. And call your friends; they miss you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;Hardly any of these hours were productive. Often I&amp;rsquo;d refresh my email, or stare at a code editor in a daze before realizing I&amp;rsquo;d been sitting there with my mouth open for half an hour.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:worklike&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll look like Magnum,&amp;rdquo; I tried to tell myself. But I knew — even then, I knew — it was all a horrible, creepy lie.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:mustache&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re currently rationalizing how you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in the Overkill Cult even though you meet all the criteria, you&amp;rsquo;re definitely a member.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:denial&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;These studies focus on walking a few minutes a day. Not even an actual hobby or dedicated non-work activity. The negative effects of &amp;ldquo;all work and no play&amp;rdquo; are staggering, if you think about it.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:walking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;Or, if you want to exclude meals and such, &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; four hours. That&amp;rsquo;s enough time to go to the gym &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; pick up a hobby. Or even, you know, hang out with other humans or something.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:nonworktime&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;I also made other changes that helped with turn-around times, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/effective-project-planning/&#34;&gt;planning more effectively&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:turnaround&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;Waking up without an alarm is, by far, my favorite thing about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;digital nomad lifestyle&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful to lead.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9ede6b4ba1d5c9385adce138a51754f0:noalarm&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Break</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/better-productivity-work-less</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 15:28:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/better-productivity-work-less</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday I took a break. A &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met a few of my friends for brunch at 10:45am in Toronto. When the meal ended, we weren&amp;rsquo;t ready to call it, so we relocated to coffee shop and kept our conversation rolling. Then we were hungry again, so we grabbed lunch, then beers at a brewery. After the brewery, dinner. And an ice cream sandwich to wrap up the evening at 10:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twelve hours spent with friends. No electronics. No work. Just conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may sound like a waste of a day — especially if you consider that it was a Thursday — but would you believe me if I told you that &lt;strong&gt;I was &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; productive than usual&lt;/strong&gt; this week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-i-look-away-this-all-falls-apart:09e2db200e2124d8bbfaa5aa3e3d3c0b&#34;&gt;If I Look Away, This All Falls Apart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disconnecting is hard.&lt;/strong&gt; When I&amp;rsquo;m not staying on top of email and checking in with my team at work, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m cheating. Like I&amp;rsquo;m somehow letting myself and my coworkers down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If I look away, this all falls apart,&amp;rdquo; I tell myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes the idea of leaving my phone at home terrifying. My chest tightens the way it would if I forgot my wallet or left the stove on — &lt;em&gt;something terrible is about to happen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My fear of the chaos that could happen if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t constantly present led me to work an average of 10 hours every day in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not Monday through Friday. &lt;em&gt;Every. Damn. Day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-myself-on-fire:09e2db200e2124d8bbfaa5aa3e3d3c0b&#34;&gt;Setting Myself on Fire&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My health and happiness suffered — mostly due to the high stress levels of never turning off — and I realized something needed to change. I suspected my work habits were the source, so I decided to experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;m not one for dipping a toe in, &lt;strong&gt;I decided to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire/&#34;&gt;set myself on fire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; I went to Alaska for eight days &lt;em&gt;without a phone or a computer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No safety net. No escape hatch. I was there until my return flight, with no option to change my mind. Like it or not, I was disconnected and I was going to see the experiment through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-s-what-i-thought-would-happen-when-i-disconnected:09e2db200e2124d8bbfaa5aa3e3d3c0b&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I thought would happen when I disconnected:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of my clients would fire me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of my projects would descend into chaos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d come home to the wreckage of my career&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After sweeping up the shattered bits of my former life, I would move into my parents&amp;rsquo; basement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would die poor, alone, and ashamed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-s-what-actually-happened-when-i-disconnected:09e2db200e2124d8bbfaa5aa3e3d3c0b&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; happened when I disconnected:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None of that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hiked, and relaxed, and had some time to reflect on how things were being done (rather than just focusing on what needed to be done next). &lt;strong&gt;My unconscious mind spun up and rolled ideas around, and I found the solutions to several lingering problems on both work and personal projects.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All of my fears were ridiculous and unfounded.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;doing-less-is-more-productive:09e2db200e2124d8bbfaa5aa3e3d3c0b&#34;&gt;Doing Less Is More Productive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turning off isn&amp;rsquo;t slacking off.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/08/10/opinion/sunday/hit-the-reset-button-in-your-brain.html&#34;&gt;giving the other parts of my brain time to work&lt;/a&gt;. This is actually &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; for productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, when I work non-stop, I find myself moving slowly and wasting a lot of time idly checking email. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not getting more done in more hours; I&amp;rsquo;m just &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s likely I&amp;rsquo;m actually accomplishing less.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should take three hours takes six because I don&amp;rsquo;t feel any urgency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With breaks, your work days become shorter. It becomes easier to focus. &amp;ldquo;I know I have to shut down by 3pm, so I&amp;rsquo;d better crank on this for the next four hours to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s finished before then.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve adopted actual breaks into my days, I have actually been getting more done in fewer total hours worked.&lt;/strong&gt; It seems counterintuitive, but there&amp;rsquo;s actually a mountain of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcompany.com/3015567/the-25-hour-work-week-and-other-radical-ideas-for-better-employee-productivity&#34;&gt;research supporting this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-dare-for-you-take-a-personal-day:09e2db200e2124d8bbfaa5aa3e3d3c0b&#34;&gt;A Dare for You: Take a Personal Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re feeling overwhelmed at work, or if you feel like your productivity is starting to flag, try an experiment: &lt;em&gt;take a day off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plan a full day without your computer. Leave your phone at home. Shut off. Work less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is a full day too scary? Start small: &lt;strong&gt;take just two hours to leave your phone at home and spend time alone or with a friend without any electronic distractions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be surprised at what you&amp;rsquo;re able to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>