<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:22:56 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>No one is coming to save you. Are you going to save yourself?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/no-one-is-coming-to-save-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:22:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/no-one-is-coming-to-save-you/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At fourteen, I felt a lot of rage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, my anger wasn&amp;rsquo;t much more than the vinegar-and-baking-soda aftermath of my first waves of conscious individualism breaking against jagged, hormonal shores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-high-school-bad-attitude.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf in high school with a shitty attitude.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This is the face of struggle.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the time, my rage felt like my only defense against the countless injustices I was forced to endure&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the cruelty of a world out to keep me from feeling any real joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was angry because it felt like things were out of my control. I was debris swept away in a flood — a helpless, hapless bystander caught in a cosmic battle that had nothing at all to do with me: the victim of cruel happenstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world was happening &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; me, and I felt helpless.&lt;/strong&gt; So &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; I was pissed; helplessness has got to be in the Top 5 for Reasons People Get Angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovering-logical-thought:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Discovering Logical Thought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere around fifteen or sixteen, my great-aunt sent me a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1T2FuaG&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which started me down a philosophical rabbit-hole.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1eSrpPt&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1MMo4jH&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I read generation-defining pop-philosophy in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1IkeUXC&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fight Club&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and learned about the true nature of not giving a fuck in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1KQ4Dq0&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Factotum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and realized I&amp;rsquo;d never even come close to hitting bottom from &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1IGLrV4&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus&amp;rsquo; Son&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reading led to questions, which led to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2FTAT.com&#34;&gt;deep conversations with a friend&lt;/a&gt;, which led to critical&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; insights, and — finally — to actual changes in my behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, after a few minutes&amp;rsquo; logical thought, I realized two things that drastically changed my life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-no-one-is-out-to-get-me:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;1. No one is out to get me.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no dark force or diabolical villain working to make my life harder. It was hard to swallow, but I realized that &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just not that important.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, hardly anyone thinks about me &lt;em&gt;at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to imagine that I have critical importance and will therefore face critical opposition, but that&amp;rsquo;s an extraordinarily myopic view of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that — while I am the most important person in &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; world — I barely register in the broader scope of &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably 95% of the human beings I pass on the street receive zero attention. Of the 5% I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; notice, I only notice a single feature (&amp;ldquo;Cool shoes!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nice ass!&amp;rdquo;) and they&amp;rsquo;re forgotten the instant they leave my line of sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://38.media.tumblr.com/c958931381d9efa62f158d885f3ca811/tumblr_mirhy5eQPY1s6tut4o1_r1_500.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;House of Cards nobody cares&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1856010/&#34;&gt;House of Cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who am I to think I&amp;rsquo;m somehow deserving of everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention when I barely give them any thought at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To roughly 7,348,999,994 of the 7,349,000,000 people on the planet, I either don&amp;rsquo;t exist or don&amp;rsquo;t matter enough to occupy short-term memory.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a target. I&amp;rsquo;m not being singled out for cruelty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a victim.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-no-one-is-coming-to-save-me:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;2. No one is coming to save me.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my story has no villains, it&amp;rsquo;s safe to assume there aren&amp;rsquo;t any heroes, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As fate would have it, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fragile, extraterrestrial secret weapon&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/River_Tam&#34;&gt;severely damaged government experiment on the run&lt;/a&gt; — &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just a person.&lt;/strong&gt; My interests are all fairly commonplace, my talents are all borderline commodities, and my opinions are the mutant, amalgamated offspring of the opinions of authors and mentors I&amp;rsquo;ve paid attention to while I&amp;rsquo;ve been alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only unique thing about me is the &lt;em&gt;precise&lt;/em&gt; arrangement of my interests, talents, actions, and opinions. Otherwise, everything I am, do, and believe is more or less standard-issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s no need to save me; I&amp;rsquo;m not vital to the future of our planet. &lt;strong&gt;No one is going to &amp;ldquo;rescue me&amp;rdquo; from my life.&lt;/strong&gt; I won&amp;rsquo;t be &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lana_Turner&#34;&gt;discovered in a drug store&lt;/a&gt; and propelled to stardom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m on my own.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-empty-director-s-chair:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;The Empty Director&amp;rsquo;s Chair&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its face, this may sound bleak: I&amp;rsquo;m all alone and no one cares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is actually &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; news. It was probably the best news I&amp;rsquo;d ever received as a teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent most of my youth terrified of looking foolish. And when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t worried about looking foolish, I was convinced that I would get in trouble if I made the wrong decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I realized no one gave a shit about me, life became immeasurably easier.&lt;/strong&gt; I could strip down to one of those novelty thongs where my penis becomes an elephant trunk and sprint through a town hall meeting belting out the latest Taylor Swift single at the top of my lungs and &lt;em&gt;no one would care.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/elephant-g-string.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Elephant G-string&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Baby, I&#39;m just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake...

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teddygirl.com/elephant-gstring.html&#34;&gt;TGL, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, people would laugh, and someone would definitely put it on YouTube, but no one would &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; care. I&amp;rsquo;d be a momentary amusement, and then I&amp;rsquo;d fade right back into the anonymous social landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made it far easier to do things that were less ridiculous, like taking a chance on making it as a touring musician, or quitting my full-time job to give freelancing a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My whole life, I&amp;rsquo;d believed that &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/project-grownup/the-real-life-truman-show-1cd6b2aa9c34&#34;&gt;people were watching me&lt;/a&gt;, and that some unseen hand was shoving me along a path I had no control over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was wrong: &lt;strong&gt;there was no one making decisions about my life.&lt;/strong&gt; Except me, I guess — assuming I worked up the guts to make any decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my life was a movie, up until this point there&amp;rsquo;d been no director. I&amp;rsquo;d been carried along by the unstoppable current of time, but uncaptained, rudderless, drifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless I chose to act heroically, my movie had no hero. No villains unless I acted villainously. Unless I climbed in and took charge, the director&amp;rsquo;s chair was — and would remain — empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/whos-writing-your-story.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Who&amp;#39;s writing your story?&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-s-writing-your-story:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Who&amp;rsquo;s Writing Your Story?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I assumed responsibility for my own life, everything changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world didn&amp;rsquo;t happen &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; me anymore. &lt;em&gt;I happened to the world&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started steering myself away from the things that frustrated and depressed me, and toward things that excited and motivated me. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long road, and I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it today. I expect I&amp;rsquo;ll probably still be working on it when I die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started seeing immediate improvement: my life was now my choice, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a victim of anything. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t pleasant to admit that a relationship ended because I acted like a dick, or that a project failed because I let everyone down and slacked, but &lt;strong&gt;making my own mistakes was &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; better than feeling helpless against the whims of a malevolent universe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-in-my-own-way:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Getting in My Own Way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comfortably at the helm of my personal narrative, I immediately started closing doors and adding restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of man was I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the type of man who didn&amp;rsquo;t buy into bullshit corporate puppetry and advertising-driven entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the type of man who questioned all authority and made my own path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the type of man who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be lumped in with a group or clique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/south-park-non-conformists.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;South Park non-conformists&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://southpark.cc.com/clips/154322/non-conformist-coffee&#34;&gt;South Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, free thinker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, beacon of logical reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, renegade individualist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, prisoner of silly, self-imposed roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-are-you:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Who Are You?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I graduated high school, my parents took my whole family to Florida. It was half-intended as a graduation gift, and half-intended as a long-overdue family vacation. We went to Universal Studios and Disney World. Daytona Beach. Some enormous waterpark I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the name of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-high-school.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf high school photo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  &#34;As you&#39;ve probably already guessed by my hairstyle, I hate everything. Especially you.&#34;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And I — bound by my staunch opposition to corporate profiteering, herd mentality, and enjoying anything popular — made sure I was miserable the whole time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hot and muggy in the way Florida is usually hot and muggy, but I wore long sleeves and black pants the whole time. While my brother and sister carried their tubes to the top of a big-ass whirlpool-looking deathtrap, I sulked in the shade.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire premise of my family&amp;rsquo;s vacation violated my identity. It was an affront to the core of my being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, of course, that my parents&amp;rsquo; choice for a family vacation spot had exactly &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with my identity, and &lt;strong&gt;I was really just letting some dude in a Mickey Mouse costume ruin family time simply by standing nearby.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of power to give a stranger wearing a giant rubber head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-cages-we-build-for-ourselves:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;The Cages We Build for Ourselves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brick by brick, I&amp;rsquo;d built a wall between what was and was not acceptable for Someone Like Me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me listens to death metal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me would &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; shop at Walmart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me loves &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_the_Homicidal_Maniac&#34;&gt;Jhonen Vasquez&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me doesn&amp;rsquo;t love Jhonen Vasquez anymore because Hot Topic started carrying his comics.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was proud of the wall at first, because it created a clear separation between &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo; (me) and &amp;ldquo;them&amp;rdquo; (the sheeple).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building the wall was my tiny way of asserting a tiny bit of dominance over the tiny shadow I&amp;rsquo;d cast on the Earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/nate-green-jason-lengstorf_high-school-attitude.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Nate Green and Jason Lengstorf high school bad attitude&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt; and me showing the world just how cool we were.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: a wall is a wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, I was trapped by the imaginary Malevolent Universe that ensured my life happened &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now, I was trapped by the imaginary Someone Like Me who ensured only a tiny subset of all available choices were ever seriously considered.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-identity-snowball:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;The Identity Snowball&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was born, I was a tiny spark of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no memories. I knew nothing. All I cared about was whether I was hungry or sleepy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When something happened, I had no frame of reference. I could only observe, consider it as an isolated event, and make a decision about what that meant to me in that moment.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-childhood.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf childhood photo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  No agenda, no prejudices — just a sweet bear sweater.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no subtext or personal politics. &lt;strong&gt;Things were what they appeared to be. How could a thing be more than it is?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew, I learned language and fear and prejudice and opinion from my environment. Cat peed on me when I was four? Now I hate cats. Dog bit me? I&amp;rsquo;m scared of Dalmatians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends teased me about my Looney Tunes t-shirts, so that stuff was for babies. My mom knew the words to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2H5uWRjFsGc&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tubthumping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so it was clearly too mainstream for me to listen to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slow accumulation of experiential biases continued until &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d become so mired in my identity that I could no longer see an event as A Thing That Happened&lt;/strong&gt;; now it was inextricably linked to things I&amp;rsquo;d seen or heard before, opinions I&amp;rsquo;d adopted or developed, and my own historical stance on events of this type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My tiny spark of consciousness had grown into a hulking snowball of opinions and filters and fears and prejudices, and it was growing larger every day. There was no such thing as an isolated incident anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t asking myself what I should do in response to an event; I was asking myself what Someone Like Me would do in response to that event.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet again, I was out of the director&amp;rsquo;s chair and letting something else make my decisions for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-melt-the-snowball:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;How to Melt the Snowball&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 28, I was invited to try wake surfing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d always hated water: I nearly drowned on multiple occasions&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; when I was really young; I had a chip on my shoulder about being too cool for sports (especially water sports); but mostly I was chubby, pasty, and generally uncomfortable in anything but long sleeves and pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I made the decision to hate water before I can remember.&lt;/strong&gt; As a result, I&amp;rsquo;d spent nearly twenty years flatly refusing any activity involving water because — through the filter of my projected identity: Someone Like Me — water activities were stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my knee-jerk reaction was to refuse. Someone Like Me wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do it, so of course I won&amp;rsquo;t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then — at the insistence of my then-girlfriend — I started examining that refusal. Did I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; dislike water sports, or was it just something I&amp;rsquo;d told myself years ago and never since questioned? &lt;strong&gt;Was I cutting myself off from activities I might really enjoy because of something my idiot teenaged self had decided due to body issues and anti-conformity complexes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to test it: I&amp;rsquo;d go wake surfing, and if I hated it, my dislike for water sports was justified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I liked it, &lt;strong&gt;I needed to reevaluate my opinions about the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;taking-back-control-from-my-past-selves:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Taking Back Control from My Past Selves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wake surfing was a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;fb-video aligncenter&#34;
  data-href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/jlengstorf/videos/vb.107496345986942/519589568110949/&#34;
  data-width=&#34;730&#34;
  data-allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;
  data-autoplay=&#34;false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve since learned how to surf, snorkel, and kayak.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Each time, I was participating in water-based activities — the ones I&amp;rsquo;d always told myself I hated — and each time, I had a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many other decisions was I letting my pre-teen self make? My teenage self? My twenty-two-year-old post-rockstar-aspirational self?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been cheating myself out of dozens — if not &lt;em&gt;hundreds&lt;/em&gt; — of experiences because I&amp;rsquo;d let my unexamined emotional detritus hobble me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was I really in control of my life if a fifteen-year-old grudge against water was holding me back from things I truly enjoyed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-what-i-am:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;I Am What I Am&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the wake surfing incident, I&amp;rsquo;ve started running all my decisions through a do-I-really-feel-that-way-or-am-I-listening-to-my-idiot-teenaged-self-again filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/popeye-i-yam-what-i-yam.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Popeye I Yam What I Yam&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://popeye.com/&#34;&gt;Popeye the Sailor Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt I catch all of them. Good ideas still snag on my emotional barnacles more often than I&amp;rsquo;d prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m trying to keep my identity lean and adaptable. I&amp;rsquo;ve got new &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Popeye&#34;&gt;Popeye-esque mantra&lt;/a&gt;, even:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am who I am — not who I was — and I&amp;rsquo;m working to become who I want to be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, at least, I feel happier than I&amp;rsquo;ve ever felt — and significantly more in-control of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/marisa-morby-nate-green-jason-lengstorf-pot-luck-of-meaning.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Marisa Morby, Nate Green, Jason Lengstorf at a Precision Nutrition charity pot luck.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://marisamorby.com/&#34;&gt;Marisa&lt;/a&gt;, Nate, and me at a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.precisionnutrition.com/&#34;&gt;Precision Nutrition&lt;/a&gt; charity potluck. Big smiles brought to you by a low emotional bullshit quotient.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m free to become the hero of my story.&lt;/strong&gt; To take control of my part in its outcome. To try anything that might make me a better person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, I&amp;rsquo;m free to let my past experiences make me lighter — they&amp;rsquo;re there to show me what I &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; need to carry, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An abridged list of injustices endured by fourteen-year-old Jason Lengstorf:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mother who forced the removal of a tongue ring, despite the fact that it cost a week&amp;rsquo;s pay and several hours of subterfuge in order to get someone to do the piercing in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Girls who were mysteriously repelled by the black hair, zipper-and-safety-pin-laden clothing, death metal t-shirts, and generally shitty attitude of a &lt;em&gt;really nice guy&lt;/em&gt; (which they&amp;rsquo;d know, if they would stop being jerks and overlook all that so they could get to know him).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet commenters who couldn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp that the Insane Clown Posse is just &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt;, despite mountains of empirical evidence. Also, why were those idiot juggalos on the Eminem fan forum, anyways? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OvmvxAcT_Yc&#34;&gt;Fucking magnets&lt;/a&gt;, right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve read Ayn Rand. Yes, the books made me think and influenced me in certain ways. No, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to hang out, Glenn Beck.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;There were also non-critical insights: I realized that I was smarter than everyone else on the planet; I solved all the world&amp;rsquo;s problems (short version: &amp;ldquo;Everyone should just think and act &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; like me.&amp;ldquo;); I discovered rhetoric&amp;rsquo;s more sinister uses and brutally terrorized my less-eloquent teachers.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;The six people I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure think about me regularly: me, Marisa, Nate, my parents, and Nadia (whose job involves making sure I&amp;rsquo;m still alive and accomplishing things).
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leeloo Dallas &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119116/quotes?item=qt0464059&#34;&gt;mul-ti-pass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;No matter how I try to say this, it feels cheesy. I feel like some doofy motivational speaker trying to pump up an audience whenever I share this idea. But shifting that power dynamic changed everything in my life, so fuck it: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/kevinkruse/2012/11/28/zig-ziglar-10-quotes-that-can-change-your-life/&#34;&gt;call me Zig&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;I was probably doing something &lt;em&gt;totally unique&lt;/em&gt;, like writing emo lyrics or reading Chuck Palahniuk.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;When I got a JtHM tattoo at seventeen, I never imagined the sort of people who would — in their thirties — recognize and start a conversation with me because of said tattoo. I imagine it feels the same for people who got Disturbed tattoos.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Or maybe not. Maybe they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;stoked&lt;/em&gt; about the folks still down with the sickness twenty years later.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;My go-to responses were &amp;ldquo;crying&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;not crying&amp;rdquo;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;Turns out it&amp;rsquo;s bad news to be both A) recklessly inclined to jump into large bodies of water and B) the opposite of buoyant.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;I say &amp;ldquo;learned&amp;rdquo; loosely. I stood up on a surfboard a couple times, figured out that a snorkel is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a giant straw for drinking ocean water quickly, and dumped a kayak in the shallows while an older couple looked on and laughed.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do More with Less: Drop Dead Physical &amp; Psychological Weight</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/do-more-with-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 04:34:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/do-more-with-less/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re serious? I can just&amp;hellip;take whatever I want?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pile of stuff in the corner of my apartment was huge. A drill I&amp;rsquo;d only used once sat on top of a box full of cables I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize I still had. An empty TV stand was littered with basically-new kitchen utensils and three different wifi routers. A full set of throw pillows I found in a closet sat on top of a toolbox full of art supplies I hadn&amp;rsquo;t opened since I dropped out of college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My neighbor had responded to a message I sent out to the building announcing a giveaway. I&amp;rsquo;ve never met this woman before. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming we live in the same building, but I can&amp;rsquo;t recall having seen her before — but then again, I&amp;rsquo;m not usually one to notice people passing by unless they&amp;rsquo;re holding food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She picks out some kitchen utensils, a whiteboard, and a package of AA batteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re sure? Anything?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Absolutely,&amp;rdquo; I reassure her. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re doing me a favor by taking this. Honest.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She leaves with her armload of booty, looking over her shoulder at me as if I&amp;rsquo;m going to change my mind and tackle her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, Marisa arrives with her own pile of stuff. A few hours later our friends arrive at the going-away-slash-holiday party we&amp;rsquo;ve arranged so we can see everyone before we leave the country the following Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friends all have the same bewildered look my neighbor wore when we start shoving our possessions into their arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, Nicole from the cleaning service arrives to do the move-out clean. I tell her to take anything she wants, and I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to see that she wants pretty much everything. She borrows the hand truck from the building to take a few loads out to her car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take everything that&amp;rsquo;s left and load it into Marisa&amp;rsquo;s trunk. At the donation drop, a man opens the door for Marisa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What a lovely day it is! What a lovely day to be alive! And how are you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marisa loves this guy. He&amp;rsquo;s a bit disheveled and wild-looking, like James Brown&amp;rsquo;s mugshot, and has the best attitude I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wow! Look at all this great stuff! Miss, you have excellent taste in movies — see this one right here? I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; this one right here!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He runs a cheerful commentary the whole time he helps us unload the trunk. (&amp;ldquo;This is a fantastic coat! I may have to buy this coat! You think it&amp;rsquo;ll fit me?&amp;rdquo;) His attitude is contagious. (&amp;ldquo;My oh my this blanket is &lt;em&gt;lovely!&lt;/em&gt; If I had this blanket and a mugful of hot cocoa I&amp;rsquo;d be the happiest man on Earth.&amp;ldquo;) As we pull out of the lot, waving, Marisa and I are wearing wide grins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop is a used car dealer, who buys Marisa&amp;rsquo;s car. He surprises her by offering more than she had expected for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, lying on the floor of my now-empty apartment, staring at the entirety of my worldly possessions in two small bags against the wall, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the way I&amp;rsquo;d expected to feel. I thought giving away all my things — possessions I&amp;rsquo;d carefully curated over the last few years — would feel like losing a limb. There was the art I&amp;rsquo;d collected from local cafés that showed my aesthetic preferences. The couch I&amp;rsquo;d had custom-built that was wide enough for four people to sit on and deep enough for two people to spoon. The bar full of all my favorite spirits and the proper glasses to serve drinks that announced to the world I was a whiskey kind of guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d feel empty.&lt;/strong&gt; I thought the absence of my things — this stuff that turned my insides out — would leave me hollowed out, back at Square One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But I felt exactly the opposite.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked down on the sum total of everything I owned with an incredible feeling of lightness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tiny pile of clothes and electronics was all I had to worry about. The internal pressure I felt to make sure my actions matched up with the material presentation I&amp;rsquo;d constructed — &amp;ldquo;is my attitude right now the attitude of a man who owns Herman Miller furniture?&amp;rdquo; — dissolved. My external pressure was gone; I only needed to make sure my actions matched up with the way I believed a man like me should act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/do-more-with-less.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;do more with less — emotional and material minimalism&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;minimalism-without-the-bullshit:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Minimalism, Without the Bullshit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try pretty hard to avoid labeling myself — I don&amp;rsquo;t want the actions of a group I don&amp;rsquo;t control to affect how people perceive me — so I don&amp;rsquo;t call myself a minimalist. But the core idea of the minimalist lifestyle does align with how I see the world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism is a lifestyle that helps people question what things add value to their lives. By clearing the clutter from life’s path, we can all make room for the most important aspects of life: health, relationships, passion, growth, and contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theminimalists.com/pitch/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Minimalists&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dropping-dead-weight:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Dropping Dead Weight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, &lt;strong&gt;every single thing we add to our lives, both physical and psychological, adds a tiny bit of extra weight that we have to carry around.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My operating view of the world is that my &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; self — the part that makes me a free-thinking, individual entity — is very small and virtually weightless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I experience the world, the things I do form memories, associations, and predictive models that help me navigate the world. These are the building blocks of my identity. I once threw up after eating cooked spinach from a can, and now I don&amp;rsquo;t like cooked spinach at all. I learned from my dad to always try to understand why things work, so I&amp;rsquo;m a shitty employee because I second-guess my bosses at every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These experiences make me into the person I am today, informing my personality and worldview, but each one adds a little weight to my identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To express my identity, I build a model of the kind of person I want to be seen as. I want to be seen as successful, so I only want to buy nice things. I want to be seen as discerning and stylish, so I only buy clothes and furniture with designs that have stood the test of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These possessions echo my experiences and reinforce them. If I thought I was a whiskey guy before I put a bunch of effort into finding a bottle of Black Maple Hill, I was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; a whiskey guy once I had that bottle in my bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The added weight of the material possessions and emotional biases on my decisions made it hard to be objective. &lt;strong&gt;Instead of asking, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s best in this situation?&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d find myself asking, &amp;ldquo;What would a guy like me do here?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cutting-the-crap:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Cutting the Crap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I pushed all of the possessions out of my life that weren&amp;rsquo;t essential for my daily life, it became easier for me to make objective decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, my plans to travel the world came with caveats: I&amp;rsquo;ll have to find a place to keep my Dordoni Worktop Table — I love that table — and my art collection will need a storage unit with climate control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could do what I wanted, but only after I&amp;rsquo;d made sure to take care of all my crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once those things were gone, I could weigh my options objectively and make quick, agile decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I want to go to Madrid? Well&amp;hellip;sure. Let&amp;rsquo;s do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No conditions or caveats — I can just pick up my two small bags and go with no guilt, no worries, and no hassles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;people-like-me:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;People Like Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I haven&amp;rsquo;t reduced my essential self back down to its weightless state. I&amp;rsquo;ve only changed my view of what &amp;ldquo;people like me&amp;rdquo; do; instead of thinking of myself as the kind of person who owns nice things and drinks good whiskey, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a new description for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of person who values experience over things and doesn&amp;rsquo;t worry about material possessions because they add stress instead of happiness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not enlightened, superior, or even better off; I&amp;rsquo;ve simply traded one guiding philosophy for another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this transition has allowed me to pursue the things I find meaningful. My old guiding philosophy was holding me back, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see it — the threat to my view of &amp;ldquo;people like me&amp;rdquo; was blocking me from seeing that I could be happier by trying a different outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-people-like-you-holding-you-back:af831ffeac1200a80bc2c91c082b2d8f&#34;&gt;Are People Like You Holding You Back?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separating ourselves from our experiences is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; — there&amp;rsquo;s no denying it. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason people dedicate their whole lives to meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we don&amp;rsquo;t need to reach enlightenment to try and spot our own biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the easiest ways to catch ourselves being owned by our emotional and physical crap is to ask what we&amp;rsquo;d advise our friends to do if they were facing the same decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a friend came to you and asked, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve got this opportunity to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;travel the world&lt;/a&gt; while still making a living, but I&amp;rsquo;d have to sell all of my stuff in order to do it — what should I do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve known your friend has wanted to travel as long as you&amp;rsquo;ve been friends. What would you tell your friend to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re facing the same opportunity to travel right now. What would you tell yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your answers are different, you&amp;rsquo;re probably letting your physical and psychological dead weight get in the way of making objective decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard. You have to be really honest with yourself. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to face some uncomfortable personal demons. But think of everything you stand to gain by freeing yourself from the useless burdens you carry around — both in the closets you haven&amp;rsquo;t opened since you jammed your box full of &amp;ldquo;just in case&amp;rdquo; shit inside, and in the biased corners of your mind that hinder your ability to act objectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>