<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Magic on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/magic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Magic on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 09:55:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/magic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is the Magic?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/magic</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 09:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/magic</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As kids, we see a lot of the world around us as magical. Then, as we get older, the magic gives way to understanding. &lt;strong&gt;But is losing the magic a good thing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/where-is-the-magic.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Where is the magic?&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/bobjagendorf/&#34;&gt;Bob Jagendorf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-curse-of-knowledge:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;The Curse of Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was first starting out in business, I read a book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://cptr.me/XoBEmg&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Made to Stick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Among other things, I was introduced to The Curse of Knowledge, which is the idea that — as we become more familiar with a given topic — we are unable to explain an idea well to someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about any time you&amp;rsquo;ve played charades, and by the end you&amp;rsquo;re ready to scream at your team, &amp;ldquo;How could you &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; get that?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your head you were perfectly pantomiming &lt;em&gt;Gone with the Wind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What your team saw was you riding an imaginary horse and waving your fingers like you were casting a spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; something, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely difficult to see it from the perspective of someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-other-curse-of-knowledge:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;The Other Curse of Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another curse of knowledge, though, and it&amp;rsquo;s a little sneakier. &lt;em&gt;The Revenge of the Curse of Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/are-you-wizard.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;are you a wizard&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young, I thought my dad was basically a wizard because he could tie shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought my mom was conjuring up cookies through some dark art or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiny people lived in my television to entertain me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rabbit and a fat man broke into my house to leave candy and gifts every so often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My closet was a portal to the worst place imaginable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world was full of magic, and I was awestruck.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disillusionment-or-how-the-magic-died-in-a-book:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;Disillusionment, or How the Magic Died in a Book&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I learned how to tie my shoes. I added the ingredients my mom had measured out into a bowl and watched cookies take shape. I learned enough about TV signals to know there weren&amp;rsquo;t actually tiny people in there. Dad spilled the beans about Santa and the Easter Bunny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The closet still creeps me out, though.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bit by bit, the magic was stripped away and the simple truth about how things worked was laid plain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was no longer awestruck. Instead, I was condescending to the people around me who hadn&amp;rsquo;t learned yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-world-without-magic:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;A World without Magic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I see something amazing, it feels like magic. I&amp;rsquo;m blown away. I tell my friends. If there&amp;rsquo;s a YouTube clip, I&amp;rsquo;m sharing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8F6EoMdn95E?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw this guy — &lt;a href=&#34;http://dubfx.com/&#34;&gt;Dub FX&lt;/a&gt; — on the streets of Amsterdam, and I was &lt;em&gt;convinced&lt;/em&gt; he was a sorceror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just a dude with a microphone. He starts singing. Then&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;holy shit what just happened? &lt;strong&gt;It must be magic!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not. It&amp;rsquo;s a talented musician who can beatbox and operate a looping station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impressive? Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic? Not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;losing-my-sense-of-wonder:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;Losing My Sense of Wonder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not just entertainment and childhood stories that have lost the soft glow of pixie dust; I&amp;rsquo;ve felt a similar sense of disillusionment with my own life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started &lt;a href=&#34;http://copterlabs.com/&#34;&gt;building websites&lt;/a&gt;, code was still fairly mystical to me. I could do a few things, but most of what I saw was beyond my grasp; otherworldly manifestations brought forth by the legendary Mystics of Nerd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful freelancing was a dark art. Saving money required an incantation from a book bound in human skin. If I wanted to be any good at sex, I needed to sacrifice a goat at Kilauea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the more I learned, the more I realized that none of this is sacred, supernatural, or even secret. There are no shortcuts. No &amp;ldquo;weird tricks&amp;rdquo; to make someone suddently good at a skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no magic. It&amp;rsquo;s all just hard work, practice, actually giving a shit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;does-magic-matter:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;Does Magic Matter?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/Justin-Flom-Magic-Trick.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Justin Flom magic trick&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    


    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.justinflom.com/&#34;&gt;Justin Flom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, who cares if there&amp;rsquo;s no magic? We&amp;rsquo;re adults, dammit, and magic is for children. And David Blaine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure. That&amp;rsquo;s fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m not ready to give up my sense of wonder. I like being blown away by something that I don&amp;rsquo;t understand.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I want to be surrounded by wizards and fairies and sorceresses who are making impossible things happen all around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I lose my sense of wonder, then I&amp;rsquo;m resigning to a life of familiar, comfortable tasks. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing left to surprise me.&lt;/strong&gt; Giving in to the part of me that&amp;rsquo;s jaded and pessimistic that beleives there&amp;rsquo;s nothing new anyways and why bother at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d like myself without the hope for magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-how-can-we-bring-the-magic-back:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;So How Can We Bring the Magic Back?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with The Revenge of the Curse of Knowledge is that once you&amp;rsquo;ve seen behind the curtain, you can&amp;rsquo;t unsee it. The wizard is just a dude with a killer pyrotechnics setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s no going back to the kind of awe and wonder we felt as children. And that&amp;rsquo;s probably okay; I lost a lot of sleep wondering if my uncle would ever give my nose back, and I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford that today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we can find new magic, and remember to &lt;em&gt;actually feel&lt;/em&gt; that amazement that comes along with seeing something new and wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be big stuff, like learning that there were &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iflscience.com/plants-and-animals/first-ever-swimming-dinosaur-ate-sharks&#34;&gt;shark-eating dinosaurs&lt;/a&gt; or that scientists are working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nature.com/ncomms/2014/140826/ncomms5712/full/ncomms5712.html&#34;&gt;tiny robots that fight cancer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or it can be the little things we might completely dismiss if we&amp;rsquo;re not paying attention: when the new project you&amp;rsquo;re working on falls into place for the first time; when the outfit you chose today gets compliments from everyone you meet; when you think to yourself, &amp;ldquo;I really wish I had a blueberry muffin,&amp;rdquo; and then someone from the office lets you know there are muffins in the break room and should they save you one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our lives are full of small, magical moments.&lt;/strong&gt; If we&amp;rsquo;re looking for them, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-magical-in-your-life-right-now:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Magical in Your Life Right Now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think back over the last few days. &lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s happened that felt like magic?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted cheesecake the other night, and a local bar had a cheesecake special that night. I toured the Willett Distillery, saw how some of my favorite bourbon is made, and sampled some of the very rare, expensive labels. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gsnrzr0Bm80&#34;&gt;discovered a band&lt;/a&gt; that makes my hair stand on end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not quite Santa Claus, but it&amp;rsquo;s enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where have you felt a little bit of magic in your life lately?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;At least at first; eventually I want to know how it works.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>