<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 09:07:22 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Sell Without Selling</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-sell-without-selling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 09:07:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-sell-without-selling/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Marisa is a few months into her new career as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://marisamorby.com&#34;&gt;freelance copywriter and editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has a literature degree&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:degree&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:degree&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and hundreds of thousands of words under her belt. She&amp;rsquo;s written for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themuse.com/author/marisa-morby&#34;&gt;large&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lifehack.org/author/marisa-morby&#34;&gt;publications&lt;/a&gt;. She&amp;rsquo;s created an &lt;a href=&#34;http://creatingtheconversation.com/hire-probability-not-potential/&#34;&gt;information product&lt;/a&gt; and the marketing to go with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m telling you this to establish a fact: Marisa is extremely well-qualified to work as a copywriter. Anyone who hires her will be very happy with the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But despite all her qualifications, her freelance career was slow out of the gate. The skill was there, but the clients weren&amp;rsquo;t piling up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;100-of-becoming-a-freelancer-is-sales:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;100% of Becoming a Freelancer Is Sales&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spend more than a few minutes skimming &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/freelance/&#34;&gt;the freelance Subreddit&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely see at least a half-dozen posts from freelancers who are struggling and unhappy because they don&amp;rsquo;t have steady work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all qualified people&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:reddit&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:reddit&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; who could easily handle freelance contracts. And yet they&amp;rsquo;re stuck without work, or forced to race to the bottom on sites like Upwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these people aren&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;freelancers&lt;/em&gt; — they&amp;rsquo;re employees without bosses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freelancers are — first and foremost — salespeople.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-can-only-get-hired-if-someone-knows-you-exist:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;You Can Only Get Hired If Someone Knows You Exist&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/i-exist.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;I exist!&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Does anyone know you&#39;re here?

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trustcollective.com/portfolio/content/bent_drpepper.htm&#34;&gt;Bent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth about freelancing is that getting hired as a freelancer has exactly &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with your abilities as a freelancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an analogy to try and put this in perspective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say I need a deck built. I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything resembling construction or woodworking since I made a lopsided toothpick box in seventh grade shop class, so I&amp;rsquo;m walking in pretty blind here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start by asking people I trust: my dad, who&amp;rsquo;s had things built before; my friends who own houses; a buddy who used to work construction. Do they know anyone I could ask about building the deck?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After people I trust, I might put the word out through whatever channels are available to me. A call for help on Facebook or Twitter. Maybe someone knows someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I consult the internet at large. Are there any reviews? Who&amp;rsquo;s the best deck-builder in my city?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a list. Or, more than likely, one of my trusted sources will have a recommendation, and I&amp;rsquo;ll just go with that unquestioningly — why doubt the endorsement of someone I trust?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am, a deck contract awarded, and I know nothing about my contractor except that my friend Troy likes him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A freelancer&amp;rsquo;s skills mean jack shit in the decision-making process for most clients.&lt;/strong&gt; You know that cheesy cliché, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you know; it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; you know&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a cliché for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;100-of-building-client-relationships-is-skill:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;100% of Building Client Relationships Is Skill&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But wait,&amp;rdquo; you say, &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s so much more to freelancing than sales!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course. But none of that matters if you&amp;rsquo;re not selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where sales stop mattering is &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the sale is made. &lt;strong&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve won a client, gotten a deposit, and started a project, your sales ability can&amp;rsquo;t help you anymore — you&amp;rsquo;re on the hook to be good at your job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your talent as a freelancer will make clients happy, and it will keep them coming back. Plus, it creates referrals — which we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to in a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;selling-feels-gross:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Selling Feels Gross&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look: I hate selling. &lt;em&gt;Hate it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accosting a friend or stranger and asking for money feels presumptuous, invasive, and greasy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/used-car-salesman.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;used car salesman&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Selling shouldn&#39;t make you feel like this guy.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/pictures/efik45ejedd/pay-attention/&#34;&gt;Forbes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never made a cold call in my life.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:coldcalls&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:coldcalls&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve sent fewer than a dozen unsolicited emails asking for business. I get anxiety thinking about approaching someone who has no idea who I am and trying to convince them I&amp;rsquo;m worth money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power dynamics are weird; the approach puts me at a social disadvantage, and forces me to work extra hard to prove I know something. I would never buy something from a stranger I&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of before; why would I expect anyone to buy from me when I&amp;rsquo;m a stranger?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-still-have-to-own-your-position:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;You Still Have to Own Your Position&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t like approaching someone cold, but I have no issue whatsoever telling someone what I do — what I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s critical to fully own your ability to do the job you&amp;rsquo;re telling people you can do.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don&amp;rsquo;t trust yourself to be outstanding at your job, why should anyone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I started freelancing full time, I waffled on what I was. Was I a guy who worked at Kinko&amp;rsquo;s and made the odd website on the side? Or was I a web designer working to bootstrap a new freelance business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt like an impostor telling people I was a web designer. They&amp;rsquo;d think I was a liar if they walked into Kinko&amp;rsquo;s and saw me there, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not a healthy way to look at things. When I was younger, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t an issue for me: sure, I worked at Pizza Hut part-time, but I was a &lt;em&gt;musician&lt;/em&gt; first and foremost. My band didn&amp;rsquo;t make much money, but we practiced a few times a week and played a show every month or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, it was much easier to tell people I was a musician than to tell them I was a web designer.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:roles&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:roles&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was easier to call myself a musician because I had a group of friends to be part of my band, and as a freelancer I was just a guy working alone on my couch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was because being a freelancer seemed more important, and I was more afraid of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever it was, something made me uncomfortable about saying the phrase, &amp;ldquo;I am a freelance web designer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;confidence-is-critical:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Confidence Is Critical&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally quit my job at Kinko&amp;rsquo;s to become a full-time freelancer, my confidence instantly shot through the roof. I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire/&#34;&gt;set myself on fire&lt;/a&gt;, and it was time to put up or shut up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/i-am-really-good-at-this.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;I am really good at this. Self-confidence, freelance, sales.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  You have to believe in yourself, or no one else will.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As soon as I felt like a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; web designer, I immediately started landing more business.&lt;/strong&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t think this was a coincidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a chicken-egg problem: in order to have confidence about our abilities, we feel like we need clients; but in order to get clients, we need to have confidence in our abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t trying to sell people my services, mind you. I simply felt more confident saying, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a web designer, and I can build awesome websites.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People sensed my confidence, and suddenly I was being approached more often about jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/use-your-network.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Freelancers who hate selling need to use their network.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-sell-without-selling:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;How to Sell Without Selling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidence doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve all problems, though. I was getting approached for jobs, but that was because people knew who I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I didn&amp;rsquo;t like selling and wasn&amp;rsquo;t cold-calling people, how did anyone know who I was?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, there are two ways to get new business as a freelancer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sell your services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have other people sell your services for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that comfortable with option 1, so I wanted to find a way to make option 2 happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I needed to create a killer referral network.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-s-still-some-selling-involved:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s Still Some Selling Involved&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let me mislead you into thinking you won&amp;rsquo;t have to do any selling — that&amp;rsquo;s, unfortunately, just not true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll have to sell. But you can do a different, more comfortable kind of selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instead of selling to strangers, start selling to your network.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/use-your-network-whisper.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;freelancers use their network to build referrals&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Never underestimate the power of word-of-mouth.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-advantage-of-your-network:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Take Advantage of Your Network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most people, there&amp;rsquo;s a loose network of acquaintances and &amp;ldquo;buddies&amp;rdquo; spread through the community, state, country, and/or world. Not necessarily people that you keep in touch with daily, but the kind of people you speak to every month or two — just to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;be-willing-to-ask-for-help:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Be Willing to Ask for Help&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you talk to these folks, they&amp;rsquo;ll inevitably ask you, &amp;ldquo;So what&amp;rsquo;s new?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, the default answer might be to say, &amp;ldquo;Not much. I&amp;rsquo;m working as a freelancer now, which is pretty exciting. How are you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is factual, &lt;em&gt;but it could be much better.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, look: we&amp;rsquo;re not trying to scam our friends into anything. But we &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want to make sure our friends are aware of what we&amp;rsquo;re doing, and that they could help us do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when our friend asks, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s new?&amp;rdquo; we don&amp;rsquo;t brush the question off. Instead, we present a friendly, opt-in request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, my biggest news is that I&amp;rsquo;ve just start working as a freelance web designer, which is pretty exciting. The biggest challenge so far is finding clients, so if you know anyone who needs a website, I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate it if you&amp;rsquo;d drop my name or make an intro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You haven&amp;rsquo;t asked for anything that puts your friend out. All you&amp;rsquo;re doing is putting it in her head that she can help you out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the deck analogy from earlier? People love to have the answers to other people&amp;rsquo;s problems. &lt;strong&gt;If my friend can connect me to someone who needs my services, she wins twice:&lt;/strong&gt; she helped me grow my business, and helped her other friend solve their website problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-don-t-have-to-wait-for-an-opening:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;You Don&amp;rsquo;t Have to Wait for an Opening&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also start this conversation. Email your acquaintances to catch them up on things, including a nudge to send any potential leads your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That email is almost the same. It might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, friend–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you&amp;rsquo;re doing well! I wanted to drop you a line to see how things are going and catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Talk about things that are relevant: do they have kids? were they starting something new last time you spoke?]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things on my end are pretty exciting right now. My biggest news is that I&amp;rsquo;ve just start working as a freelance web designer. The biggest challenge so far is finding clients, so if you know anyone who needs a website, I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate it if you&amp;rsquo;d drop my name or make an intro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Catch them up on anything else in your life that you want to share here.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I hope you&amp;rsquo;re having an awesome summer. I&amp;rsquo;ll look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This message isn&amp;rsquo;t hiding an agenda. You&amp;rsquo;re not trying to weasel something out of a friend. You&amp;rsquo;re simply sharing big life news and making it known that — if they happen to hear someone needs a website — they can help you out by spreading the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you sent this message without the note about referring leads, it would still be a meaningful message to you and your friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remember-these-are-your-friends:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Remember: These Are Your Friends&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/dont-be-a-dick.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;How not to be a dick.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dontbeadickday.com&#34;&gt;Wil Wheaton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big goal, of course, is not to be a dick about this. You are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; going to get good results by pestering everyone you know about buying a website to &amp;ldquo;help you out&amp;rdquo; or whatever. That&amp;rsquo;s multi-level marketing — are you a freelancer, or are you hawking Scentsy candles?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you send an email, make sure you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be upset if you received the same email from your friend.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to be made aware that someone is looking for work; it&amp;rsquo;s another thing entirely to be pumped for leads and/or pressured into buying things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll be fine if you just follow Wheaton&amp;rsquo;s Law: &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t be a dick.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grow-your-network:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Grow Your Network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to your existing network, make an effort to meet people — especially people who are in the industries you&amp;rsquo;d like to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has the added benefit of building a community. You can help people in whatever way you&amp;rsquo;re able, and they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to reciprocate as best as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;attend-local-meetups-and-professional-groups:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Attend Local Meetups and Professional Groups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-community.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;freelancers build local community&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  In Missoula, running a small workshop in 2010.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started out, I started attending a small group called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Montana-Programmers/&#34;&gt;MT Programmers&lt;/a&gt; in Missoula. &lt;strong&gt;I started to get involved, and through the people I met there, I was introduced to more and more people in the community&lt;/strong&gt; — more than a few of my first gigs came from these introductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, I spent money to attend conferences, and &lt;strong&gt;I found myself surrounded by people who were focusing on their businesses and willing to spend money to get what they needed&lt;/strong&gt; — often, this meant they needed website help, so it naturally came up in conversation that we could help each other out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bring-your-clients-into-your-network:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Bring Your Clients into Your Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I get a new project, I bust my ass to make sure the client is really happy with me. I know that &lt;strong&gt;happy clients are worth &lt;em&gt;way more&lt;/em&gt; than just the value of a given project.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my clients became life-long friends. I&amp;rsquo;ve been invited to book launch parties, weddings, vacations, and more. This could never have happened if I didn&amp;rsquo;t show that I&amp;rsquo;m a stand-up guy through my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a financial perspective, lots of my clients came back later with additional projects. Far more of them referred friends and colleagues to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ask-clients-for-referrals:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Ask Clients for Referrals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my wrapping-up process with clients is to send an email letting them know that I don&amp;rsquo;t advertise, and the only way I get new clients is by word-of-mouth from my existing clients. I ask them — if they feel like I did a good job and they&amp;rsquo;re happy with my work — to please keep me in mind if they meet someone else who needs a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also offer a referral bonus as a token of my appreciation. It&amp;rsquo;s not much — $100 for any referral who signs on with me — but I like to send it over as a token of my appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make sure to send a personal note thanking the person for each referral as well, except in the case of my highest-referring clients — they send too many leads, so I&amp;rsquo;d be spamming them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;eventually-you-can-stop-selling:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Eventually You Can Stop Selling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple years, &lt;strong&gt;I had a large enough network that my referral stream was too much for me to handle.&lt;/strong&gt; I received several inquiries a week from people who were serious about web projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was swamped. I had to hire subcontractors to help. I had a waiting list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;strong&gt;this meant I never had to go out and &amp;ldquo;do sales&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; the way that freelancers typically view sales. No cold calls or emails, no advertising, no proposals. Just a steady stream of referrals — which is a different (far less awkward) type of selling.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:dating&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:dating&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;freelancing-is-for-conversationalists:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Freelancing Is for Conversationalists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s direct sales or leveraging a network for introductions, &lt;strong&gt;your job as a freelancer is to generate conversations with people who may need your services.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that your ability to speak in a clear and friendly manner is perhaps your most valuable skill. If you sound confident, and you don&amp;rsquo;t seem like a dick, chances are you&amp;rsquo;ll get the job over someone who seems unsure or comes off as abrasive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As unfair as it may seem, a freelancer with better conversational skills will likely win a job over a more competent freelancer who speaks poorly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-can-be-successful-without-selling:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;You Can Be Successful Without Selling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a slower road than hard selling, but you can successfully build a freelance career only by networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let your friends know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them to refer anyone who might need your services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go out and meet people — especially if they&amp;rsquo;re in your target demographic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be helpful and confident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kick ass for your clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them for referrals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a referral network after my first project, and it grew steadily with each new project I took on. It seemed to me that most projects would lead to one referral, and every once in a while a project would lead to a huge number of referrals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you hate sales, don&amp;rsquo;t worry — you can still be a freelancer. You may need to hold onto your day job a bit longer, but you can get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just stay confident, ask for leads, and remember that your skills finish the job and earn new referrals — so do good work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:degree&#34;&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t actually remember &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what her degree is. It&amp;rsquo;s something to do with English, writing, and/or literature. Whatever it is, it&amp;rsquo;s very relevant to writing professionally.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:degree&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:reddit&#34;&gt;Correction: 61% of Reddit users are actually &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squirreltruth.com/facts&#34;&gt;seven squirrels in a human suit&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:reddit&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:coldcalls&#34;&gt;These work. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; make cold calls. I just never liked the idea of becoming a telemarketer for my own services, so I worked around the problem.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:coldcalls&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:roles&#34;&gt;This was especially odd given that I was always a mediocre musician at best, but web design came to me pretty naturally. Comparatively, my design skill set was stronger than my musical skill set almost immediately.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:roles&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:dating&#34;&gt;I think of it like dating, because to me it&amp;rsquo;s kind of the same thing. I have &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; had success approaching a stranger and wooing her. However, if I get introduced by a mutual friend, I feel far less awkward and there&amp;rsquo;s a much higher chance that we&amp;rsquo;ll hit it off.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I think this happens because the introduction creates a reason for me to be there. My friend has vouched for me, and this means the conversation starts on level ground — I don&amp;rsquo;t have to prove I deserve to be there, and the conversation can progress naturally.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:dating&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Freelance from Anywhere in the World: Audio Interview</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-freelance-anywhere-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 09:14:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-freelance-anywhere-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A little while back, I got an email from an anonymous email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guy — let&amp;rsquo;s call him &amp;ldquo;John&amp;rdquo; — had a lot of questions about how I was actually making my lifestyle work. Never mind the travel tips, he said, I want to know how you &lt;em&gt;make money.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked John if he&amp;rsquo;d be willing to get on a call with me and let me record our conversation. He agreed, and we talked for about 50 minutes. John grilled me on how I got started, how long it took me to break even, and how I keep things moving now that I&amp;rsquo;m half a world away from the people I work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/206033656&amp;color=e26700&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The audio ends rather abruptly; John wanted to ask a couple questions off the record (that were very specific to his own situation), so I cut the audio off there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, I&amp;rsquo;ve summarized what we talked about on the call. John&amp;rsquo;s questions are the headlines, and my (heavily paraphrased) responses are the text in each section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-how-to-freelance-from-anywhere-in-the-world.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;How to Freelance from Anywhere in the World&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-actual-nature-of-the-work-you-re-doing:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;What Is the Actual Nature of the Work You&amp;rsquo;re Doing?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I work as a freelance web developer, but I have a single long-term contract with one client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day-to-day tasks center around software research and development: I build experimental apps quickly to test new ideas (kind of a one-man &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skunkworks_project&#34;&gt;skunkworks&lt;/a&gt;). I try out something crazy on a small alpha audience, and if it proves viable, the project is handed off to the production team as a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; project with dedicated resources and so on.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:techstack&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:techstack&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-you-get-to-the-point-of-feeling-established:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Did You Get to the Point of Feeling &amp;ldquo;Established&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within a year and a half of going full-time freelance, I was able to make about $30K/year. For me, who had no family, debt, or much overhead at all, was more than enough to get by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-you-get-started:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Did You Get Started?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first got interested in web design when I was playing in a band. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to hire help, so I volunteered myself to do design when we needed it. It stayed interesting, so I kept learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the band broke up, I was still interested in web design. I built a website for a close friend of mine, which led to leads for a couple local websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of those leads gave me the opportunity to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/how-to-become-location-independent/&#34;&gt;quit my day job and freelance full-time&lt;/a&gt;. I took the plunge, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been my own boss ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-your-business-grew-organically:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;So Your Business Grew Organically?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first I had to take work wherever I could find it, and I spent a lot of time chasing leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, though, I started to get emails from people asking about websites. Most of them were health and fitness professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my work for Nate — the first website I ever built that wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me — and due largely in part to Nate&amp;rsquo;s incredible success in the health and fitness sector as a journalist, I was introduced to a few up-and-coming fitness pros who needed websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built sites for John Romaniello, Tony Gentilcore, and Mike Robertson. They all had (or would soon have) enormous online presence, and their recommendations carried a lot of weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guys were rising stars in the industry. They were speaking at conferences, writing articles, getting interviewed in major publications — they were the connectors, to put it into &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tipping_Point#The_three_rules&#34;&gt;Gladwellian terms&lt;/a&gt;. Other people looking to make it as fitness pros asked my clients for advice, and when it came to web design, my name was dropped frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This turned into a very strong referral network that became effective enough over time that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to go looking for clients anymore; I had 3–5 new leads coming to me each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had become &amp;ldquo;the guy for that&amp;rdquo; — this has been the ultimate secret to my success. I have become dependably excellent in my area of expertise: my clients could trust me to solve their problems effectively without requiring much of their time. That trust led them to continue working with me and referring me to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-long-did-it-take-before-you-felt-comfortable:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Long Did It Take Before You Felt Comfortable?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took about a year and a half to get to the point where I was making $30K/year. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything extravagant, but I was able to live comfortably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dealing-with-dry-months:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;Dealing with Dry Months&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where things were rough for me, starting out, was when I had a slow month. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think ahead and put money aside when I had good months, so the dry months were rough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have solved that problem fast, had I been a little smarter about things, and it would have made me far more stable as a freelancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was dumb, so I&amp;rsquo;d have a good month and — instead of putting it away to cover a slow month later — I&amp;rsquo;d say, &amp;ldquo;Fuck yeah, let&amp;rsquo;s go to Hawaii!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-you-gain-the-technical-competency-to-get-where-you-are-now:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Did You Gain the Technical Competency to Get Where You Are Now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been really curious about how things work, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s probably the single biggest advantage I have in life.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:dad&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:dad&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to being generally curious, I also had a need: my band needed a website if we were going to tour effectively, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I learned to customize a MySpace page. Then I built a crappy website after a shitload of Googling. I built it again. And again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would come up against a problem that we needed to solve, and then I would find a way to solve it. It was fun for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-hubris-of-being-19:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;The Hubris of Being 19&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was curious about how to make more powerful tools, and I needed to find a way to let my clients update their own websites without requiring me to go in and do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of the open source community at this time, or of WordPress. Plus, I was a cocky teenager who thought I could build something better than anything else that was out there — so I built a CMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a terrible business plan, but an excellent learning tool. As a result I understand a lot of what happens behind the scenes in a tool like WordPress or Ghost, and when those tools don&amp;rsquo;t do what I need them to do, I can usually figure out a way to build something new to solve my problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-you-get-marketing-skills-in-combination-with-the-tech-skills:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Did You Get Marketing Skills in Combination with the Tech Skills?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have this delusional belief that — if I continue to study — eventually I&amp;rsquo;ll understand everything.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since a lot of my clients work in the same industry, I saw them all running up against the same kinds of problems. I also saw what was working for my more successful clients, and what wasn&amp;rsquo;t for the clients who were struggling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And since I love learning how things work, I started to dig into the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; of it all. I saw patterns emerging, and I learned how to apply what I learned to new clients in a way that helped them grow their businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had marketing experience out of the necessity of being a broke musician. I had to figure out a way to convince high school kids to come pay $5 to watch a band they&amp;rsquo;d never heard of before from Montana — it was a good primer on marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, on bigger projects, I&amp;rsquo;d hire experts to come in and set up complicated marketing efforts, and I&amp;rsquo;d watch what they did and keep asking why they were doing it. So even when I didn&amp;rsquo;t do the work myself, I tried to continue learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-would-you-design-your-own-curriculum-for-getting-a-skill-set:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Would You Design Your Own Curriculum for Getting a Skill Set?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical side is the biggest job pool, but you can find non-technical jobs as well: customer support, executive assistants, writers, accountants, lawyers — the world is set up to make most knowledge work possible remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to go the tech route, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to figure out how you learn best: some people get the most out of reading tutorials and documentation; others have better luck with video instruction like &lt;a href=&#34;https://teamtreehouse.com/&#34;&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;; and then there&amp;rsquo;s always something to be said for learning in an in-person, hands-on environment.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:hands-on&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:hands-on&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For hands-on training, there are a lot of new bootcamps popping up all over. In Portland, for example, you can take a four-month course through &lt;a href=&#34;http://epicodus.com&#34;&gt;Epicodus&lt;/a&gt; that guarantees real-world job experience through an internship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For non-technical careers, start looking for jobs on the many job boards out there, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://remoteok.io/&#34;&gt;remoteok.io&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://weworkremotely.com/&#34;&gt;weworkremotely.com&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wfh.io/&#34;&gt;wfh.io&lt;/a&gt;. Many of the listings are for tech jobs, but there are a good number of support, content, marketing, and human resources jobs posted as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-hurdles:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;What Are the Hurdles?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easily the biggest hurdle to making it as a freelancer is your own temperament. Are you excited about your work and eager to get tasks knocked out? Or are you more likely to need someone cracking the whip over you before you&amp;rsquo;ll get things done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Further reading: &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/scheduling-maximum-productivity/&#34;&gt;Get More Done Faster — Scheduling for Maximum Productivity&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;breaking-into-the-industry:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;Breaking into the Industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just keep doing projects in the industry. If you have to start out doing free work, do it. But try to get paid every time — you&amp;rsquo;re providing a service, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to learn cars, I&amp;rsquo;d buy books, hang out with my more mechanically inclined friends, bother my mechanic with questions about what he was doing and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d start with small projects: changing my own oil or changing the tires. Then I&amp;rsquo;d graduate up to more difficult tasks — my ultimate aim would be to know enough to take the car apart and put it back together again, and I&amp;rsquo;d get there one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find a project that&amp;rsquo;s about 10% above your skill level and take it. &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire/&#34;&gt;Set yourself on fire&lt;/a&gt; to learn the new skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 10% beyond your skill set, there&amp;rsquo;s very little risk that you&amp;rsquo;ll be unable to figure it out; where the risk comes in is if you get too ambitious and do something that requires learning several layers of skills to complete — taking a job as a lifeguard before you&amp;rsquo;ve learned to swim, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find a balance between challenging and &amp;ldquo;in way over my head&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-mutually-intelligible-are-programming-languages:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Mutually Intelligible Are Programming Languages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most programming languages share ideas. JavaScript and PHP have different syntax, but a lot of the concepts carry through. Each programming language is usually created by taking a programmer&amp;rsquo;s idea of the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; features of any number of existing programming languages, and adding or removing features as they see fit.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:clarification&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:clarification&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to build the mental models at first, which is the hard part. After that you&amp;rsquo;ll start to see patterns emerge. It starts out feeling like total nonsense, but similarities show up, and concepts cross languages. You&amp;rsquo;ll find that each new language you learn takes a lot less time than the one before it did.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:spoken&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:spoken&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-see-in-the-future-and-how-are-you-positioning-yourself-what-s-your-relationship-with-new-tools:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;What Do You See in the Future, and How Are You Positioning Yourself? What&amp;rsquo;s Your Relationship with New Tools?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to find a balance between using tools that solve problems (WordPress will solve many of your problems very quickly) and learning how things work (understand that WordPress is built in PHP, and if you know PHP you can get WordPress to do &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; rather than being limited by WordPress plugins).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-approach-data-security:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Do You Approach Data Security?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate in that most of what I do isn&amp;rsquo;t sensitive. (The most sensitive data I deal with is email addresses — and I try to avoid even dealing with those.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tunnelbear.com/&#34;&gt;TunnelBear&lt;/a&gt; as a simple, cheap &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple solution that will do a pretty good job of protecting my data without making security an additional job for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://db.tt/gPmxlbE&#34;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;disclosure: if you sign up with that link, I get bonus storage&lt;/em&gt;) to make sure I don&amp;rsquo;t lose any data — I could drop my computer off a cliff and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t lose any of my files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-long-do-you-intend-to-travel:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Long Do You Intend to Travel?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a definite answer to this question. I intend to travel for as long as travel seems like the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m always checking in with myself: am I doing this because I&amp;rsquo;ve convinced myself that I&amp;rsquo;m the type of person that travels, or because it actually makes me happy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A time may come in a decade, a year, a month — or tomorrow — when I decide that I&amp;rsquo;d be happier if I was in one place instead of moving every few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for right now, I don&amp;rsquo;t see an end in sight. I expect I&amp;rsquo;ll be traveling for at least the next couple years unless something unexpected happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-overcome-the-absence-of-in-person-interaction:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;How Do You Overcome the Absence of In-Person Interaction?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John asks, &amp;ldquo;How do you make sure people remember you when you&amp;rsquo;re not in the room? If your best impression is face-to-face, how do you preserve that?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I build my business as a &amp;ldquo;remote first&amp;rdquo; workplace. I&amp;rsquo;ve always worked with people without regard for geographical constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I would only correspond with my clients by email, but there were drawbacks to this: my relationships were weak and strictly business, and it can be hard to communicate tone effectively. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;d think I was making a silly joke, and my client would think I was being a dick; other times, I&amp;rsquo;d think my client was unhappy, but they&amp;rsquo;d just responded in a hurry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I require phone calls (preferably video calls) for big deliverables and check-ins. This allows me to walk through what I did and why, and gather feedback in realtime. It also allows discussion, just like a face-to-face meeting would. You lose the stiffness of email, and you build a real connection with your clients. This has resolved a lot of conflicts before they had a chance to start — it&amp;rsquo;s easy to yell in an email; it&amp;rsquo;s hard to yell at someone who&amp;rsquo;s right in front of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I do try to show up where my clients are from time to time. If I know I&amp;rsquo;ll be somewhere that a client lives, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to meet them for dinner or coffee. When a conference is happening where a good group of my clients is planning to show up, I&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can make it work. Even with video calls, there&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of added value in just spending time with people, in person, without any agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-yourself-useful:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;Make Yourself Useful&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I meet a potential client, I don&amp;rsquo;t try to sell them something. I just share a solution if I have one.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:solution&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:solution&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This establishes me as an expert and — even if they don&amp;rsquo;t hire me — they&amp;rsquo;ll remember that I was able to help them out. If they meet someone who needs help in the future, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a referral, and if they need to hire help in the future they&amp;rsquo;ll think of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-questions-do-you-have-about-going-location-independent:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a&#34;&gt;What Questions Do You Have About Going Location-Independent?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John had questions that centered largely around technical skills, running a freelance business, and client acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What questions do you have about becoming location-independent? Click the discussion link and fire away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:techstack&#34;&gt;For the technically inclined, I&amp;rsquo;m working heavily in realtime video right now: Node.js, Socket.IO, WebRTC powering the back-end, and a plain vanilla HTML/CSS/JS UI.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:techstack&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:dad&#34;&gt;My dad would play the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; game in reverse when I was growing up. Whenever I had a chore, or a homework assignment, or anything at all, really, my dad would ask me how it was done. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get away with cop-out answers: I needed to have a thorough understanding of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; priming a lawn mower helped it start; or &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it was faster to sweep out the garage if I followed a pattern instead of whisking the dirt around haphazardly; &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; the lights turned on when I flipped the switch. As a kid, it was fucking infuriating; as an adult, I don&amp;rsquo;t think any other single factor has contributed as much to my success as my ingrained habit of asking why something works (or doesn&amp;rsquo;t) instead of shrugging and continuing about my business.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:dad&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:hands-on&#34;&gt;In the audio, I refer to &amp;ldquo;Code School&amp;rdquo; in Portland as a bootcamp. It&amp;rsquo;s actually called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epicodus.com/&#34;&gt;Epicodus&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:hands-on&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:clarification&#34;&gt;I had some of my facts wrong in the audio interview. I talked about languages having ancestors, which isn&amp;rsquo;t correct. &lt;a href=&#34;https://line.do/ww/history-of-php/r5q4x1/vertical&#34;&gt;PHP&lt;/a&gt; was &lt;em&gt;written&lt;/em&gt; in C. JavaScript is a standard of its own, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7005729/what-language-is-javascript-written-in&#34;&gt;interpreters&lt;/a&gt; that are written in C, C++, Java, or even — in truly meta fashion — JavaScript.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:clarification&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:spoken&#34;&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested this theory, but I have a hunch this applies to spoken language as well. I&amp;rsquo;m getting better at Spanish, and just barely starting to learn French; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily feel &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; to learn French, but I have some strategies and constructs in place that are definitely helpful.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:spoken&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:solution&#34;&gt;Sharing a solution is very different from doing actual work. If we&amp;rsquo;re talking and I can help you out by just rattling off some knowledge I have that applies to your situation, then I&amp;rsquo;ll do that. But I won&amp;rsquo;t pull out my laptop and solve the problem for you unless we work out a budget and scope first.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:40764f8fabb8b8dbf4b836b6c199189a:solution&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ditch the Day Job: How to Become Location-Independent</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-become-location-independent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 06:32:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-become-location-independent/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Becoming location independent clears the way for you to start working from anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who&amp;rsquo;s ever considered long-term travel, location-independent income is a non-negotiable part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started, though, can be stressful — and scary as hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start by telling you how I made the transition out of the traditional workplace and into a role that allows me to make a living no matter where I am in the world. (Hello from Thailand!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterward, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over several options for making a living from anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-departure-from-the-9-to-5:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;My Departure from the 9-to-5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in my early twenties, I moonlighted as a freelance web developer while keeping 9-to-5 jobs ranging from a night auditor at a hotel to a project manager at a Kinko&amp;rsquo;s to a graveyard shift cook at a bowling alley diner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I wanted to work for myself, but I had no idea where to start. I only had a few clients, and sometimes I would go a month between jobs. What if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find work? What if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pay my rent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last job — working at Kinko&amp;rsquo;s — was a huge help in building my resolve to avoid corporate culture. Kinko&amp;rsquo;s had just been acquired by FedEx, and I watched as all the things that Kinko&amp;rsquo;s used to do for employees that made them love their jobs were systematically stripped away and replaced with more aggressive performance goals and stricter punishments for missing them —all with little or no reward for meeting goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a year I watched FedEx methodically dismantle employee morale. I kept my spirits up by working my off hours on web projects, repeating to myself over and over, &lt;em&gt;This is just for now. Things will get better soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-terrifying-glimmer-of-hope:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;A Terrifying Glimmer of Hope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got my chance, it felt like a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/best-friends/&#34;&gt;good friend&lt;/a&gt; had introduced me to a guy named David, who was trying to start a company building simple websites for B-list-or-lower actors and performers. His budget wasn&amp;rsquo;t huge, but he could offer me $1,300/month for three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, I was spending about $1,050/month on living expenses. If I took David&amp;rsquo;s offer, I&amp;rsquo;d have $250/month to pay my mobile phone bill, buy any necessities, and, y&amp;rsquo;know, &lt;em&gt;eat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it was only three months of guaranteed income. What if he didn&amp;rsquo;t renew for a fourth month? What if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any income?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-siren-song-of-security:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;The Siren Song of Security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same week I started discussing David&amp;rsquo;s project, I got an unexpected offer from a local creative agency. They asked me to come in and interview with them — they&amp;rsquo;d heard of me because of my volunteer work with a local coders&amp;rsquo; meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went through the interview process, which involved several days&amp;rsquo; worth of meetings with different department heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, they told me they were prepared to offer me a job as a web developer and designer. I would more or less be the entirety of their digital department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the meeting, we finally got down to heavy details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;d want to bring you in at a mid-range salary to show you that we&amp;rsquo;re serious,&amp;rdquo; said the woman who made the hiring decisions. &amp;ldquo;We can offer you $30,000/year.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt a rush of mixed emotions. On the one hand, $2,500/month was more than I&amp;rsquo;d ever made before, and it would provide me with significantly more spending money than the freelance gig. But on the other hand, $30K was a &lt;em&gt;mid-range&lt;/em&gt; developer salary at this agency? I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what was normal, but this felt pretty low to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Okay,&amp;rdquo; I started carefully, &amp;ldquo;so assuming this all goes well and I&amp;rsquo;m a good fit for the team. What&amp;rsquo;s my growth potential here? Would I be able to see an increase in that salary after proving I&amp;rsquo;m able to handle the workload here?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shifted uncomfortably. &amp;ldquo;Well, yes. I would say you have the potential to make up to $35,000 a year here, assuming everything goes well.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt my heart sink. I had a vision of software development at an ad agency as a glamorous job, full of challenging work and long hours, but with high pay to make it all worth it. But this job was offering me less than my manager at Kinko&amp;rsquo;s made in a year, with virtually no growth potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But still&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little voice&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc:mom&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc:mom&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; nagged at me that this was &lt;em&gt;security&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;stability&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;a steady paycheck&lt;/em&gt;. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-by-on-ramen-noodles-and-hope:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Getting By on Ramen Noodles and Hope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep much the next few days. I kept rolling around my options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logical part of me was convinced. &lt;em&gt;Take the agency job. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of money, but it&amp;rsquo;s experience that you can use to trade up in a couple years. And it&amp;rsquo;s not like you&amp;rsquo;re taking a pay cut to move into a job you like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my gut didn&amp;rsquo;t feel right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re only considering this agency job because you&amp;rsquo;re a chickenshit,&lt;/em&gt; it hissed at me. &lt;em&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve been telling everyone you know that you just need a chance to be self-employed, and now you have that chance. So are you going to take it? Or are you a liar and a coward?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was right, I realized. I had been looking for this chance for over a year, and now it was in my hands. If I turned it down, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be sure how long it would take to get another chance like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I called the agency and declined, citing my concerns about growth potential. They seemed miffed, but it also sounded like they were already expecting me to turn it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I called David and accepted the contract. He told me he&amp;rsquo;d drop the check in the mail that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put in my two weeks&amp;rsquo; notice at Kinko&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I bought a pallet of ramen noodles, sat down on my couch, and hyperventilated for the rest of the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-payoff:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;The Payoff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After leaving Kinko&amp;rsquo;s, a funny thing happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leads I&amp;rsquo;d been talking to for months without any movement were suddenly ready to pull the trigger. I started getting new leads around town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was almost like people could smell that I&amp;rsquo;d started taking web development seriously. I was no longer doing web design on the side; &lt;em&gt;I was a web developer, full stop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between receiving David&amp;rsquo;s first check and the end of our contract (five months later), I had built up enough business to be bringing in an average of $3,000/month. If I could keep this up, I&amp;rsquo;d make $36,000 or so for the year — more than the agency would have paid assuming they found me especially good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was terrified to leave the security of my day job. I was convinced that I had no hope of making a decent living on my own. I was sure that the concerns of my parents, past employers, teachers — basically every adult I&amp;rsquo;d ever met — were correct and that the only way to really make it was to get a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; job: the kind with health insurance and paid vacation and annual reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my instincts said there was a better way. And I took a leap of faith, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire/&#34;&gt;set myself on fire&lt;/a&gt;, and trusted myself to be okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And my life has never been the same since. I&amp;rsquo;m happier now, more confident in myself, less bothered by the unknown — every part of my life improved as a direct result of taking charge of my life and becoming self-employed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/become-location-independent.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;how to become location independent and earn a living from anywhere&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-options-exist-for-remote-work:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;What Options Exist for Remote Work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many options for making a living without having to be physically present in a particular place. Three of the most common (and versatile) options are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a passive income stream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convince your boss to let you work remotely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work from anywhere as a freelancer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-passive-income:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Create Passive Income&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passive income is the most alluring form of making money remotely. After all, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to make money while they sleep?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal experience with passive income has been generating it for other people; my own passive revenue streams are limited to affiliate sales on Amazon, book royalties, and whatever my investments earn — in short, it&amp;rsquo;s a very small part of my overall income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that reason, I won&amp;rsquo;t talk too much about generating passive income. There are other people more qualified to cover the subject — check out Chris Guillebeau&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307951529/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0307951529&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=jl1985-20&amp;amp;linkId=MDOK4KJXNHWBOYVV&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;$100 Startup&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for a good starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;digital-products:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Digital Products&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most successful passive revenue stream I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to reproduce for my clients has been digital products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, my friend and client &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theptdc.com/who-we-are/jonathan-goodman-2/&#34;&gt;Jonathan Goodman&lt;/a&gt; runs a business from all over the world that sells digital products helping personal trainers become better at personal training, selling their services, and establishing additional revenue streams like online coaching. He has a small handful of products — most of which he created, built a marketing funnel for, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t had to touch (much) since — that earn him a comfortable living without a lot of weekly effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-services:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Online Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another friend and client, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.johnromaniello.com/&#34;&gt;John &amp;ldquo;Roman&amp;rdquo; Romaniello&lt;/a&gt;, has built passive income by creating companies that he more or less only provides ideas for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roman&amp;rsquo;s created an online client management platform that he uses for his own online clients, but that he also sells to other coaches on a monthly basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has a development team to keep it afloat, a management and marketing team to keep it running smoothly, and various other people on his team to take care of the day-to-day operation of the company — his only real job at the company is to give direction for what the team should focus on next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;passive-is-kind-of-a-misnomer:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Passive&amp;rdquo; Is Kind of a Misnomer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important, though, to note that while Jon doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to put a lot of effort into building the products themselves, and Roman doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to deal with much of the daily operations of his coaching platform, both of these guys spend &lt;em&gt;a lot of time&lt;/em&gt; working on creating content and staying active on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passive income is very rarely &lt;em&gt;completely&lt;/em&gt; passive, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-a-full-time-job-that-lets-you-work-remotely:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Find a Full-Time Job That Lets You Work Remotely&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways, this is a little bit like having your cake and eating it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can find full-time employment that&amp;rsquo;s entirely remote, you&amp;rsquo;ve effectively managed to hold on to the security of a 9-to-5 job while also gaining the freedom of working from anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hunt-for-remote-jobs:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Hunt for Remote Jobs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, being a remote worker is no longer uncommon. Many notable companies, including Automattic (the company that built WordPress), Basecamp, and Buffer are almost entirely remote, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://globalworkplaceanalytics.com/telecommuting-statistics&#34;&gt;reports claim&lt;/a&gt; that 3.3 million full-time employees in the US workforce were able to telecommute at least part of the time as of 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone looking to start a new career, or move to a new job, there are a large number of job boards that specialize exclusively in listing remote jobs, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://remoteok.io/&#34;&gt;remoteok.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jobs.remotive.io/&#34;&gt;jobs.remotive.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://weworkremotely.com/&#34;&gt;weworkremotely.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wfh.io/&#34;&gt;WFH.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few other options — if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for remote work, you won&amp;rsquo;t have too much trouble finding companies willing to hire you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;convince-your-boss-to-let-you-work-remotely:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Convince Your Boss to Let You Work Remotely&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a little more challenging, but if you feel confident that you can do your existing job without going into the office, it&amp;rsquo;s worth trying to convince your boss that it&amp;rsquo;s possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a strong case for why the company would be better off with you telecommuting, and build trust in your ability to work from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(For an in-depth strategy, read &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/convince-your-boss-remote-work/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Convince Your Boss to Let You Work Remotely&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;freelance-remotely:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Freelance Remotely&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously the simplest and most difficult way to make a living remotely, freelancing is one of the most common approaches taken by digital nomads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the riskiest prospect because there&amp;rsquo;s no guarantee of work, but with a little care and a lot of effort, you can build a strong referral network to keep your sales funnel full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;position-yourself-as-an-expert:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Position Yourself as an Expert&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find things that you&amp;rsquo;re very good at and interested in — the things you get excited talking about — and start teaching them: speak at local meetups, submit conference talk proposals, write tutorials, and do anything you can to publicly stake a claim that you &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; whatever arena you want to work in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes you appear to be an authority, and people looking for freelancers want to hire the best available help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an added bonus, &lt;strong&gt;nothing will force you to &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; know your shit like trying to teach it to someone else.&lt;/strong&gt; You can&amp;rsquo;t gloss over details when you&amp;rsquo;re explaining it to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-damn-sure-you-get-a-good-referral:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Make Damn Sure You Get a Good Referral&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re working remotely, you may not get the chance to go out and meet your clients — especially in more remote locations — so you need to make sure that other people are doing your sales for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get a client, become their hero. They&amp;rsquo;ve come to you to solve a problem, so solve that problem completely, and make sure they know what&amp;rsquo;s going on at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can A) solve your clients&amp;rsquo; problems for them, and B) make sure they never felt like you had disappeared&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc:communication&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc:communication&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; during the project, you&amp;rsquo;re almost ensured a good referral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of each successful project, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to ask your client to either send you a testimonial (you can use this for marketing, too) or ask them to complete a survey about your performance — in either case, they finish the project by reminding themselves all the things they liked about working with you. Later, when a friend mentions a problem that you can solve, your client will be eager to drop your name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;remove-the-anchor-of-office-bound-work:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc&#34;&gt;Remove the Anchor of Office-Bound Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing the anchor of reporting to an office every day is an astonishingly liberating accomplishment, whether your goal is to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;sell everything and travel the world&lt;/a&gt;, or simply to cut your commute and eliminate the requirement to wear pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also daunting, and it requires some legwork to make it happen. But don&amp;rsquo;t give up — I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to meet &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt; who made the transition to remote work and regretted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc:mom&#34;&gt;This voice sounded alarmingly similar to my mother&amp;rsquo;s.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc:mom&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc:communication&#34;&gt;#protip: The window of time between your last communication and when the client will wonder what you&amp;rsquo;re doing is much shorter than you think. Daily communication is ideal — you don&amp;rsquo;t need to deliver something every day, but make sure they know you&amp;rsquo;re working on their project.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:c51eaed3932b197d41756e8db78d0bdc:communication&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Convince Your Boss to Let You Work Remotely</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/convince-your-boss-remote-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 04:13:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/convince-your-boss-remote-work/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of benefits to being an employee. Things like health care, paid vacation, and — of course — a steady paycheck are nothing to scoff at. But if you&amp;rsquo;re sick of being stuck in an office, how can you convince your boss to let you work remotely?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re ready to take off and see the world, looking to cut down on your commute, or if you&amp;rsquo;d just like to have extra time with your loved ones, telecommuting is the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while the business world seems to be coming around to telecommuting, you may still be facing an uphill battle to convince your boss to let you cut the cord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can you convince your boss to let you work from home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/how-to-convince-your-boss-remote-work.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;how to convince your boss to let your work from home&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-out-the-logistics-ahead-of-time:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee&#34;&gt;Work Out the Logistics Ahead of Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want your boss to take your proposal seriously, make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve got all the details worked out before you bring it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your office has anything special in place — a VPN, for example — figure out how you can connect to it from home. Be ready to explain, in vivid detail, all the ways you&amp;rsquo;ll be overcoming hurdles between you and your goal of working from home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;arm-yourself-with-research:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee&#34;&gt;Arm Yourself with Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re ready to back up your claims with actual data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, you&amp;rsquo;re not going to have any trouble finding research to support your claims. There&amp;rsquo;s a growing mountain of research papers proving that employees &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; employers benefit from remote working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look for it, you&amp;rsquo;ll find data proving that remote workers are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18020794&#34;&gt;less likely to quit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2014/01/to-raise-productivity-let-more-employees-work-from-home&#34;&gt;more productive&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sqwiggle.com/working-remotely-saves-money/&#34;&gt;less expensive for the company&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s just the tip of the iceberg; for a more in-depth look, read &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-everyone-wins/&#34;&gt;how remote work is a win for everyone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;focus-on-the-benefits-to-the-company:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee&#34;&gt;Focus on the Benefits to the Company&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put yourself in your boss&amp;rsquo;s shoes: if someone walked into your office and started talking about this thing they want you to let them do that will make their lives super awesome but that makes no difference for you, what&amp;rsquo;s your initial reaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At best, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably be nonplussed about the whole idea. Why should you bother putting the effort into changing this arrangement if it only benefits one person? There are surely other projects you could work on that would benefit everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At worst, you might be inclined to turn down the idea because it sounds awesome and you want it, but you can&amp;rsquo;t have it, so no one should have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you bring the idea to your boss, compare these two statements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 1: How Working Remotely Benefits You&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you let me work from home, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to spend more time with my family and friends, avoid the commute, and have fewer distractions when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get stuff done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 2: How Working Remotely Benefits Your Boss&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If I work from home, you&amp;rsquo;ll be saving the company over $10,000 each year, studies have shown a 13.5% boost in remote productivity over office-based productivity, and remote workers are also more likely to take ownership of their tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re the boss, which one sounds like a better call for the company?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because if you&amp;rsquo;re not the boss, you&amp;rsquo;re asking for exactly the same outcome with both statements; one just makes you sound selfish, and one makes you sound like a team player looking out for the company&amp;rsquo;s best interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-small-with-trial-runs:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee&#34;&gt;Start Small with Trial Runs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve never worked remotely before, it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to propose that you just&amp;hellip;don&amp;rsquo;t come in anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, propose something small, like one day per week to work remotely. It should go without saying that your teleworking day needs to be your most productive for the week to prove the point that this is better for everyone. (To give yourself a running start on your remote days, make sure you have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/effective-project-planning/&#34;&gt;clear plan&lt;/a&gt; for what you&amp;rsquo;re going to work on.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve established that you&amp;rsquo;re reliable as a remote worker, attempt to up the number of days out of the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to prove that you&amp;rsquo;re better when you&amp;rsquo;re not in the office, and that nothing went wrong without your physical presence. You can use the evidence to support your case to go fully remote — it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to make the case if you&amp;rsquo;ve got metrics, so use something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rescuetime.com/&#34;&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of how your time was spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-forgiveness-not-permission:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee&#34;&gt;Ask Forgiveness, Not Permission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your company isn&amp;rsquo;t receptive to a trial period, you can always adopt a different tactic and drag them, kicking and screaming, to victory.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee:faintofheart&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee:faintofheart&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Call in sick on a weekday — probably not a Monday or Friday so you don&amp;rsquo;t look like you&amp;rsquo;re trying to squeeze out a long weekend — and just work remotely. Get your tasks done, keep in touch with your team, and handle the day like you would if it was a normal, remote working day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a note of how much more productive the day was. If you can prove it, prove it. If not, make sure your boss is included on the task completion notices so they can see that you cranked things out from home — even while &amp;ldquo;sick&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dad used this technique to build up to the point where he was only coming into the office a couple times a month. After a while, he would take his phone as a mobile hotspot out on his boat and work while fishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His boss was none the wiser — after several months of working from his favorite fishing hole, his boss finally asked him to come into the office. &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of a lake right now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than getting in trouble for surreptitiously working from wherever he felt like for months, my dad was able to remove all ties from his office because they realized that, really, he&amp;rsquo;d already done it without their knowledge. They never had a clue because he never faltered in his productivity or responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-give-up:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Give Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re coming from a traditional 9-to-5 role, convincing your boss to let you leave the office is going to be an uphill battle in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just remember that big changes take time, and often times the resistance to an idea isn&amp;rsquo;t due to someone disagreeing with you; it&amp;rsquo;s just too new and uncomfortable, and they need some time to chew on it before they can consider it objectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To recap, when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to convince your boss to let you work remotely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have all your ducks in a row and be ready to overcome any logistical objections about your ability to get the job done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be ready to present research to back up all your claims that remote work is a win for the company as much as it is for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on the ways that remote work will benefit your boss; people are much more motivated by self-interest, and bosses want to look good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t go for full independence right out of the gate. Instead, start with trial runs to prove that you&amp;rsquo;re willing to work with your boss to prove this is good for everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t convince your boss, you can try to just do it anyways and ask for forgiveness instead of permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And, of course, if all else fails, you can look at other &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/how-to-become-location-independent/&#34;&gt;ways of becoming location independent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee:faintofheart&#34;&gt;This technique is not for the faint of heart. You need to be willing to 100% own this decision — if you falter, or seem anything less than unwaveringly convinced that you&amp;rsquo;re in the right, this technique could end up harming your career. Use at your own risk.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:44e33bcb7b5407046c6d7da22589ebee:faintofheart&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewarding Incompetence: How Time-Based Management Kills Motivation</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/results-based-work</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 00:50:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/results-based-work</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you&amp;rsquo;re given a task at your salaried job: you have to write a year-end summary of your department&amp;rsquo;s most valuable projects, which will be used to guide next year&amp;rsquo;s project selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get right to work and knock out the whole report in two days. Your boss is pleasantly surprised at your speed, but nothing can happen until a coworker finishes the report for his department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, there&amp;rsquo;s a box of invoices that need to be audited, and since you&amp;rsquo;re ahead of schedule can you take care of it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, your coworker takes a week and a half to finish the report. It&amp;rsquo;s mentioned that you finished faster, but that&amp;rsquo;s about the closest thing to a reprimand he&amp;rsquo;ll hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re clearly more productive, but your coworker is rewarded: he made &lt;em&gt;way more money&lt;/em&gt; for doing far less work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You were both paid for time, not output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-danger-of-butts-in-chairs:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;The Danger of Butts In Chairs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;rsquo;s hard to measure output, many companies have reverted to a much simpler, horribly inefficient approach to tracking an employee&amp;rsquo;s worth: butts in chairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rather than asking what someone produced, they ask how many hours he worked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it effective at telling who&amp;rsquo;s a good employee? No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it helpful in determining who the company&amp;rsquo;s stars are? Nope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it help motivated employees stay motivated? &lt;a href=&#34;http://discover.umn.edu/news/arts-humanities/flexible-schedules-and-results-oriented-work-environments-reduce-work-family&#34;&gt;Exactly the opposite&lt;/a&gt;, in fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; remove the need to do a little extra legwork for management, so — despite the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s arguably one of the absolute worst management metrics available — it still gets used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/results-based-work.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;results-based work is much more productive that time-based work&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You were both here for 8 hours, right? Why &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; you be paid the same?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/johnjoh/368511463&#34;&gt;John Joh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;time-based-management-means-rewarding-poor-performance:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Time-Based Management Means Rewarding Poor Performance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a culture where the only deliverable is time spent at the office, the business is actively encouraging employees to do less.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A project that should only take a day gets stretched out to two, because who cares? There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;nothing to be gained&lt;/em&gt; by working quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-frightening-economics-of-time-based-management:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;The Frightening Economics of Time-Based Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an employee, the economics look like this: that hypothetical report from the beginning of this post took you two days to finish, or 16 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say your salary is $50,000/year. That means that you get paid roughly $24/hour. So for finishing that report, you made about $385.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your coworker, who spent a week and a half (say 56 hours) doing the same project at the same salary was paid about $1,345 for the same job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, by working quickly, were punished for your efficiency. The message being sent is, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about how long it takes; you get paid the same salary whether it&amp;rsquo;s done today or done in a month.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-stop-rewarding-failure:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;How to Stop Rewarding Failure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve the problem where your less-efficient coworker gets rewarded, imagine a results-based office instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your boss assigns a project to you and your coworker and sets a due date of the following Monday, giving you six business days (48 hours) to complete the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on your salary, your boss has just valued this project at about $1,150.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s assume that you still get it done in 16 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the business is results-based, you are now free to do whatever you want until the following Monday, and you just made $71.88/hour for creating that report — &lt;strong&gt;your efficiency was just rewarded with a higher hourly rate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your coworker, on the other hand, manages to spend all of the allotted time plus a couple late nights working on the report, and still somehow manages to take 56 hours to create the report. He&amp;rsquo;s just lowered his hourly rate to $20.54.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is far more rewarding to efficient employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-rewarding-the-right-employees-helps-businesses:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;How Rewarding the Right Employees Helps Businesses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a business that implements a results-based environment, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gorowe.com/pages/about-rowe&#34;&gt;the rewards&lt;/a&gt; are also huge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;easily-spot-star-employees:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Easily Spot Star Employees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A results-based company needs to spot stars in the company — the people who seem to always get done ahead of schedule — and move them to more important, higher-value projects. When employees are measured by their results, this is extremely easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spotting and rewarding star employees creates an incentive for employees to work more efficiently,&lt;/strong&gt; which is good for morale, deadlines, and pretty much everything else businesses want to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;spot-problem-employees-quickly:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Spot Problem Employees Quickly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measuring results instead of time helps the company identify, coach, and — if necessary — weed out problem employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very difficult to just coast along in a company where you&amp;rsquo;re measured by results, so &lt;strong&gt;employees who don&amp;rsquo;t get much done are quickly identified by their low output.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;save-a-small-fortune-on-salaries:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Save a Small Fortune on Salaries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much of a company&amp;rsquo;s payroll goes toward funding Facebook and Reddit sessions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a company shifts to results-based systems, measuring output and whether an employee is earning their salary suddenly becomes not only possible, but easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of reviews relying on a manager&amp;rsquo;s memory and how many days an employee was absent, it&amp;rsquo;s suddenly possible to measure exact output:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pat was paid $50,000 for the year, and during that time turned in 35 projects that we valued at a total of $50,500 — clearly Pat&amp;rsquo;s salary was earned, and we could even consider a small raise.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Terry was paid $50,000 for the year, and during that time turned in 30 projects that we valued at a total of $43,300. We need to coach Terry and see a marked improvement or we&amp;rsquo;ll have to consider termination.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terry&amp;rsquo;s inefficiency may not have been caught without measuring results — a $6,700 oversight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-make-the-change:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;How to Make the Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re caught in a business that values time over results, or if you&amp;rsquo;re a manager or employer that&amp;rsquo;s fallen into the butts-in-chairs trap, there&amp;rsquo;s still hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will take an effort, but if &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/business/psychology_of_management/2014/05/best_buy_s_rowe_experiment_can_results_only_work_environments_actually_be.html&#34;&gt;industry giants&lt;/a&gt; can implement and benefit from it, so can you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-figuring-out-what-needs-to-be-done:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Start Figuring Out What Needs to Be Done&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find that you&amp;rsquo;re unable to clearly state what needs to be done in an organization, drop everything and start by defining what the result needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managers can&amp;rsquo;t expect anyone to be effective if there&amp;rsquo;s not a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/effective-project-planning/&#34;&gt;clear plan&lt;/a&gt; in place for what needs to be done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees can&amp;rsquo;t do good work if they&amp;rsquo;re not 100% clear on what &amp;ldquo;good work&amp;rdquo; means in the context of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you can measure results, you need to &lt;em&gt;define the results to be measured.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-a-case-to-the-boss:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Make a Case to the Boss&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not at the top of your organization, you&amp;rsquo;re at the mercy of higher-ups. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you&amp;rsquo;re helpless, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring up the detriments of butts-in-chairs to your boss. Talk about the benefits to everyone of results-based work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the people at the top are actually interested in making the company better, they&amp;rsquo;ll take what you have to say into consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be smart about it, though, because your boss won&amp;rsquo;t likely change everything just because you waved this article in her face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, make a small suggestion: &lt;strong&gt;as an experiment, your team could try a results-based arrangement and report back after 3–6 months with findings.&lt;/strong&gt; Figure out a way to measure results that will get management excited, and put a plan in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your team has demonstrated that results-based management gets results, your boss will take ownership of the idea and run it up the ladder, hopefully creating a ripple effect that helps move the whole company to a better arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, your team will likely be allowed to keep up the same arrangement — after all, you &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;vote-with-your-feet:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Vote with Your Feet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your organization doesn&amp;rsquo;t respond and insists that your only value to the company is your butt in a chair for 8+ hours a day, then &lt;strong&gt;it may be time to look at other options.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are results-based employment options ranging from the obvious (software and copywriting) to the entry-level (customer support) to the unbelievable (accounting firms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s stressful to hunt for a new job, but there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://weworkremotely.com/&#34;&gt;lots&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flexjobs.com/jobs&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jobs.remotive.io/&#34;&gt;options&lt;/a&gt; for finding remote work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t change your culture, &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself be the one who&amp;rsquo;s punished for someone else&amp;rsquo;s incompetence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>