<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sales on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/sales/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sales on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 09:07:22 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/sales/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Sell Without Selling</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-sell-without-selling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 09:07:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-sell-without-selling/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Marisa is a few months into her new career as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://marisamorby.com&#34;&gt;freelance copywriter and editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has a literature degree&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:degree&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:degree&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and hundreds of thousands of words under her belt. She&amp;rsquo;s written for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themuse.com/author/marisa-morby&#34;&gt;large&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lifehack.org/author/marisa-morby&#34;&gt;publications&lt;/a&gt;. She&amp;rsquo;s created an &lt;a href=&#34;http://creatingtheconversation.com/hire-probability-not-potential/&#34;&gt;information product&lt;/a&gt; and the marketing to go with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m telling you this to establish a fact: Marisa is extremely well-qualified to work as a copywriter. Anyone who hires her will be very happy with the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But despite all her qualifications, her freelance career was slow out of the gate. The skill was there, but the clients weren&amp;rsquo;t piling up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;100-of-becoming-a-freelancer-is-sales:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;100% of Becoming a Freelancer Is Sales&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spend more than a few minutes skimming &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/freelance/&#34;&gt;the freelance Subreddit&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely see at least a half-dozen posts from freelancers who are struggling and unhappy because they don&amp;rsquo;t have steady work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all qualified people&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:reddit&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:reddit&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; who could easily handle freelance contracts. And yet they&amp;rsquo;re stuck without work, or forced to race to the bottom on sites like Upwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these people aren&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;freelancers&lt;/em&gt; — they&amp;rsquo;re employees without bosses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freelancers are — first and foremost — salespeople.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-can-only-get-hired-if-someone-knows-you-exist:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;You Can Only Get Hired If Someone Knows You Exist&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/i-exist.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;I exist!&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Does anyone know you&#39;re here?

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trustcollective.com/portfolio/content/bent_drpepper.htm&#34;&gt;Bent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth about freelancing is that getting hired as a freelancer has exactly &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with your abilities as a freelancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an analogy to try and put this in perspective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say I need a deck built. I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything resembling construction or woodworking since I made a lopsided toothpick box in seventh grade shop class, so I&amp;rsquo;m walking in pretty blind here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start by asking people I trust: my dad, who&amp;rsquo;s had things built before; my friends who own houses; a buddy who used to work construction. Do they know anyone I could ask about building the deck?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After people I trust, I might put the word out through whatever channels are available to me. A call for help on Facebook or Twitter. Maybe someone knows someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I consult the internet at large. Are there any reviews? Who&amp;rsquo;s the best deck-builder in my city?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a list. Or, more than likely, one of my trusted sources will have a recommendation, and I&amp;rsquo;ll just go with that unquestioningly — why doubt the endorsement of someone I trust?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am, a deck contract awarded, and I know nothing about my contractor except that my friend Troy likes him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A freelancer&amp;rsquo;s skills mean jack shit in the decision-making process for most clients.&lt;/strong&gt; You know that cheesy cliché, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you know; it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; you know&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a cliché for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;100-of-building-client-relationships-is-skill:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;100% of Building Client Relationships Is Skill&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But wait,&amp;rdquo; you say, &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s so much more to freelancing than sales!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course. But none of that matters if you&amp;rsquo;re not selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where sales stop mattering is &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the sale is made. &lt;strong&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve won a client, gotten a deposit, and started a project, your sales ability can&amp;rsquo;t help you anymore — you&amp;rsquo;re on the hook to be good at your job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your talent as a freelancer will make clients happy, and it will keep them coming back. Plus, it creates referrals — which we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to in a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;selling-feels-gross:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Selling Feels Gross&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look: I hate selling. &lt;em&gt;Hate it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accosting a friend or stranger and asking for money feels presumptuous, invasive, and greasy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/used-car-salesman.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;used car salesman&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Selling shouldn&#39;t make you feel like this guy.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/pictures/efik45ejedd/pay-attention/&#34;&gt;Forbes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never made a cold call in my life.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:coldcalls&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:coldcalls&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve sent fewer than a dozen unsolicited emails asking for business. I get anxiety thinking about approaching someone who has no idea who I am and trying to convince them I&amp;rsquo;m worth money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power dynamics are weird; the approach puts me at a social disadvantage, and forces me to work extra hard to prove I know something. I would never buy something from a stranger I&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of before; why would I expect anyone to buy from me when I&amp;rsquo;m a stranger?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-still-have-to-own-your-position:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;You Still Have to Own Your Position&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t like approaching someone cold, but I have no issue whatsoever telling someone what I do — what I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s critical to fully own your ability to do the job you&amp;rsquo;re telling people you can do.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don&amp;rsquo;t trust yourself to be outstanding at your job, why should anyone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I started freelancing full time, I waffled on what I was. Was I a guy who worked at Kinko&amp;rsquo;s and made the odd website on the side? Or was I a web designer working to bootstrap a new freelance business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt like an impostor telling people I was a web designer. They&amp;rsquo;d think I was a liar if they walked into Kinko&amp;rsquo;s and saw me there, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not a healthy way to look at things. When I was younger, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t an issue for me: sure, I worked at Pizza Hut part-time, but I was a &lt;em&gt;musician&lt;/em&gt; first and foremost. My band didn&amp;rsquo;t make much money, but we practiced a few times a week and played a show every month or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, it was much easier to tell people I was a musician than to tell them I was a web designer.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:roles&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:roles&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was easier to call myself a musician because I had a group of friends to be part of my band, and as a freelancer I was just a guy working alone on my couch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was because being a freelancer seemed more important, and I was more afraid of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever it was, something made me uncomfortable about saying the phrase, &amp;ldquo;I am a freelance web designer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;confidence-is-critical:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Confidence Is Critical&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally quit my job at Kinko&amp;rsquo;s to become a full-time freelancer, my confidence instantly shot through the roof. I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire/&#34;&gt;set myself on fire&lt;/a&gt;, and it was time to put up or shut up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/i-am-really-good-at-this.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;I am really good at this. Self-confidence, freelance, sales.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  You have to believe in yourself, or no one else will.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As soon as I felt like a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; web designer, I immediately started landing more business.&lt;/strong&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t think this was a coincidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a chicken-egg problem: in order to have confidence about our abilities, we feel like we need clients; but in order to get clients, we need to have confidence in our abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t trying to sell people my services, mind you. I simply felt more confident saying, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a web designer, and I can build awesome websites.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People sensed my confidence, and suddenly I was being approached more often about jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/use-your-network.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Freelancers who hate selling need to use their network.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-sell-without-selling:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;How to Sell Without Selling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidence doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve all problems, though. I was getting approached for jobs, but that was because people knew who I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I didn&amp;rsquo;t like selling and wasn&amp;rsquo;t cold-calling people, how did anyone know who I was?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, there are two ways to get new business as a freelancer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sell your services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have other people sell your services for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that comfortable with option 1, so I wanted to find a way to make option 2 happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I needed to create a killer referral network.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-s-still-some-selling-involved:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s Still Some Selling Involved&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let me mislead you into thinking you won&amp;rsquo;t have to do any selling — that&amp;rsquo;s, unfortunately, just not true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll have to sell. But you can do a different, more comfortable kind of selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instead of selling to strangers, start selling to your network.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/use-your-network-whisper.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;freelancers use their network to build referrals&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Never underestimate the power of word-of-mouth.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-advantage-of-your-network:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Take Advantage of Your Network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most people, there&amp;rsquo;s a loose network of acquaintances and &amp;ldquo;buddies&amp;rdquo; spread through the community, state, country, and/or world. Not necessarily people that you keep in touch with daily, but the kind of people you speak to every month or two — just to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;be-willing-to-ask-for-help:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Be Willing to Ask for Help&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you talk to these folks, they&amp;rsquo;ll inevitably ask you, &amp;ldquo;So what&amp;rsquo;s new?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, the default answer might be to say, &amp;ldquo;Not much. I&amp;rsquo;m working as a freelancer now, which is pretty exciting. How are you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is factual, &lt;em&gt;but it could be much better.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, look: we&amp;rsquo;re not trying to scam our friends into anything. But we &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want to make sure our friends are aware of what we&amp;rsquo;re doing, and that they could help us do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when our friend asks, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s new?&amp;rdquo; we don&amp;rsquo;t brush the question off. Instead, we present a friendly, opt-in request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, my biggest news is that I&amp;rsquo;ve just start working as a freelance web designer, which is pretty exciting. The biggest challenge so far is finding clients, so if you know anyone who needs a website, I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate it if you&amp;rsquo;d drop my name or make an intro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You haven&amp;rsquo;t asked for anything that puts your friend out. All you&amp;rsquo;re doing is putting it in her head that she can help you out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the deck analogy from earlier? People love to have the answers to other people&amp;rsquo;s problems. &lt;strong&gt;If my friend can connect me to someone who needs my services, she wins twice:&lt;/strong&gt; she helped me grow my business, and helped her other friend solve their website problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-don-t-have-to-wait-for-an-opening:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;You Don&amp;rsquo;t Have to Wait for an Opening&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also start this conversation. Email your acquaintances to catch them up on things, including a nudge to send any potential leads your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That email is almost the same. It might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, friend–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you&amp;rsquo;re doing well! I wanted to drop you a line to see how things are going and catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Talk about things that are relevant: do they have kids? were they starting something new last time you spoke?]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things on my end are pretty exciting right now. My biggest news is that I&amp;rsquo;ve just start working as a freelance web designer. The biggest challenge so far is finding clients, so if you know anyone who needs a website, I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate it if you&amp;rsquo;d drop my name or make an intro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Catch them up on anything else in your life that you want to share here.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I hope you&amp;rsquo;re having an awesome summer. I&amp;rsquo;ll look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This message isn&amp;rsquo;t hiding an agenda. You&amp;rsquo;re not trying to weasel something out of a friend. You&amp;rsquo;re simply sharing big life news and making it known that — if they happen to hear someone needs a website — they can help you out by spreading the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you sent this message without the note about referring leads, it would still be a meaningful message to you and your friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remember-these-are-your-friends:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Remember: These Are Your Friends&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/dont-be-a-dick.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;How not to be a dick.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dontbeadickday.com&#34;&gt;Wil Wheaton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big goal, of course, is not to be a dick about this. You are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; going to get good results by pestering everyone you know about buying a website to &amp;ldquo;help you out&amp;rdquo; or whatever. That&amp;rsquo;s multi-level marketing — are you a freelancer, or are you hawking Scentsy candles?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you send an email, make sure you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be upset if you received the same email from your friend.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to be made aware that someone is looking for work; it&amp;rsquo;s another thing entirely to be pumped for leads and/or pressured into buying things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll be fine if you just follow Wheaton&amp;rsquo;s Law: &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t be a dick.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grow-your-network:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Grow Your Network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to your existing network, make an effort to meet people — especially people who are in the industries you&amp;rsquo;d like to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has the added benefit of building a community. You can help people in whatever way you&amp;rsquo;re able, and they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to reciprocate as best as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;attend-local-meetups-and-professional-groups:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Attend Local Meetups and Professional Groups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-community.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;freelancers build local community&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  In Missoula, running a small workshop in 2010.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started out, I started attending a small group called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Montana-Programmers/&#34;&gt;MT Programmers&lt;/a&gt; in Missoula. &lt;strong&gt;I started to get involved, and through the people I met there, I was introduced to more and more people in the community&lt;/strong&gt; — more than a few of my first gigs came from these introductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, I spent money to attend conferences, and &lt;strong&gt;I found myself surrounded by people who were focusing on their businesses and willing to spend money to get what they needed&lt;/strong&gt; — often, this meant they needed website help, so it naturally came up in conversation that we could help each other out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bring-your-clients-into-your-network:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Bring Your Clients into Your Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I get a new project, I bust my ass to make sure the client is really happy with me. I know that &lt;strong&gt;happy clients are worth &lt;em&gt;way more&lt;/em&gt; than just the value of a given project.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my clients became life-long friends. I&amp;rsquo;ve been invited to book launch parties, weddings, vacations, and more. This could never have happened if I didn&amp;rsquo;t show that I&amp;rsquo;m a stand-up guy through my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a financial perspective, lots of my clients came back later with additional projects. Far more of them referred friends and colleagues to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ask-clients-for-referrals:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Ask Clients for Referrals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my wrapping-up process with clients is to send an email letting them know that I don&amp;rsquo;t advertise, and the only way I get new clients is by word-of-mouth from my existing clients. I ask them — if they feel like I did a good job and they&amp;rsquo;re happy with my work — to please keep me in mind if they meet someone else who needs a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also offer a referral bonus as a token of my appreciation. It&amp;rsquo;s not much — $100 for any referral who signs on with me — but I like to send it over as a token of my appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make sure to send a personal note thanking the person for each referral as well, except in the case of my highest-referring clients — they send too many leads, so I&amp;rsquo;d be spamming them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;eventually-you-can-stop-selling:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Eventually You Can Stop Selling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple years, &lt;strong&gt;I had a large enough network that my referral stream was too much for me to handle.&lt;/strong&gt; I received several inquiries a week from people who were serious about web projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was swamped. I had to hire subcontractors to help. I had a waiting list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;strong&gt;this meant I never had to go out and &amp;ldquo;do sales&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; the way that freelancers typically view sales. No cold calls or emails, no advertising, no proposals. Just a steady stream of referrals — which is a different (far less awkward) type of selling.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:dating&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:dating&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;freelancing-is-for-conversationalists:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;Freelancing Is for Conversationalists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s direct sales or leveraging a network for introductions, &lt;strong&gt;your job as a freelancer is to generate conversations with people who may need your services.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that your ability to speak in a clear and friendly manner is perhaps your most valuable skill. If you sound confident, and you don&amp;rsquo;t seem like a dick, chances are you&amp;rsquo;ll get the job over someone who seems unsure or comes off as abrasive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As unfair as it may seem, a freelancer with better conversational skills will likely win a job over a more competent freelancer who speaks poorly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-can-be-successful-without-selling:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8&#34;&gt;You Can Be Successful Without Selling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a slower road than hard selling, but you can successfully build a freelance career only by networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let your friends know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them to refer anyone who might need your services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go out and meet people — especially if they&amp;rsquo;re in your target demographic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be helpful and confident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kick ass for your clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them for referrals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a referral network after my first project, and it grew steadily with each new project I took on. It seemed to me that most projects would lead to one referral, and every once in a while a project would lead to a huge number of referrals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you hate sales, don&amp;rsquo;t worry — you can still be a freelancer. You may need to hold onto your day job a bit longer, but you can get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just stay confident, ask for leads, and remember that your skills finish the job and earn new referrals — so do good work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:degree&#34;&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t actually remember &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what her degree is. It&amp;rsquo;s something to do with English, writing, and/or literature. Whatever it is, it&amp;rsquo;s very relevant to writing professionally.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:degree&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:reddit&#34;&gt;Correction: 61% of Reddit users are actually &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squirreltruth.com/facts&#34;&gt;seven squirrels in a human suit&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:reddit&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:coldcalls&#34;&gt;These work. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; make cold calls. I just never liked the idea of becoming a telemarketer for my own services, so I worked around the problem.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:coldcalls&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:roles&#34;&gt;This was especially odd given that I was always a mediocre musician at best, but web design came to me pretty naturally. Comparatively, my design skill set was stronger than my musical skill set almost immediately.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:roles&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:dating&#34;&gt;I think of it like dating, because to me it&amp;rsquo;s kind of the same thing. I have &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; had success approaching a stranger and wooing her. However, if I get introduced by a mutual friend, I feel far less awkward and there&amp;rsquo;s a much higher chance that we&amp;rsquo;ll hit it off.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I think this happens because the introduction creates a reason for me to be there. My friend has vouched for me, and this means the conversation starts on level ground — I don&amp;rsquo;t have to prove I deserve to be there, and the conversation can progress naturally.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5a60a7c2d0a1ec88cefdcd1d049c39b8:dating&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>