<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regret on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/regret/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Regret on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 15:17:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/regret/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Take the Trip</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/take-the-trip</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 15:17:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/take-the-trip</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You should come, too!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to brush an invite off as an empty courtesy, or to decline for any number of arguably legitimate reasons. &lt;em&gt;It feels safe to turn down an invitation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what are we missing out on by being safe?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wanna-hang-out-in-the-forest-with-a-bunch-of-sweaty-nerds:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;Wanna Hang Out in the Forest with a Bunch of Sweaty Nerds?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago, I found myself in Nashville, TN as part of a trip to Kentucky and Tennessee that I&amp;rsquo;d planned with &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/best-friends/&#34;&gt;my friend Nate&lt;/a&gt;. While we were there, Nate called his friend Steve Kamb, the creator of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nerdfitness.com/&#34;&gt;Nerd Fitness&lt;/a&gt;, and we all met up for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point during the conversation, Steve started talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://camp.nerdfitness.com/&#34;&gt;Camp Nerd Fitness&lt;/a&gt; — a weekend out in a remote area of Georgia with a bunch of healthy-minded nerds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wrapped up his description of the event with, &amp;ldquo;You should come!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was September 5. Camp Nerd Fitness started September 18. As far as notice goes, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get much shorter than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate already had travel planned, so he couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it. But I had no plans at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immediate impulse was to decline. &lt;em&gt;Two weeks isn&amp;rsquo;t enough time. I&amp;rsquo;m traveling right now; it would be insane to take another trip so soon. I have too much going on at work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-take-the-trip:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;Just Take the Trip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best pieces of advice I&amp;rsquo;ve ever received was from &lt;a href=&#34;http://barefootfts.com/instructors/craig-weller&#34;&gt;Craig Weller&lt;/a&gt;; we were discussing travel and happiness one evening, and he told me, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just take the trip.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way Craig sees things, if there&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity to do something, and that opportunity doesn&amp;rsquo;t create &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; problems,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:actual-problems&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:actual-problems&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; he will absolutely take the trip. No questions asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, Craig has been all over the world in circumstances ranging from a comfortable family-style getaway in Italy to living with a monkey in a tent in Africa. His stories are incredible, and &lt;strong&gt;none of them would have happened if &amp;ldquo;too busy&amp;rdquo; was an excuse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-really-at-stake-here:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Really at Stake, Here?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking a little harder about Steve&amp;rsquo;s offer, I realized I wasn&amp;rsquo;t risking anything if I chose to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had plenty of airline miles; I could book the plane ticket without spending any money. I was mostly caught up on projects, and two weeks is a good amount of time to crank on things and get a bit ahead to cover the day and a half I&amp;rsquo;d miss for the camp. Steve seemed like a really smart guy — someone who could bring a lot to the table both as a friend and as a business contact.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:call-me&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:call-me&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My first reaction was to think of everything that might go wrong if I took the trip; what I needed to consider was all of the opportunities I&amp;rsquo;d miss by staying home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-ll-only-regret-the-trips-you-don-t-take:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll Only Regret the Trips You Don&amp;rsquo;t Take&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be tempting to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/fear/&#34;&gt;let fear hold you back&lt;/a&gt;, but — when I really think about it — I only regret the trips I &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a chance to see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=14tBBSFF90c&#34;&gt;George Carlin&lt;/a&gt; in 2007, but I decided I was too busy to go. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll wait until his next tour,&amp;rdquo; I said. Now I&amp;rsquo;ll never get the chance&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:george-carlin&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:george-carlin&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to see one of the greatest comedians of all time, all because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/better-productivity-work-less/&#34;&gt;take a break&lt;/a&gt; to go see a show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t recall a single trip I&amp;rsquo;ve taken that I actually regret. I can think of things I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do again, but &lt;strong&gt;the experience and lessons I took away from the &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; trips were worth taking the trip.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-in:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;Are You In?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A day or so after we got home from Kentucky, Nate connected Steve and I via email, and Steve sent the question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still had reservations, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of any &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; excuses. &lt;strong&gt;I took the trip.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/1514573_10152988144498488_2980244324311718297_n.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Camp Nerd Fitness&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.willbyington.com/&#34;&gt;Will Byington&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the last weekend playing ultimate frisbee, reliving my mid-20s in an informal powerlifting competition,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:powerlifter&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:powerlifter&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and not understanding all the comic book, anime, and video game references that were being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I decided to take the trip, I met a whole new group of people I never knew existed, made some new friends, learned some new tricks,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:new-tricks&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:new-tricks&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and had a really unique experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And — perhaps more importantly — because I took this trip, &lt;em&gt;nothing went wrong in my life personally or professionally.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-ready-to-take-the-trip:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;Are You Ready to Take the Trip?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What trips have you taken, even when you felt nervous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What trips have you turned down for artificial reasons?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Of the two, which do you feel better about?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:actual-problems&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;actual&amp;rdquo; is paramount, here. &amp;ldquo;Too busy&amp;rdquo; is not an actual problem. &amp;ldquo;Too short of notice&amp;rdquo; is not an actual problem. They&amp;rsquo;re inconveniences. An &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; problem is something like, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m in my friend&amp;rsquo;s wedding that weekend,&amp;rdquo; or, &amp;ldquo;My parents are in town that day.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:actual-problems&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:call-me&#34;&gt;Steve, have your people call my people. We&amp;rsquo;ll do lunch. I&amp;rsquo;ll fax you the details.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:call-me&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:george-carlin&#34;&gt;George Carlin passed away in June of 2008.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:george-carlin&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:powerlifter&#34;&gt;And then, as I hobbled around on my aching joints, remembered why I stopped training like a powerlifter.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:powerlifter&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:new-tricks&#34;&gt;Parkour! Handstands!
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:new-tricks&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Montana</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 17:46:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Years back, before I moved to Portland, I used to haunt a bar called Al&amp;rsquo;s and Vic&amp;rsquo;s in Missoula, Montana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of those dives where it was too loud to hear yourself think and the floor was &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; sticky, but they sold a bucket of PBR for four dollars, and a Montana Happy Meal&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a night where I&amp;rsquo;d been called in as wingman for Scott, we met with his date and — for the span of a beer — I did my best not to make him sound like a degenerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His date, whose name I don&amp;rsquo;t remember but whose face looked like a Bernadette, told us her friends were arriving and would we mind standing at the bar with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette introduced us to her friends, Mandy and Kate. Mandy, it turns out, was a friend of Scott&amp;rsquo;s, and the two of them pulled Bernadette into conversation, leaving Kate and I to fend for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate was beautiful. Like, &lt;em&gt;holy shit&lt;/em&gt; good-looking — the kind of attractive that usually requires about a grand&amp;rsquo;s worth of Photoshop cleanup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, on the other hand, was wearing a cowboy shirt with pearl snaps, sporting an extra twenty pounds or so, and unshaven in the not-sexy way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, despite my homeless desperado ensemble, we hit it off immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was funny, sharp-witted. I was scrambling to keep up, but she was laughing. The hoarse mating calls of a hundred college kids were muffled under the sound of her voice, like bourbon over fine-grit sandpaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The faces around us blurred and faded; it was just me and Kate and my beer and her whisky diet and this moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain was leaking that special cocktail of chemicals that only happens the first time you make a connection with someone. In that moment I understood how people can meet and fall in love and end up making long-term promises to each other in front of an Elvis impersonator — all in the span of one intense night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spark between us had magnetized the air; my heart was trying to pull out of my chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette reappeared over Kate&amp;rsquo;s shoulder, and the room snapped back into focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandy was with her, and Scott returned a moment later with a fresh bucket of beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott gave me a &lt;em&gt;how&amp;rsquo;d it go for you&lt;/em&gt; look. I tried not to look upset about the interruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls did their secret eye contact telepathy thing, and Bernadette started preparing her exit. Mandy and Kate took her cue and started gathering their purses and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate caught my eye as she swung her coat around her shoulders, and my heart went all squishy and weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I formed the words in my brain — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number&lt;/em&gt; — opened my mouth to speak — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number, you idiot!&lt;/em&gt; — and I said, &amp;ldquo;It was really nice meeting you. Have a great night.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She might have hesitated. I was too disgusted with myself to notice. The next thing I knew I was watching her hair bounce in the red bar-glow as she walked away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of running after her, telling her I couldn&amp;rsquo;t let her get away without knowing I could see her again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s romantic? Probably creepy. Better not.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of asking Scott for Bernadette&amp;rsquo;s number so I could call her and ask for Kate&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s even worse. Stop it. All of your ideas are bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did nothing. I watched the door close behind her. My mouth was probably hanging open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Scotty — never one to pass up a kidney punch — said, &amp;ldquo;Blew that one, huh?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the beer he offered and did a poor job of acting nonchalant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You know who she is, right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shook my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a special kind of schadenfreude that only men experience. It occurs when we watch a friend — hitting it off with a woman who is clearly out of his league — suddenly and spectacularly self-destruct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a teeball benchwarmer. Kate was one good season away from the big show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scotty was so darkly gleeful he should have been stroking a Persian cat as he said, &amp;ldquo;She was Miss Montana last year.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goddammit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot with Miss Montana, and I let her walk out of the bar. After fifteen minutes of great conversation and good chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replayed the moments before she left in my head. I met her eyes. &lt;em&gt;She was waiting for you to ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot. I did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-wasted-second-chance:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;The (Wasted) Second Chance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks later, I was out with Scotty again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was late, and we had slunk into the bar everyone despised. The sign on the door said &amp;ldquo;Bodega&amp;rdquo;, but it may has well have been called You&amp;rsquo;re Hammered Again &amp;amp; None of the Girls Will Talk to You, Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out front, I bummed a cigarette off a stranger and wobbled gently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jason?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wheeled and found myself facing Kate. I immediately stamped out my cigarette. I could feel the air starting to magnetize again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate smiled. And then she hugged me. Her hair smelled like vanilla-scented heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smelled like an ashtray full of whiskey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So how are you?&amp;rdquo; I managed to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Great! Oh, by the way, these are my brothers, Jeff and Mark,&amp;rdquo; she said, motioning to the two frighteningly large men who flanked her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded. They nodded back, then pretended not to pay attention while this drunken asshole in front of The Saddest Bar in Missoula tried to flirt with their sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow we just fell back into it. She teased me about my smoking, I poked fun at the shoes she was carrying, and we both laughed. My heart did the squishy-weird thing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it was time to make the move. Her brothers weren&amp;rsquo;t going to stand there all night, and I needed to head back inside before Scott ordered me any more drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried scraping every last bit of courage off the walls of my rib cage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just ask. Ask for her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to think of a line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a line, dickhead: &amp;ldquo;Can I get your number and call you sometime?&amp;rdquo; Just. Ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I caught eyes with the larger of her two brothers. And then I wondered if I&amp;rsquo;d misread the whole situation and she was just being nice to me. And then I froze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, hey, it was great seeing you again. I should probably get back inside.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idiot. Idiot. Idiot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flushed. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even make eye contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As suddenly as she&amp;rsquo;d appeared, Kate — Miss Montana — the gorgeous, funny girl I love-at-first-sighted (twice) was gone into the night. For good this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lost-in-the-woulds:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;Lost in the Woulds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would have been a great couple. She would have had a secret family recipe for waffles and a mean Scrabble game. Maybe her disturbingly attractive genes would compensate for my hairiness and we&amp;rsquo;d make the world&amp;rsquo;s hottest babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She would have shot me down. We&amp;rsquo;d have only had another thirty seconds of good conversation left in us. She would have had a boyfriend. I would have hated her guts after two weeks of hanging out. Or, more likely, she&amp;rsquo;d have hated mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand wonderful memories, starting with the one where I asked if I could call and she said yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand mistakes and alienated myself from the Montana Beautiful Women&amp;rsquo;s Club&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any of those outcomes would have been fine. Even bad experiences are still &lt;em&gt;experiences&lt;/em&gt;, you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;em&gt;wondering!&lt;/em&gt; The wondering is murder. There&amp;rsquo;s no lesson to learn in &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s just the nagging of an unanswered question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, I&amp;rsquo;m not the guy who took a long shot with a beauty queen and succeeded against the odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also not the guy who took a shot and missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just a guy who had a shot and stood there looking foolish while the clock ran out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;A shot of Jameson with a PBR back.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;Totally a thing.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>