<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motivation on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/category/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motivation on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 01:01:08 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/category/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Have It All: Living for Now AND Later</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 01:01:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of guilt packed into our culture. We hear phrases like &amp;ldquo;hard work and sacrifice&amp;rdquo; tossed around to describe virtuous lifestyles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re trained to feel ashamed of having a good time.&lt;/strong&gt; We can only allowed to enjoy ourselves for an allotted number of vacation days — any further enjoyment is a sure sign that you don&amp;rsquo;t give a fuck about The Future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, would you like to come on this trip to Costa Rica with us?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, I can&amp;rsquo;t. I have The Future to consider, you know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what good is that sacrifice, really? &lt;strong&gt;Does the decision to suffer today for the sake of The Future actually result in a better future?&lt;/strong&gt; Or are we just depriving ourselves because we&amp;rsquo;ve been told it&amp;rsquo;s the right thing to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sacrifices-make-sense-sometimes:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Sacrifices Make Sense — Sometimes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly some sacrifice is a good thing. But how do we tell the difference between a sacrifice that will benefit us and a sacrifice that just makes us miserable for no reason?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ramen.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;ramen&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  #thestruggleisreal

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was building my business, I took a contract that barely covered my living expenses, quit my day job, and bought a pallet of ramen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the decision to sacrifice my short-term comfort for the potential to significantly improve my life in the long run. &lt;strong&gt;I felt comfortable making this sacrifice because there was a concrete goal, a timeline, and a measurable outcome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be self-employed (concrete goal). I had three months (timeline) on the contract to either make a livable wage (measurable outcome) — or decide I would be better off hunting for a new employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By making this sacrifice, I was able to make the jump from moonlighting as a web designer to working as a full-time freelancer — and this has paid me back many times over since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;base-decisions-on-tangible-criteria:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Base Decisions on Tangible Criteria&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should all be aware of what our later years will hold. But we &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; be blindly denying ourselves enjoyment today for the sake of The Future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid making unnecessary sacrifices for The Future — and to avoid making decisions that could negatively affect our &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; future — &lt;strong&gt;we need to define what The Future actually looks like.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a standard of living, an &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/calculator/retirement/retirement-need/&#34;&gt;exact dollar amount&lt;/a&gt;, or whatever you decide your future will require — it just needs to be concrete. Make sure it&amp;rsquo;s not, &amp;ldquo;I want to be able to live comfortably.&amp;rdquo; What does &amp;ldquo;comfortably&amp;rdquo; mean?&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you defined your future as requiring, say, $60,000/year for retirement, and you want to retire at 67, then you&amp;rsquo;d need to put a plan in place to save at least $1.5M between now and your 67th birthday.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By creating a plan, you now have a concrete goal with a timeline and a measurable outcome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-whatever-doesn-t-interfere-with-the-plan:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Do Whatever Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Interfere with the Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a real plan, anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect it is fair game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to go on a trip, see a concert, or blow off work for the afternoon to visit your friends? Do it, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s not to the detriment of your plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we have a clear plan, the guilt and uncertainty associated with The Future goes away. We can now test the things we want now against the things we want later — and I think we&amp;rsquo;ll all be shocked by how rarely the two are opposed to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/crippling-fear-of-uncertainty.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Sorry I couldn&amp;#39;t come with you, but I have my crippling fear of uncertainty to consider, you know.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This is what we&#39;re saying when we turn down the things we want &#34;for The Future&#34;.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keep-the-future-in-context:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3&#34;&gt;Keep the Future in Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Without context, The Future is just a foggy, looming uncertainty.&lt;/strong&gt; It has nothing to do with our comfort or wealth in years to come — it&amp;rsquo;s just a nagging fear that we don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s next, so maybe we should hedge our bets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d be better off calling it The Crippling Fear of Uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, would you like to come on this trip to Costa Rica with us?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, I can&amp;rsquo;t. I have my Crippling Fear of Uncertainty to consider, you know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living the lives we want to live today is certainly a threat to The Future. But &lt;strong&gt;to a well-considered plan for the future, our happiness is no threat at all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have to ask ourselves: are we holding back because this sacrifice will have a measurable impact on our plans for the future? Or are we just scared of The Future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;For me, that might mean a house made out of hammocks where I&amp;rsquo;ll be fed various morsels of imported cheese by an extremely well-trained octopus. Your &amp;ldquo;comfortable&amp;rdquo; living situation may vary.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:comfort&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;This is an incredibly simplified approach to saving money for retirement, and it&amp;rsquo;s most likely wrong. Please do research and talk to a professional about your own retirement plans.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:c7049dd36461b22b443c08769e7223e3:simplified&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewarding Incompetence: How Time-Based Management Kills Motivation</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/results-based-work</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 00:50:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/results-based-work</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you&amp;rsquo;re given a task at your salaried job: you have to write a year-end summary of your department&amp;rsquo;s most valuable projects, which will be used to guide next year&amp;rsquo;s project selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get right to work and knock out the whole report in two days. Your boss is pleasantly surprised at your speed, but nothing can happen until a coworker finishes the report for his department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, there&amp;rsquo;s a box of invoices that need to be audited, and since you&amp;rsquo;re ahead of schedule can you take care of it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, your coworker takes a week and a half to finish the report. It&amp;rsquo;s mentioned that you finished faster, but that&amp;rsquo;s about the closest thing to a reprimand he&amp;rsquo;ll hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re clearly more productive, but your coworker is rewarded: he made &lt;em&gt;way more money&lt;/em&gt; for doing far less work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You were both paid for time, not output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-danger-of-butts-in-chairs:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;The Danger of Butts In Chairs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;rsquo;s hard to measure output, many companies have reverted to a much simpler, horribly inefficient approach to tracking an employee&amp;rsquo;s worth: butts in chairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rather than asking what someone produced, they ask how many hours he worked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it effective at telling who&amp;rsquo;s a good employee? No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it helpful in determining who the company&amp;rsquo;s stars are? Nope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it help motivated employees stay motivated? &lt;a href=&#34;http://discover.umn.edu/news/arts-humanities/flexible-schedules-and-results-oriented-work-environments-reduce-work-family&#34;&gt;Exactly the opposite&lt;/a&gt;, in fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; remove the need to do a little extra legwork for management, so — despite the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s arguably one of the absolute worst management metrics available — it still gets used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/results-based-work.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;results-based work is much more productive that time-based work&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You were both here for 8 hours, right? Why &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; you be paid the same?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/johnjoh/368511463&#34;&gt;John Joh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;time-based-management-means-rewarding-poor-performance:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Time-Based Management Means Rewarding Poor Performance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a culture where the only deliverable is time spent at the office, the business is actively encouraging employees to do less.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A project that should only take a day gets stretched out to two, because who cares? There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;nothing to be gained&lt;/em&gt; by working quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-frightening-economics-of-time-based-management:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;The Frightening Economics of Time-Based Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an employee, the economics look like this: that hypothetical report from the beginning of this post took you two days to finish, or 16 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say your salary is $50,000/year. That means that you get paid roughly $24/hour. So for finishing that report, you made about $385.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your coworker, who spent a week and a half (say 56 hours) doing the same project at the same salary was paid about $1,345 for the same job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, by working quickly, were punished for your efficiency. The message being sent is, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about how long it takes; you get paid the same salary whether it&amp;rsquo;s done today or done in a month.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-stop-rewarding-failure:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;How to Stop Rewarding Failure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve the problem where your less-efficient coworker gets rewarded, imagine a results-based office instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your boss assigns a project to you and your coworker and sets a due date of the following Monday, giving you six business days (48 hours) to complete the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on your salary, your boss has just valued this project at about $1,150.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s assume that you still get it done in 16 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the business is results-based, you are now free to do whatever you want until the following Monday, and you just made $71.88/hour for creating that report — &lt;strong&gt;your efficiency was just rewarded with a higher hourly rate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your coworker, on the other hand, manages to spend all of the allotted time plus a couple late nights working on the report, and still somehow manages to take 56 hours to create the report. He&amp;rsquo;s just lowered his hourly rate to $20.54.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is far more rewarding to efficient employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-rewarding-the-right-employees-helps-businesses:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;How Rewarding the Right Employees Helps Businesses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a business that implements a results-based environment, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gorowe.com/pages/about-rowe&#34;&gt;the rewards&lt;/a&gt; are also huge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;easily-spot-star-employees:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Easily Spot Star Employees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A results-based company needs to spot stars in the company — the people who seem to always get done ahead of schedule — and move them to more important, higher-value projects. When employees are measured by their results, this is extremely easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spotting and rewarding star employees creates an incentive for employees to work more efficiently,&lt;/strong&gt; which is good for morale, deadlines, and pretty much everything else businesses want to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;spot-problem-employees-quickly:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Spot Problem Employees Quickly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measuring results instead of time helps the company identify, coach, and — if necessary — weed out problem employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very difficult to just coast along in a company where you&amp;rsquo;re measured by results, so &lt;strong&gt;employees who don&amp;rsquo;t get much done are quickly identified by their low output.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;save-a-small-fortune-on-salaries:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Save a Small Fortune on Salaries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much of a company&amp;rsquo;s payroll goes toward funding Facebook and Reddit sessions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a company shifts to results-based systems, measuring output and whether an employee is earning their salary suddenly becomes not only possible, but easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of reviews relying on a manager&amp;rsquo;s memory and how many days an employee was absent, it&amp;rsquo;s suddenly possible to measure exact output:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pat was paid $50,000 for the year, and during that time turned in 35 projects that we valued at a total of $50,500 — clearly Pat&amp;rsquo;s salary was earned, and we could even consider a small raise.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Terry was paid $50,000 for the year, and during that time turned in 30 projects that we valued at a total of $43,300. We need to coach Terry and see a marked improvement or we&amp;rsquo;ll have to consider termination.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terry&amp;rsquo;s inefficiency may not have been caught without measuring results — a $6,700 oversight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-make-the-change:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;How to Make the Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re caught in a business that values time over results, or if you&amp;rsquo;re a manager or employer that&amp;rsquo;s fallen into the butts-in-chairs trap, there&amp;rsquo;s still hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will take an effort, but if &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/business/psychology_of_management/2014/05/best_buy_s_rowe_experiment_can_results_only_work_environments_actually_be.html&#34;&gt;industry giants&lt;/a&gt; can implement and benefit from it, so can you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-figuring-out-what-needs-to-be-done:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Start Figuring Out What Needs to Be Done&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find that you&amp;rsquo;re unable to clearly state what needs to be done in an organization, drop everything and start by defining what the result needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managers can&amp;rsquo;t expect anyone to be effective if there&amp;rsquo;s not a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/effective-project-planning/&#34;&gt;clear plan&lt;/a&gt; in place for what needs to be done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees can&amp;rsquo;t do good work if they&amp;rsquo;re not 100% clear on what &amp;ldquo;good work&amp;rdquo; means in the context of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you can measure results, you need to &lt;em&gt;define the results to be measured.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-a-case-to-the-boss:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Make a Case to the Boss&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not at the top of your organization, you&amp;rsquo;re at the mercy of higher-ups. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you&amp;rsquo;re helpless, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring up the detriments of butts-in-chairs to your boss. Talk about the benefits to everyone of results-based work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the people at the top are actually interested in making the company better, they&amp;rsquo;ll take what you have to say into consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be smart about it, though, because your boss won&amp;rsquo;t likely change everything just because you waved this article in her face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, make a small suggestion: &lt;strong&gt;as an experiment, your team could try a results-based arrangement and report back after 3–6 months with findings.&lt;/strong&gt; Figure out a way to measure results that will get management excited, and put a plan in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your team has demonstrated that results-based management gets results, your boss will take ownership of the idea and run it up the ladder, hopefully creating a ripple effect that helps move the whole company to a better arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, your team will likely be allowed to keep up the same arrangement — after all, you &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;vote-with-your-feet:066e8470fa035a33749e94d4dbd891a3&#34;&gt;Vote with Your Feet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your organization doesn&amp;rsquo;t respond and insists that your only value to the company is your butt in a chair for 8+ hours a day, then &lt;strong&gt;it may be time to look at other options.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are results-based employment options ranging from the obvious (software and copywriting) to the entry-level (customer support) to the unbelievable (accounting firms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s stressful to hunt for a new job, but there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://weworkremotely.com/&#34;&gt;lots&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flexjobs.com/jobs&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jobs.remotive.io/&#34;&gt;options&lt;/a&gt; for finding remote work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t change your culture, &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself be the one who&amp;rsquo;s punished for someone else&amp;rsquo;s incompetence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ll Be Happy When...</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/finding-happiness</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/finding-happiness</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy once I solve this problem.&amp;rdquo; But with the solution comes new problems. Can we ever be happy? Or do we only pursue happiness and never feel it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-get-this-toy:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;I Get This Toy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1989 I was obsessed with the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dressed up as a Ninja Turtle for something like four straight Halloweens, watched a VHS tape with a few cartoon episodes until I literally wore it out, and owned dozens of TMNT toys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/pizza-thrower.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles Pizza Thrower&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The epitome of combat effectiveness and practicality.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lQOo17fHTKE&#34;&gt;pizza thrower&lt;/a&gt; came out, &lt;em&gt;I had to have it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ninja-rap.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Vanilla Ice — Ninja Rap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Go ninja! Go ninja! Go!

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1O1Ldwi&#34;&gt;TMNT II: The Secret of the Ooze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I begged. I bargained.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:next-birthday&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:next-birthday&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I threw tantrums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on Christmas morning, 1989, I found a gift just the right size under the tree. The clouds parted, an other-worldly glow illuminated the box, and an angelic Foot Clan choir burst into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R_K6971WmAs&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ninja Rap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as I unwrapped the pizza thrower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had imagined this moment for months.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:reality&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:reality&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It was going to &lt;em&gt;change playtime forever&lt;/em&gt; — all of my friends would be &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; jealous. I would &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; get sick of this toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be so happy once I had this toy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within days — maybe even hours — I had lost all the pizzas. And besides, I could never hit my target anyways because the pizzas were stupid and probably broken or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lost interest before the batteries died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-get-some:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;I &amp;ldquo;Get Some&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1999 I was obsessed with getting a girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I — like every other kid my age — was the only one who was single, and I was &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; the only virgin left in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my room, listening to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2s3iGpDqQpQ&#34;&gt;Korn&lt;/a&gt; and writing poetry, I&amp;rsquo;d imagine how different life would be for me once I had a girlfriend. I&amp;rsquo;d be popular. Better-looking. I&amp;rsquo;d get invited to parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be so happy once I had a girlfriend.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In history class I sat next to Tammy West.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:fake-name&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:fake-name&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We were both weird kids, but in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tammy had grown up fast, and tried to dress and act the part — except she&amp;rsquo;d built her entire model of how a sexy, adult woman acted from &lt;em&gt;Sex and the City&lt;/em&gt; and various James Bond films.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She wore pleather bodysuits. Vinyl miniskirts. Knee-high boots. Crimson lipstick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wore heavy metal t-shirts, glow-in-the-dark sneakers with a hidden compartment for drugs in the soles, and black nail polish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of us stood a little outside the group, and our mutual lack of belonging helped us form a bond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tammy — despite her efforts to appear grown-up and sexy — was a virgin, just like me.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:clever&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:clever&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And — despite my attempts to end my sex life before it began with my fashion choices — Tammy had a crush on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We became an odd couple. My friends teased me. I imagine her friends teased her. But we didn&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks into our strange relationship, Tammy rented a hotel room&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:pervert&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:pervert&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and she took me upstairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t know about foreplay. We didn&amp;rsquo;t know about &amp;ldquo;being sexy&amp;rdquo;. We just awkwardly undressed in front of each other and climbed into the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the time it took me to say, &amp;ldquo;Oh my god, it&amp;rsquo;s in!&amp;ldquo; — it was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/its-in.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Oh my god, it&amp;#39;s in!&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    


    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1LLT6IK&#34;&gt;Superbad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a man now. I had a girlfriend. I was no longer a virgin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel any different. I certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t any cooler. My locker wasn&amp;rsquo;t flooded with notes inviting me to parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was just a weird kid who had a weird girlfriend. We didn&amp;rsquo;t last a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-free:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m Free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009 I was obsessed with independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had just ended a serious relationship, and I had a job at FedEx Office to keep the lights on while I pursued a full-time freelancing career in web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had imagined self-employment for years. No boss! No office! No pants!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be so happy once I worked for myself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of the year, I had landed one client. He agreed to pay me an amount that would &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; cover my rent and phone bill. The contract would last three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put in my notice at FedEx, bought a pallet of Top Ramen, and took the plunge into working for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/sriracha.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;sriracha&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My business grew, and soon I was able to buy a bottle of sriracha to add a little excitement to my ramen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I needed to pay taxes. And decide if I was going to be a sole-proprietor, and LLC, or an S-corporation. And figure out how billing works. And come up with an agreement to sign with new clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list grew so quickly that I went to bed most nights feeling that I&amp;rsquo;d made a huge mistake and that I needed to find a new job immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ever-i-m-moving-forward:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;Ever I&amp;rsquo;m Moving Forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, I&amp;rsquo;m obsessed with the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that I won&amp;rsquo;t find happiness in a goal: not a toy, not an act, not an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those goals are all milestones. Progress markers to let me know that I&amp;rsquo;m moving in the direction I want to move in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But they&amp;rsquo;re not the end of the journey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is a continuum, not an possession. I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that I was looking at happiness as a prize that I&amp;rsquo;d receive once I&amp;rsquo;d solved &amp;ldquo;the right problems&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;rsquo;t thought all that hard about it, but I was imagining a finish line, where I&amp;rsquo;d cross the threshold, be greeted by [insert current celebrity crush here] with a bouquet of flowers and a magic amulet that granted me happiness henceforth, and I&amp;rsquo;d just be&amp;hellip;done. With being alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I win, your princess is in this castle, game over, congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is the entire problem: &lt;strong&gt;I was looking at happiness as a destination.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, &amp;ldquo;Oh, I know I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy once I get to the top of this mountain. I just have to suffer through the climb and then all my problems will be solved!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, upon reaching the summit, I&amp;rsquo;d think, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s awful cold on this mountaintop. What a fool I&amp;rsquo;ve been! Clearly, the answer is to make my way to that valley — once I get there, all my problems will be solved!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, climbing the mountain was necessary, because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the valley until I reached the summit. But I was looking at it all wrong: I was looking at the mountain as the end of the journey instead of simply the next step in a journey that only ends when I die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was assigning all of the happiness to &lt;em&gt;completing&lt;/em&gt; the task, rather than finding joy in the process of learning, of working toward a goal, of improving bit by bit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowing myself to enjoy the fun part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m working toward a goal, I&amp;rsquo;m challenged. I&amp;rsquo;m out of my comfort zone and learning new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved the goal, all of those challenges are gone (momentarily) and I feel a sense of loss. Loss of purpose. Loss of a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not until I find the next milestone to work toward that I&amp;rsquo;m happy again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;changing-the-conversation:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb&#34;&gt;Changing the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I no longer say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy when&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy as long as&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;as long as there&amp;rsquo;s a new adventure ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;as long as there&amp;rsquo;s a challenge to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;as long as I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by people who are smarter than me in the areas where I want to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;as long as I am doing the things that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided are important to me (and not putting them off for the sake of obligations or laziness).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I want tomorrow. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;ll see from the top of the next mountain that I climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But I know that I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy as long as I&amp;rsquo;m climbing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:next-birthday&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, Mom, I promise! If you get me this you don&amp;rsquo;t have to get &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; for my next birthday! Honest,&amp;rdquo; he said, for the third straight year.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:next-birthday&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:reality&#34;&gt;In fairness, I was four years old, so it was probably only a few days.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:reality&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:fake-name&#34;&gt;Not her real name, for reasons that will become apparent.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:fake-name&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:clever&#34;&gt;I discovered this through masterfully surreptitious methods: &amp;ldquo;Are you a virgin?&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:clever&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:pervert&#34;&gt;Tammy was able to rent a hotel room at 16 because a middle-aged man ogling a teenage girl doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to look at her ID to learn exactly how big a pervert he is.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ca6409eb349c06c084fc12cbfa7e4dcb:pervert&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Make Time; Find Time</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/find-time</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 10:47:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/find-time</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I love listening to a good podcast. Something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radiolab.org/&#34;&gt;Radiolab&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://hearstartup.com/&#34;&gt;StartUp&lt;/a&gt; — things that make me think, teach me something new, spin me off on a philosophical tangent for a half hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-don-t-have-time-for-that:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Have Time for That&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a constant backlog at work. I have friends I want to visit. I like to go outside when I&amp;rsquo;m not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting quietly for 45 minutes to listen to the latest Radiolab? Sorry, but it&amp;rsquo;s not high on my list of things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The time spent listening to a podcast is too easy for me to reallocate to things that I deem &amp;ldquo;productive&amp;rdquo;, and therefore I rarely listen to podcasts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only times I ever listen to podcasts are A) when a friend hears a particularly good one and goes out of his way to listen to it again while we&amp;rsquo;re hanging out, B) on a road trip&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:road-trip&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:road-trip&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or C) when I&amp;rsquo;m sick/hung over/burned out and can&amp;rsquo;t imagine doing anything other than passively listening to something while draped over my couch like a threadbare blanket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-should-make-time:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You Should Make Time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s important to you, you should make time for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I hear that, I get a twinge of guilt. &lt;em&gt;I should. I&amp;rsquo;m such a slacker. Why don&amp;rsquo;t I just make time to do this if it&amp;rsquo;s important to me?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m making a lot of time for a lot of important things already.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently making time to write this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I will make time to go to the gym for an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evenings this week I&amp;rsquo;ll be making time to meet with friends for dinners and drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I keep &amp;ldquo;making time&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m going to run out of hours&lt;/strong&gt; for work, sleep, and showers.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:showers&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:showers&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; And if I prioritize the things I&amp;rsquo;m willing to make time for, podcasts definitely fall after writing, my health, and my social life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So does that mean I should just give up on podcasts and write them off altogether?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/find-time1.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Don&amp;#39;t make time; find time.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-the-time:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545&#34;&gt;Find the Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent conversation, I brought all this up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/best-friends/&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d love to listen to podcasts, but there just aren&amp;rsquo;t enough hours in the day, you know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a particularly avid podcast listener, Nate didn&amp;rsquo;t understand. &amp;ldquo;You can always find time to listen to a podcast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate fits his podcast listening into the spaces where nothing otherwise engaging is happening. While cooking dinner, he&amp;rsquo;ll throw on the latest &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thisamericanlife.org/&#34;&gt;This American Life&lt;/a&gt; instead of background music. Or while cleaning, or folding laundry, or some other menial task that is otherwise less-than-engaging, but unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How many minutes of your day are full of little spaces where you zone out? Where you&amp;rsquo;re taking care of something, but your brain is completely off?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to listen to more podcasts, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to &lt;em&gt;make time&lt;/em&gt; at all. &lt;strong&gt;I needed to use the time I already had more efficiently.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-the-time-in-my-day-to-day:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545&#34;&gt;Finding the Time in My Day-to-Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t own a car. It&amp;rsquo;s a benefit of living somewhere like Portland — I&amp;rsquo;m close enough to pretty much everything that I can walk there.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:options&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:options&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can walk a mile in about 15–20 minutes. I don&amp;rsquo;t like to talk on the phone while I walk, and I find it really annoying when people walk and text, so I try to keep my phone in my pocket. This means my walks are typically spent daydreaming or thinking about stuff that I can&amp;rsquo;t deal with until I get wherever I&amp;rsquo;m going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, now that I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in terms of finding time, &lt;em&gt;my walks are one or two podcast episodes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wateravenuecoffee.com/&#34;&gt;Water Avenue Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, which is just under two miles from my apartment. It took me about 35 minutes to walk here, and on the walk I listened to episode 3 of StartUp. On the walk home I&amp;rsquo;ll listen to the latest episode of Radiolab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll have spent no additional time that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t already going to spend, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have listened to two podcasts that I really enjoy.&lt;/strong&gt; That&amp;rsquo;s two more podcasts than I listened to in the previous two weeks because I was &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/too-busy/&#34;&gt;too busy&lt;/a&gt; and couldn&amp;rsquo;t make time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else do I put off or skip altogether because I can&amp;rsquo;t (or won&amp;rsquo;t) make time? And where could I find the time to &lt;em&gt;fit it into my existing commitments?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure yet, but I certainly plan to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:road-trip&#34;&gt;Road trips are a very rare thing for me nowadays; I no longer own a car and I usually travel solo, which makes airfare a cheaper, faster option in most cases.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:road-trip&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:showers&#34;&gt;I include showers here because I&amp;rsquo;ve tried the work-is-more-important-than-showers approach. &lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not.&lt;/em&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:showers&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:options&#34;&gt;Or bike, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.car2go.com/en/portland/&#34;&gt;car2go&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:827c260d78b604ba1fddaac998891545:options&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take the Trip</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/take-the-trip</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 15:17:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/take-the-trip</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You should come, too!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to brush an invite off as an empty courtesy, or to decline for any number of arguably legitimate reasons. &lt;em&gt;It feels safe to turn down an invitation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what are we missing out on by being safe?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wanna-hang-out-in-the-forest-with-a-bunch-of-sweaty-nerds:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;Wanna Hang Out in the Forest with a Bunch of Sweaty Nerds?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago, I found myself in Nashville, TN as part of a trip to Kentucky and Tennessee that I&amp;rsquo;d planned with &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/best-friends/&#34;&gt;my friend Nate&lt;/a&gt;. While we were there, Nate called his friend Steve Kamb, the creator of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nerdfitness.com/&#34;&gt;Nerd Fitness&lt;/a&gt;, and we all met up for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point during the conversation, Steve started talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://camp.nerdfitness.com/&#34;&gt;Camp Nerd Fitness&lt;/a&gt; — a weekend out in a remote area of Georgia with a bunch of healthy-minded nerds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wrapped up his description of the event with, &amp;ldquo;You should come!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was September 5. Camp Nerd Fitness started September 18. As far as notice goes, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get much shorter than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate already had travel planned, so he couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it. But I had no plans at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immediate impulse was to decline. &lt;em&gt;Two weeks isn&amp;rsquo;t enough time. I&amp;rsquo;m traveling right now; it would be insane to take another trip so soon. I have too much going on at work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-take-the-trip:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;Just Take the Trip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best pieces of advice I&amp;rsquo;ve ever received was from &lt;a href=&#34;http://barefootfts.com/instructors/craig-weller&#34;&gt;Craig Weller&lt;/a&gt;; we were discussing travel and happiness one evening, and he told me, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just take the trip.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way Craig sees things, if there&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity to do something, and that opportunity doesn&amp;rsquo;t create &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; problems,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:actual-problems&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:actual-problems&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; he will absolutely take the trip. No questions asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, Craig has been all over the world in circumstances ranging from a comfortable family-style getaway in Italy to living with a monkey in a tent in Africa. His stories are incredible, and &lt;strong&gt;none of them would have happened if &amp;ldquo;too busy&amp;rdquo; was an excuse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-really-at-stake-here:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Really at Stake, Here?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking a little harder about Steve&amp;rsquo;s offer, I realized I wasn&amp;rsquo;t risking anything if I chose to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had plenty of airline miles; I could book the plane ticket without spending any money. I was mostly caught up on projects, and two weeks is a good amount of time to crank on things and get a bit ahead to cover the day and a half I&amp;rsquo;d miss for the camp. Steve seemed like a really smart guy — someone who could bring a lot to the table both as a friend and as a business contact.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:call-me&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:call-me&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My first reaction was to think of everything that might go wrong if I took the trip; what I needed to consider was all of the opportunities I&amp;rsquo;d miss by staying home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-ll-only-regret-the-trips-you-don-t-take:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll Only Regret the Trips You Don&amp;rsquo;t Take&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be tempting to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/fear/&#34;&gt;let fear hold you back&lt;/a&gt;, but — when I really think about it — I only regret the trips I &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a chance to see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=14tBBSFF90c&#34;&gt;George Carlin&lt;/a&gt; in 2007, but I decided I was too busy to go. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll wait until his next tour,&amp;rdquo; I said. Now I&amp;rsquo;ll never get the chance&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:george-carlin&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:george-carlin&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to see one of the greatest comedians of all time, all because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/better-productivity-work-less/&#34;&gt;take a break&lt;/a&gt; to go see a show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t recall a single trip I&amp;rsquo;ve taken that I actually regret. I can think of things I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do again, but &lt;strong&gt;the experience and lessons I took away from the &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; trips were worth taking the trip.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-in:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;Are You In?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A day or so after we got home from Kentucky, Nate connected Steve and I via email, and Steve sent the question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still had reservations, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of any &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; excuses. &lt;strong&gt;I took the trip.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/1514573_10152988144498488_2980244324311718297_n.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Camp Nerd Fitness&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.willbyington.com/&#34;&gt;Will Byington&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the last weekend playing ultimate frisbee, reliving my mid-20s in an informal powerlifting competition,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:powerlifter&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:powerlifter&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and not understanding all the comic book, anime, and video game references that were being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I decided to take the trip, I met a whole new group of people I never knew existed, made some new friends, learned some new tricks,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:new-tricks&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:new-tricks&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and had a really unique experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And — perhaps more importantly — because I took this trip, &lt;em&gt;nothing went wrong in my life personally or professionally.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-ready-to-take-the-trip:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b&#34;&gt;Are You Ready to Take the Trip?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What trips have you taken, even when you felt nervous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What trips have you turned down for artificial reasons?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Of the two, which do you feel better about?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:actual-problems&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;actual&amp;rdquo; is paramount, here. &amp;ldquo;Too busy&amp;rdquo; is not an actual problem. &amp;ldquo;Too short of notice&amp;rdquo; is not an actual problem. They&amp;rsquo;re inconveniences. An &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; problem is something like, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m in my friend&amp;rsquo;s wedding that weekend,&amp;rdquo; or, &amp;ldquo;My parents are in town that day.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:actual-problems&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:call-me&#34;&gt;Steve, have your people call my people. We&amp;rsquo;ll do lunch. I&amp;rsquo;ll fax you the details.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:call-me&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:george-carlin&#34;&gt;George Carlin passed away in June of 2008.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:george-carlin&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:powerlifter&#34;&gt;And then, as I hobbled around on my aching joints, remembered why I stopped training like a powerlifter.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:powerlifter&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:new-tricks&#34;&gt;Parkour! Handstands!
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a427c13f773877b57c9aef0fd617fe6b:new-tricks&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stories We Tell Ourselves</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/stories</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 10:03:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/stories</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t regret anything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done that I saw through to the end. I only regret things I left unfinished, or never started at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-journey-is-the-story:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;The Journey Is the Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I tell you that a guy named Billy Ray Valentine was a successful investor and made a killing in the commodities market, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t bat an eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever, right? Lots of people are good at their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I tell you that Mr. Valentine came from the gutter and &lt;em&gt;got his job on a bet&lt;/em&gt;, things get a little more interesting.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/stories1.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;stories&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-good-story-isn-t-about-the-ending:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;A Good Story Isn&amp;rsquo;t About the Ending&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all love a good story. &lt;em&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s too easy to mistake the ending for the whole story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The journey is what makes a story good.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s the details. The twists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, stories don&amp;rsquo;t have to end well. Heroes can lose. Main characters can die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll allow any ending, as long as the story is good.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-lives-are-a-collection-of-short-stories:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;Our Lives Are a Collection of Short Stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we don&amp;rsquo;t sit around at dinner telling tales, &lt;strong&gt;our lives exist as a series of stories.&lt;/strong&gt; We tell these stories to ourselves, to our friends, to potential employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/bright-side/&#34;&gt;spin our stories&lt;/a&gt; and use them to create little vignettes of who we are and what we value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strangers use them to make us real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our stories become the only part of us that anyone else really touches.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-good-story-has-a-follow-through:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;Every Good Story Has a Follow-Through&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, even though the guts of a story lie in the journey, every story still needs to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it needs to &lt;em&gt;really end.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the plot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/WTy0QP&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cool Runnings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was the story of that time Derice Bannock was accidentally tripped by an opponent in the 1988 Summer Olympics qualifier before giving up on his Olympic dreams, the story would have felt incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Derice took his failure and pushed onward — and ultimately &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=31M_MdSVxV8&#34;&gt;failed again, sort of&lt;/a&gt; — and it makes for a great story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-up-to-us-to-make-our-stories-good:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Up to Us to Make Our Stories Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a choice with every story we begin: &amp;ldquo;Am I going to see this through to the end, or am I going to give up and leave the story unfinished?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When things get difficult, we can always bail and walk away. And sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s how a story needs to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for every story we leave unfinished, we&amp;rsquo;re building a narrative around ourselves. Are we leaving more stories unfinished than we&amp;rsquo;re seeing through to the end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-your-stories-say-about-you:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;What Do Your Stories Say About You?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you play back your stories in your head, do you feel good about them?&lt;/strong&gt; Or do they feel like a collection of half-finished anecdotes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that — regardless of how your stories read so far — you&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of a few stories right now. And you&amp;rsquo;ll start new stories in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to make them good ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;If you want to know Billy Ray&amp;rsquo;s full story, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/X7sjiL&#34;&gt;watch the documentary&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do It Every Day</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/do-it-every-day</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 23:52:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/do-it-every-day</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m too busy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s my favorite excuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a very lucky guy because I truly enjoy my job. I work for fun, so it never really feels like work to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dark side of this, however, is that I tend to prioritize work over everything that I don&amp;rsquo;t consider essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m too busy to go to a movie.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have too much work to do to head out to the coast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, I bury myself in work. I developed that habit in my early twenties to keep my nascent business afloat. And for all the good it did for me — I have a career, income, freedom — it also had some negative side effects: I neglected my emotional and physical health in favor of progress, and I cultivated a little bit of anxiety around &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I give myself a choice between work and &amp;ldquo;something for me&amp;rdquo;, I will choose work every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m finally starting to realize I need to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/better-productivity-work-less/&#34;&gt;spend less time working&lt;/a&gt;, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it easier to walk away from my half-finished todo list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-things-i-should-i-won-t:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836&#34;&gt;The Things I Should, I Won&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything that I tell myself I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do, I rarely do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; practice the guitar. But I usually only pick up my guitar for a few minutes a week, if that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; start learning Italian. But I haven&amp;rsquo;t even looked into starting, let alone actually learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy playing guitar, or that learning Italian doesn&amp;rsquo;t interest me. It&amp;rsquo;s that I weigh activities in my head on a cost-benefit basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning guitar is fun, but it provides no practical benefits. The emotional satisfaction I get from playing a song is the same kind of payoff that I get when designing a website&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:creative-rush&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:creative-rush&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, so my brain tells me to prioritize work on the site: I get the emotional payoff &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; it pays the bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning Italian is going to be necessary soon — I&amp;rsquo;m going to Italy at the end of this year — but my brain tells me other projects are more pressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-things-i-must-i-do:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836&#34;&gt;The Things I Must, I Do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/do-it-every-day.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;If it&amp;#39;s important, do it every day.&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s important, do it every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quote from Dan Gable&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:dan-gable&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:dan-gable&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; dozens of times without ever actually &lt;em&gt;hearing it&lt;/em&gt;. At least not until recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-must-work-out:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836&#34;&gt;I Must Work Out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to struggle to get to the gym. I can always make an argument that some project or another is too important for me to take an hour and a half to work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized spending that time at the gym helps me clear my head, improves my sleep, and boosts my confidence&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:fat-shit&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:fat-shit&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; — that&amp;rsquo;s worth the interruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s actually so valuable that I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped looking at it as optional.&lt;/strong&gt; I have a personal trainer now, who waits for me at 9am on Tuesdays and Thursdays, and who will be disappointed and inconvenienced if I don&amp;rsquo;t show up. &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an obligation. A thing I &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-must-write:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836&#34;&gt;I Must Write&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a love/hate relationship with writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to go in fits and starts; I&amp;rsquo;ll blog consistently for a month, then drop off the face of the planet for months — sometimes years – while &amp;ldquo;more important things&amp;rdquo; dominate all of my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I love writing. It&amp;rsquo;s therapeutic for me, and something that I truly enjoy. I just feel guilty spending hours writing a post that&amp;rsquo;s more or less a public diary entry for me when I have client projects to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/best-friends/&#34;&gt;best friend&lt;/a&gt; Nate was feeling the same strain, so we made a friendly bet: we would write for 30 minutes a day and publish whatever came out. No matter what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing I only have to write for 30 minutes removes the guilt around writing, and allows me to make writing something I &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; do. It&amp;rsquo;s part of my morning ritual now: wake up, coffee, write for 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-away-the-option:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836&#34;&gt;Take Away the Option&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The important shift that&amp;rsquo;s taken place with each of the habits I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully adopted is that they&amp;rsquo;re not optional.&lt;/strong&gt; Each &amp;ldquo;must do&amp;rdquo; item is just a thing that has to happen. Like eating, or paying bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, nothing has changed. I still have the same number of hours in the day, and the same list of things I want to accomplish. But I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/&#34;&gt;why I&amp;rsquo;ve failed before&lt;/a&gt;, and used those lessons to adjust my approach. &lt;strong&gt;I changed my perception of the things I want to accomplish from &amp;ldquo;desirable&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;mandatory&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the gym, I&amp;rsquo;m going on a year and a half with consistent workouts: I haven&amp;rsquo;t missed a session unless I was out of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is still too new to know for sure, but so far I&amp;rsquo;ve put in at least 30 minutes of writing a day, and only failed to publish once. Compared to the once-every-month-or-three pattern from before, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-on-your-must-do-list:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s on Your &amp;ldquo;Must Do&amp;rdquo; List?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have anything you&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off because it&amp;rsquo;s optional?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you made something non-optional and seen success similar to mine? Or, better, have you seen longer-term success?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear about it; hit the discussion link and share!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:creative-rush&#34;&gt;For me, it&amp;rsquo;s the creative rush. Stringing notes together on a guitar and stringing pixels together on the screen both feel great when they come together.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:creative-rush&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:dan-gable&#34;&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s an Olympic gold medalist and a wrestling coach. I think this quote was made famous by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.t-nation.com/free_online_article/sports_body_training_performance/the_gable_method&#34;&gt;Dan John&amp;rsquo;s article on the Gable Method&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:dan-gable&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:fat-shit&#34;&gt;Because I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like a fat shit who lives in an office chair.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3a417c9a488f6d82d095f426569a1836:fat-shit&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Montana</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 17:46:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Years back, before I moved to Portland, I used to haunt a bar called Al&amp;rsquo;s and Vic&amp;rsquo;s in Missoula, Montana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of those dives where it was too loud to hear yourself think and the floor was &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; sticky, but they sold a bucket of PBR for four dollars, and a Montana Happy Meal&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a night where I&amp;rsquo;d been called in as wingman for Scott, we met with his date and — for the span of a beer — I did my best not to make him sound like a degenerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His date, whose name I don&amp;rsquo;t remember but whose face looked like a Bernadette, told us her friends were arriving and would we mind standing at the bar with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette introduced us to her friends, Mandy and Kate. Mandy, it turns out, was a friend of Scott&amp;rsquo;s, and the two of them pulled Bernadette into conversation, leaving Kate and I to fend for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate was beautiful. Like, &lt;em&gt;holy shit&lt;/em&gt; good-looking — the kind of attractive that usually requires about a grand&amp;rsquo;s worth of Photoshop cleanup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, on the other hand, was wearing a cowboy shirt with pearl snaps, sporting an extra twenty pounds or so, and unshaven in the not-sexy way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, despite my homeless desperado ensemble, we hit it off immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was funny, sharp-witted. I was scrambling to keep up, but she was laughing. The hoarse mating calls of a hundred college kids were muffled under the sound of her voice, like bourbon over fine-grit sandpaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The faces around us blurred and faded; it was just me and Kate and my beer and her whisky diet and this moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain was leaking that special cocktail of chemicals that only happens the first time you make a connection with someone. In that moment I understood how people can meet and fall in love and end up making long-term promises to each other in front of an Elvis impersonator — all in the span of one intense night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spark between us had magnetized the air; my heart was trying to pull out of my chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette reappeared over Kate&amp;rsquo;s shoulder, and the room snapped back into focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandy was with her, and Scott returned a moment later with a fresh bucket of beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott gave me a &lt;em&gt;how&amp;rsquo;d it go for you&lt;/em&gt; look. I tried not to look upset about the interruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls did their secret eye contact telepathy thing, and Bernadette started preparing her exit. Mandy and Kate took her cue and started gathering their purses and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate caught my eye as she swung her coat around her shoulders, and my heart went all squishy and weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I formed the words in my brain — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number&lt;/em&gt; — opened my mouth to speak — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number, you idiot!&lt;/em&gt; — and I said, &amp;ldquo;It was really nice meeting you. Have a great night.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She might have hesitated. I was too disgusted with myself to notice. The next thing I knew I was watching her hair bounce in the red bar-glow as she walked away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of running after her, telling her I couldn&amp;rsquo;t let her get away without knowing I could see her again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s romantic? Probably creepy. Better not.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of asking Scott for Bernadette&amp;rsquo;s number so I could call her and ask for Kate&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s even worse. Stop it. All of your ideas are bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did nothing. I watched the door close behind her. My mouth was probably hanging open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Scotty — never one to pass up a kidney punch — said, &amp;ldquo;Blew that one, huh?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the beer he offered and did a poor job of acting nonchalant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You know who she is, right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shook my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a special kind of schadenfreude that only men experience. It occurs when we watch a friend — hitting it off with a woman who is clearly out of his league — suddenly and spectacularly self-destruct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a teeball benchwarmer. Kate was one good season away from the big show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scotty was so darkly gleeful he should have been stroking a Persian cat as he said, &amp;ldquo;She was Miss Montana last year.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goddammit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot with Miss Montana, and I let her walk out of the bar. After fifteen minutes of great conversation and good chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replayed the moments before she left in my head. I met her eyes. &lt;em&gt;She was waiting for you to ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot. I did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-wasted-second-chance:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;The (Wasted) Second Chance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks later, I was out with Scotty again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was late, and we had slunk into the bar everyone despised. The sign on the door said &amp;ldquo;Bodega&amp;rdquo;, but it may has well have been called You&amp;rsquo;re Hammered Again &amp;amp; None of the Girls Will Talk to You, Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out front, I bummed a cigarette off a stranger and wobbled gently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jason?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wheeled and found myself facing Kate. I immediately stamped out my cigarette. I could feel the air starting to magnetize again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate smiled. And then she hugged me. Her hair smelled like vanilla-scented heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smelled like an ashtray full of whiskey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So how are you?&amp;rdquo; I managed to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Great! Oh, by the way, these are my brothers, Jeff and Mark,&amp;rdquo; she said, motioning to the two frighteningly large men who flanked her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded. They nodded back, then pretended not to pay attention while this drunken asshole in front of The Saddest Bar in Missoula tried to flirt with their sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow we just fell back into it. She teased me about my smoking, I poked fun at the shoes she was carrying, and we both laughed. My heart did the squishy-weird thing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it was time to make the move. Her brothers weren&amp;rsquo;t going to stand there all night, and I needed to head back inside before Scott ordered me any more drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried scraping every last bit of courage off the walls of my rib cage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just ask. Ask for her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to think of a line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a line, dickhead: &amp;ldquo;Can I get your number and call you sometime?&amp;rdquo; Just. Ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I caught eyes with the larger of her two brothers. And then I wondered if I&amp;rsquo;d misread the whole situation and she was just being nice to me. And then I froze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, hey, it was great seeing you again. I should probably get back inside.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idiot. Idiot. Idiot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flushed. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even make eye contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As suddenly as she&amp;rsquo;d appeared, Kate — Miss Montana — the gorgeous, funny girl I love-at-first-sighted (twice) was gone into the night. For good this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lost-in-the-woulds:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;Lost in the Woulds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would have been a great couple. She would have had a secret family recipe for waffles and a mean Scrabble game. Maybe her disturbingly attractive genes would compensate for my hairiness and we&amp;rsquo;d make the world&amp;rsquo;s hottest babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She would have shot me down. We&amp;rsquo;d have only had another thirty seconds of good conversation left in us. She would have had a boyfriend. I would have hated her guts after two weeks of hanging out. Or, more likely, she&amp;rsquo;d have hated mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand wonderful memories, starting with the one where I asked if I could call and she said yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand mistakes and alienated myself from the Montana Beautiful Women&amp;rsquo;s Club&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any of those outcomes would have been fine. Even bad experiences are still &lt;em&gt;experiences&lt;/em&gt;, you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;em&gt;wondering!&lt;/em&gt; The wondering is murder. There&amp;rsquo;s no lesson to learn in &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s just the nagging of an unanswered question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, I&amp;rsquo;m not the guy who took a long shot with a beauty queen and succeeded against the odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also not the guy who took a shot and missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just a guy who had a shot and stood there looking foolish while the clock ran out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;A shot of Jameson with a PBR back.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;Totally a thing.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fear</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/fear</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 15:17:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/fear</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to back down from a challenge, or to hedge our bets to leave ourselves an out. Sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s wise. Most times we&amp;rsquo;re just scared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a terrifying thing, The Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear tells us that our ideas are too risky, or uninteresting, or just plain &lt;em&gt;bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear tells us we&amp;rsquo;ll be rejected if we try to say hello. That we&amp;rsquo;ll be ridiculed and laughed at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we stand on the starting line of a new adventure — moving to a new city, leaving an unfulfilling job — The Fear tells us we&amp;rsquo;ll never make it; could never make it; should just give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying is scary. Trying is difficult. Most of all, trying makes us vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;schrödinger-s-kiss:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738&#34;&gt;Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s Kiss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was twelve, my parents used to play cards with Cindy&amp;rsquo;s parents. She was the first girl I&amp;rsquo;d spent time alone with, and I was &lt;em&gt;in love&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I wanted to do was kiss Cindy. And I was pretty sure Cindy wanted to kiss me, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But The Fear was certain a kiss spelled disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;ll say no. She&amp;rsquo;ll tell her parents. She&amp;rsquo;ll be so disgusted she&amp;rsquo;ll throw up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I didn&amp;rsquo;t try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wondering was torture. Would she kiss me? What would kissing be like? Did she like me, or did she &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; like me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visualized every step of the kiss: Cindy and I would be playing &lt;em&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/em&gt;, and she&amp;rsquo;d be on a roll&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;d watch intently as she squared off with Dr. Robotnik.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the split second after defeating the boss, while her heart was soaring with the joy of having saved the world from the clutches of evil, I&amp;rsquo;d wrap my arms around her and we&amp;rsquo;d kiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;d be surprised, and thrilled, and we&amp;rsquo;d kiss like on those soap operas my mom watched where our heads rotate side to side for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could almost feel our lips touching, I wanted it so bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But still The Fear said it would never work, and that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t even bother trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me weeks to defeat The Fear. During a game of Truth or Dare, I finally worked up the courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I dare you to kiss me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heart was in my throat. I was tensed up, ready to sprint for the door if she said no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But she didn&amp;rsquo;t say no.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Cindy led me downstairs, where we snuck past our dads out into the garage and sat on the bumper of her mom&amp;rsquo;s minivan.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Even as she held my hand, I heard The Fear telling me it was all about to go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it didn&amp;rsquo;t go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy leaned in, and I had my very first kiss: a tight-lipped peck followed by a panicked sprint back up to her room before our parents could notice we&amp;rsquo;d left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been kissed. I was a man now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fear-as-a-friend:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738&#34;&gt;The Fear as a Friend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I overcame The Fear and got my first kiss, I had an advantage: I knew The Fear could be beaten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear told me I&amp;rsquo;d blow it on my first oral presentation in junior high. I pushed through and got a B+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear was certain I&amp;rsquo;d never win in the student elections, but I ran anyways. I was elected Junior Class Vice President.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear screamed that my band would make me the butt of a lot of jokes. But I got on stage, and discovered my first real passion in music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It never went away, The Fear, but every time I push past it, it gets a little easier the next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started to look forward to The Fear now; when it rears its head, I know I&amp;rsquo;m pushing myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m doing something that scares me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m growing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still don&amp;rsquo;t like The Fear. It makes me feel awful, paralyzed, a little nauseous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every new adventure, I&amp;rsquo;ll be that twelve-year-old boy: terrified, and desperately trying to scrape together enough courage to go in for my first kiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I welcome it now. The Fear is the starting line of a new challenge. A sign that I&amp;rsquo;m becoming more than I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth-or-dare:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738&#34;&gt;Truth or Dare?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s play a game of Truth or Dare.&lt;/strong&gt; Think of something you&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to try, but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now tell the truth: &lt;strong&gt;is there anything &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; stopping you?&lt;/strong&gt; Or is it just The Fear making excuses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, of course, the dare: I dare you — I &lt;em&gt;double dare&lt;/em&gt; you — to &lt;strong&gt;do that thing you&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do *today&lt;/strong&gt;*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s too big to do in a day, then take one step toward that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; to move past The Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it can be shared publicly, post your thing on the discussion for this post, and tell me what the one step you&amp;rsquo;re taking today will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Push through The Fear. The kiss is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brennaphotos/3499551628/&#34;&gt;Brenna Lyn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;Get it? Because&amp;hellip; because it&amp;rsquo;s Sonic. And he rolls. &lt;em&gt;Amirite?&lt;/em&gt; Ah, never mind.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;Because — of course — sneaking clumsily through the house was &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; less conspicuous than staying in her room like we always did.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;I was impeached about a month later. Long story. Ask me over drinks.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Something</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/create-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 17:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/create-something/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I feel restless or unhappy, it usually means I&amp;rsquo;m not creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always feel better when I&amp;rsquo;m creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/create-something.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;create something&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of what I create comes in the form of pixels and code for my clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I do a personal website project — like this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other times I&amp;rsquo;ll draw little characters on bar napkins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while I&amp;rsquo;ll pick up my guitar and strum, or I&amp;rsquo;ll meet up with an old friend and we&amp;rsquo;ll record &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/bearbak/trouble&#34;&gt;Taylor Swift covers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll work out a new cocktail recipe that I can make at home. Or make pizza from scratch. Or whatever. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I always feel better when I&amp;rsquo;m creating.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creation is the intersection of learning and doing.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s the application and proofing of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creation is a way of stating that — &lt;em&gt;hey, everyone!&lt;/em&gt; — there are things that I value, and that I&amp;rsquo;m willing to work for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creation is chasing ideas that inspire us, intrigue us, make us wonder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing I can imagine is to live without wonder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because when I wonder, I want to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I want to know, I learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I learn, I want to test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I test, I create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; feel better when I&amp;rsquo;m creating.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>