<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Positivity on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/positivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Positivity on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 09:55:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/positivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is the Magic?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/magic</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 09:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/magic</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As kids, we see a lot of the world around us as magical. Then, as we get older, the magic gives way to understanding. &lt;strong&gt;But is losing the magic a good thing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/where-is-the-magic.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Where is the magic?&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/bobjagendorf/&#34;&gt;Bob Jagendorf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-curse-of-knowledge:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;The Curse of Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was first starting out in business, I read a book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://cptr.me/XoBEmg&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Made to Stick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Among other things, I was introduced to The Curse of Knowledge, which is the idea that — as we become more familiar with a given topic — we are unable to explain an idea well to someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about any time you&amp;rsquo;ve played charades, and by the end you&amp;rsquo;re ready to scream at your team, &amp;ldquo;How could you &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; get that?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your head you were perfectly pantomiming &lt;em&gt;Gone with the Wind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What your team saw was you riding an imaginary horse and waving your fingers like you were casting a spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; something, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely difficult to see it from the perspective of someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-other-curse-of-knowledge:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;The Other Curse of Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another curse of knowledge, though, and it&amp;rsquo;s a little sneakier. &lt;em&gt;The Revenge of the Curse of Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/are-you-wizard.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;are you a wizard&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young, I thought my dad was basically a wizard because he could tie shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought my mom was conjuring up cookies through some dark art or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiny people lived in my television to entertain me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rabbit and a fat man broke into my house to leave candy and gifts every so often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My closet was a portal to the worst place imaginable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world was full of magic, and I was awestruck.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disillusionment-or-how-the-magic-died-in-a-book:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;Disillusionment, or How the Magic Died in a Book&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I learned how to tie my shoes. I added the ingredients my mom had measured out into a bowl and watched cookies take shape. I learned enough about TV signals to know there weren&amp;rsquo;t actually tiny people in there. Dad spilled the beans about Santa and the Easter Bunny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The closet still creeps me out, though.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bit by bit, the magic was stripped away and the simple truth about how things worked was laid plain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was no longer awestruck. Instead, I was condescending to the people around me who hadn&amp;rsquo;t learned yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-world-without-magic:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;A World without Magic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I see something amazing, it feels like magic. I&amp;rsquo;m blown away. I tell my friends. If there&amp;rsquo;s a YouTube clip, I&amp;rsquo;m sharing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8F6EoMdn95E?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw this guy — &lt;a href=&#34;http://dubfx.com/&#34;&gt;Dub FX&lt;/a&gt; — on the streets of Amsterdam, and I was &lt;em&gt;convinced&lt;/em&gt; he was a sorceror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just a dude with a microphone. He starts singing. Then&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;holy shit what just happened? &lt;strong&gt;It must be magic!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not. It&amp;rsquo;s a talented musician who can beatbox and operate a looping station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impressive? Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic? Not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;losing-my-sense-of-wonder:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;Losing My Sense of Wonder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not just entertainment and childhood stories that have lost the soft glow of pixie dust; I&amp;rsquo;ve felt a similar sense of disillusionment with my own life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started &lt;a href=&#34;http://copterlabs.com/&#34;&gt;building websites&lt;/a&gt;, code was still fairly mystical to me. I could do a few things, but most of what I saw was beyond my grasp; otherworldly manifestations brought forth by the legendary Mystics of Nerd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful freelancing was a dark art. Saving money required an incantation from a book bound in human skin. If I wanted to be any good at sex, I needed to sacrifice a goat at Kilauea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the more I learned, the more I realized that none of this is sacred, supernatural, or even secret. There are no shortcuts. No &amp;ldquo;weird tricks&amp;rdquo; to make someone suddently good at a skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no magic. It&amp;rsquo;s all just hard work, practice, actually giving a shit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;does-magic-matter:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;Does Magic Matter?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/Justin-Flom-Magic-Trick.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Justin Flom magic trick&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    


    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.justinflom.com/&#34;&gt;Justin Flom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, who cares if there&amp;rsquo;s no magic? We&amp;rsquo;re adults, dammit, and magic is for children. And David Blaine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure. That&amp;rsquo;s fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m not ready to give up my sense of wonder. I like being blown away by something that I don&amp;rsquo;t understand.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I want to be surrounded by wizards and fairies and sorceresses who are making impossible things happen all around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I lose my sense of wonder, then I&amp;rsquo;m resigning to a life of familiar, comfortable tasks. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing left to surprise me.&lt;/strong&gt; Giving in to the part of me that&amp;rsquo;s jaded and pessimistic that beleives there&amp;rsquo;s nothing new anyways and why bother at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d like myself without the hope for magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-how-can-we-bring-the-magic-back:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;So How Can We Bring the Magic Back?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with The Revenge of the Curse of Knowledge is that once you&amp;rsquo;ve seen behind the curtain, you can&amp;rsquo;t unsee it. The wizard is just a dude with a killer pyrotechnics setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s no going back to the kind of awe and wonder we felt as children. And that&amp;rsquo;s probably okay; I lost a lot of sleep wondering if my uncle would ever give my nose back, and I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford that today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we can find new magic, and remember to &lt;em&gt;actually feel&lt;/em&gt; that amazement that comes along with seeing something new and wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be big stuff, like learning that there were &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iflscience.com/plants-and-animals/first-ever-swimming-dinosaur-ate-sharks&#34;&gt;shark-eating dinosaurs&lt;/a&gt; or that scientists are working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nature.com/ncomms/2014/140826/ncomms5712/full/ncomms5712.html&#34;&gt;tiny robots that fight cancer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or it can be the little things we might completely dismiss if we&amp;rsquo;re not paying attention: when the new project you&amp;rsquo;re working on falls into place for the first time; when the outfit you chose today gets compliments from everyone you meet; when you think to yourself, &amp;ldquo;I really wish I had a blueberry muffin,&amp;rdquo; and then someone from the office lets you know there are muffins in the break room and should they save you one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our lives are full of small, magical moments.&lt;/strong&gt; If we&amp;rsquo;re looking for them, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-magical-in-your-life-right-now:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Magical in Your Life Right Now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think back over the last few days. &lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s happened that felt like magic?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted cheesecake the other night, and a local bar had a cheesecake special that night. I toured the Willett Distillery, saw how some of my favorite bourbon is made, and sampled some of the very rare, expensive labels. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gsnrzr0Bm80&#34;&gt;discovered a band&lt;/a&gt; that makes my hair stand on end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not quite Santa Claus, but it&amp;rsquo;s enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where have you felt a little bit of magic in your life lately?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;At least at first; eventually I want to know how it works.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:ff97c92e1c05a70f26fbea1e816810cb:at-first&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stories We Tell Ourselves</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/stories</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 10:03:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/stories</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t regret anything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done that I saw through to the end. I only regret things I left unfinished, or never started at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-journey-is-the-story:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;The Journey Is the Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I tell you that a guy named Billy Ray Valentine was a successful investor and made a killing in the commodities market, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t bat an eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever, right? Lots of people are good at their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I tell you that Mr. Valentine came from the gutter and &lt;em&gt;got his job on a bet&lt;/em&gt;, things get a little more interesting.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/stories1.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;stories&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-good-story-isn-t-about-the-ending:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;A Good Story Isn&amp;rsquo;t About the Ending&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all love a good story. &lt;em&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s too easy to mistake the ending for the whole story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The journey is what makes a story good.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s the details. The twists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, stories don&amp;rsquo;t have to end well. Heroes can lose. Main characters can die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll allow any ending, as long as the story is good.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-lives-are-a-collection-of-short-stories:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;Our Lives Are a Collection of Short Stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we don&amp;rsquo;t sit around at dinner telling tales, &lt;strong&gt;our lives exist as a series of stories.&lt;/strong&gt; We tell these stories to ourselves, to our friends, to potential employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/bright-side/&#34;&gt;spin our stories&lt;/a&gt; and use them to create little vignettes of who we are and what we value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strangers use them to make us real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our stories become the only part of us that anyone else really touches.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-good-story-has-a-follow-through:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;Every Good Story Has a Follow-Through&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, even though the guts of a story lie in the journey, every story still needs to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it needs to &lt;em&gt;really end.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the plot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/WTy0QP&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cool Runnings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was the story of that time Derice Bannock was accidentally tripped by an opponent in the 1988 Summer Olympics qualifier before giving up on his Olympic dreams, the story would have felt incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Derice took his failure and pushed onward — and ultimately &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=31M_MdSVxV8&#34;&gt;failed again, sort of&lt;/a&gt; — and it makes for a great story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-up-to-us-to-make-our-stories-good:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Up to Us to Make Our Stories Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a choice with every story we begin: &amp;ldquo;Am I going to see this through to the end, or am I going to give up and leave the story unfinished?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When things get difficult, we can always bail and walk away. And sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s how a story needs to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for every story we leave unfinished, we&amp;rsquo;re building a narrative around ourselves. Are we leaving more stories unfinished than we&amp;rsquo;re seeing through to the end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-your-stories-say-about-you:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;What Do Your Stories Say About You?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you play back your stories in your head, do you feel good about them?&lt;/strong&gt; Or do they feel like a collection of half-finished anecdotes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that — regardless of how your stories read so far — you&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of a few stories right now. And you&amp;rsquo;ll start new stories in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to make them good ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;If you want to know Billy Ray&amp;rsquo;s full story, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/X7sjiL&#34;&gt;watch the documentary&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bright Side</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/bright-side</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 15:28:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/bright-side</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Every time you talk to another person, you&amp;rsquo;re affecting the way they feel. Try not to make them feel like shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re meeting two people for dinner. One sits down with a smile, making eye contact, sitting up straight, looking pretty happy; the other is despondent, flopped in his chair like a sack of laundry, and studying the palms of his hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now ask about their days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paulie-poopypants:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Paulie Poopypants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The schmoopy one says, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough day. I was late getting to work, and as soon as I showed up my boss dropped this giant project in my lap. And then — as if my day wasn&amp;rsquo;t already bad enough — it was raining after work so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t go to the park like I wanted to.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bobbi-brightside:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Bobbi Brightside&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smiley one says, &amp;ldquo;Today was pretty good! I took an extra-long shower, which was great even though I had to rush to work afterward. I just got a new project at work that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a great challenge — I think if I do well, I might get a promotion. And since it was rainy after work I got a chance to write a letter to a friend I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to send.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;they-re-describing-exactly-the-same-day:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re Describing Exactly the Same Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever someone tells a story, they spin it. Their feelings and motives color the narrative, and we feel — to a certain extent, at least — what they feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that. Because it&amp;rsquo;s huge: &lt;strong&gt;you have the ability to control the moods of the people around you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-fun-to-be-around:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Are You Fun to Be Around?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone wants to feel happy. It&amp;rsquo;s why we seek out things like music and love and beauty; it&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href=&#34;http://illegal-art.net/girltalk/&#34;&gt;Girl Talk&lt;/a&gt; causes spontaneous dance parties; it&amp;rsquo;s why I prefer to hear &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/&#34;&gt;stories with happy endings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have the ability to make me feel happy when I ask about your day. What were the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jlengstorf/stop-glossing-over-the-good-stuff-b89e25f7c714&#34;&gt;good things that happened to you&lt;/a&gt;? What&amp;rsquo;s the bright side? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the best thing about today?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you focus on the negative, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to feel great. And I&amp;rsquo;m going to associate that feeling with you. And if it happens frequently, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start avoiding you, because you&amp;rsquo;re a downer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-to-paulie-and-bobbi:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Back to Paulie and Bobbi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s assume you have the option to hang out with either Paulie Poopypants or Bobbi Brightside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a lot more fun hanging out with Bobbi; positivity is contagious, and optimism cures a lot of ills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of all the people you look forward to spending time with. Are any of those people constantly bringing you down with stories about how hard, unfair, or hopeless things are?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-your-silver-lining:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Find Your Silver Lining&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything has a bright side.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s up to you to let the bright side give you hope instead of letting the challenge bring you down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/eeyore.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Eeyore&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself become an emotional black hole.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you see your glass as half-empty or half-full, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s still your glass.&lt;/strong&gt; And you have to deal with that regardless of your attitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; control is how you frame your circumstances in conversation. Bringing a little sunshine to someone else&amp;rsquo;s day means they&amp;rsquo;ll look forward to your company. And you might even find that projecting positivity outward makes you more inwardly positive as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ask yourself: Are you a source of positivity and happiness for other people? Or are you the Eeyore that shits on everyone else&amp;rsquo;s good time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;Okay, okay, not everything. Some things are irredeemable. But if you have time to read a blog like mine, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to bet that you and I are talking better than 95% First World Problems, here. #realtalk
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>