<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acting Like A Grown Up on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/category/acting-like-a-grown-up/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Acting Like A Grown Up on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:22:56 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/category/acting-like-a-grown-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>No one is coming to save you. Are you going to save yourself?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/no-one-is-coming-to-save-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:22:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/no-one-is-coming-to-save-you/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At fourteen, I felt a lot of rage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, my anger wasn&amp;rsquo;t much more than the vinegar-and-baking-soda aftermath of my first waves of conscious individualism breaking against jagged, hormonal shores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-high-school-bad-attitude.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf in high school with a shitty attitude.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  This is the face of struggle.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the time, my rage felt like my only defense against the countless injustices I was forced to endure&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the cruelty of a world out to keep me from feeling any real joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was angry because it felt like things were out of my control. I was debris swept away in a flood — a helpless, hapless bystander caught in a cosmic battle that had nothing at all to do with me: the victim of cruel happenstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world was happening &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; me, and I felt helpless.&lt;/strong&gt; So &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; I was pissed; helplessness has got to be in the Top 5 for Reasons People Get Angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovering-logical-thought:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Discovering Logical Thought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere around fifteen or sixteen, my great-aunt sent me a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1T2FuaG&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which started me down a philosophical rabbit-hole.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1eSrpPt&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1MMo4jH&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I read generation-defining pop-philosophy in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1IkeUXC&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fight Club&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and learned about the true nature of not giving a fuck in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1KQ4Dq0&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Factotum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and realized I&amp;rsquo;d never even come close to hitting bottom from &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1IGLrV4&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus&amp;rsquo; Son&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reading led to questions, which led to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2FTAT.com&#34;&gt;deep conversations with a friend&lt;/a&gt;, which led to critical&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; insights, and — finally — to actual changes in my behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, after a few minutes&amp;rsquo; logical thought, I realized two things that drastically changed my life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-no-one-is-out-to-get-me:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;1. No one is out to get me.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no dark force or diabolical villain working to make my life harder. It was hard to swallow, but I realized that &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just not that important.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, hardly anyone thinks about me &lt;em&gt;at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to imagine that I have critical importance and will therefore face critical opposition, but that&amp;rsquo;s an extraordinarily myopic view of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that — while I am the most important person in &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; world — I barely register in the broader scope of &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably 95% of the human beings I pass on the street receive zero attention. Of the 5% I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; notice, I only notice a single feature (&amp;ldquo;Cool shoes!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nice ass!&amp;rdquo;) and they&amp;rsquo;re forgotten the instant they leave my line of sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://38.media.tumblr.com/c958931381d9efa62f158d885f3ca811/tumblr_mirhy5eQPY1s6tut4o1_r1_500.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;House of Cards nobody cares&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1856010/&#34;&gt;House of Cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who am I to think I&amp;rsquo;m somehow deserving of everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention when I barely give them any thought at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To roughly 7,348,999,994 of the 7,349,000,000 people on the planet, I either don&amp;rsquo;t exist or don&amp;rsquo;t matter enough to occupy short-term memory.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a target. I&amp;rsquo;m not being singled out for cruelty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a victim.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-no-one-is-coming-to-save-me:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;2. No one is coming to save me.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my story has no villains, it&amp;rsquo;s safe to assume there aren&amp;rsquo;t any heroes, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As fate would have it, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fragile, extraterrestrial secret weapon&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/River_Tam&#34;&gt;severely damaged government experiment on the run&lt;/a&gt; — &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just a person.&lt;/strong&gt; My interests are all fairly commonplace, my talents are all borderline commodities, and my opinions are the mutant, amalgamated offspring of the opinions of authors and mentors I&amp;rsquo;ve paid attention to while I&amp;rsquo;ve been alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only unique thing about me is the &lt;em&gt;precise&lt;/em&gt; arrangement of my interests, talents, actions, and opinions. Otherwise, everything I am, do, and believe is more or less standard-issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s no need to save me; I&amp;rsquo;m not vital to the future of our planet. &lt;strong&gt;No one is going to &amp;ldquo;rescue me&amp;rdquo; from my life.&lt;/strong&gt; I won&amp;rsquo;t be &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lana_Turner&#34;&gt;discovered in a drug store&lt;/a&gt; and propelled to stardom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m on my own.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-empty-director-s-chair:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;The Empty Director&amp;rsquo;s Chair&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its face, this may sound bleak: I&amp;rsquo;m all alone and no one cares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is actually &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; news. It was probably the best news I&amp;rsquo;d ever received as a teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent most of my youth terrified of looking foolish. And when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t worried about looking foolish, I was convinced that I would get in trouble if I made the wrong decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I realized no one gave a shit about me, life became immeasurably easier.&lt;/strong&gt; I could strip down to one of those novelty thongs where my penis becomes an elephant trunk and sprint through a town hall meeting belting out the latest Taylor Swift single at the top of my lungs and &lt;em&gt;no one would care.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/elephant-g-string.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Elephant G-string&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Baby, I&#39;m just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake...

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teddygirl.com/elephant-gstring.html&#34;&gt;TGL, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, people would laugh, and someone would definitely put it on YouTube, but no one would &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; care. I&amp;rsquo;d be a momentary amusement, and then I&amp;rsquo;d fade right back into the anonymous social landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made it far easier to do things that were less ridiculous, like taking a chance on making it as a touring musician, or quitting my full-time job to give freelancing a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My whole life, I&amp;rsquo;d believed that &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/project-grownup/the-real-life-truman-show-1cd6b2aa9c34&#34;&gt;people were watching me&lt;/a&gt;, and that some unseen hand was shoving me along a path I had no control over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was wrong: &lt;strong&gt;there was no one making decisions about my life.&lt;/strong&gt; Except me, I guess — assuming I worked up the guts to make any decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my life was a movie, up until this point there&amp;rsquo;d been no director. I&amp;rsquo;d been carried along by the unstoppable current of time, but uncaptained, rudderless, drifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless I chose to act heroically, my movie had no hero. No villains unless I acted villainously. Unless I climbed in and took charge, the director&amp;rsquo;s chair was — and would remain — empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/whos-writing-your-story.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Who&amp;#39;s writing your story?&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-s-writing-your-story:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Who&amp;rsquo;s Writing Your Story?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I assumed responsibility for my own life, everything changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world didn&amp;rsquo;t happen &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; me anymore. &lt;em&gt;I happened to the world&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started steering myself away from the things that frustrated and depressed me, and toward things that excited and motivated me. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long road, and I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it today. I expect I&amp;rsquo;ll probably still be working on it when I die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started seeing immediate improvement: my life was now my choice, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a victim of anything. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t pleasant to admit that a relationship ended because I acted like a dick, or that a project failed because I let everyone down and slacked, but &lt;strong&gt;making my own mistakes was &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; better than feeling helpless against the whims of a malevolent universe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-in-my-own-way:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Getting in My Own Way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comfortably at the helm of my personal narrative, I immediately started closing doors and adding restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of man was I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the type of man who didn&amp;rsquo;t buy into bullshit corporate puppetry and advertising-driven entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the type of man who questioned all authority and made my own path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the type of man who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be lumped in with a group or clique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/south-park-non-conformists.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;South Park non-conformists&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://southpark.cc.com/clips/154322/non-conformist-coffee&#34;&gt;South Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, free thinker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, beacon of logical reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, renegade individualist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, prisoner of silly, self-imposed roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-are-you:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Who Are You?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I graduated high school, my parents took my whole family to Florida. It was half-intended as a graduation gift, and half-intended as a long-overdue family vacation. We went to Universal Studios and Disney World. Daytona Beach. Some enormous waterpark I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the name of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-high-school.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf high school photo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  &#34;As you&#39;ve probably already guessed by my hairstyle, I hate everything. Especially you.&#34;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And I — bound by my staunch opposition to corporate profiteering, herd mentality, and enjoying anything popular — made sure I was miserable the whole time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hot and muggy in the way Florida is usually hot and muggy, but I wore long sleeves and black pants the whole time. While my brother and sister carried their tubes to the top of a big-ass whirlpool-looking deathtrap, I sulked in the shade.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire premise of my family&amp;rsquo;s vacation violated my identity. It was an affront to the core of my being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, of course, that my parents&amp;rsquo; choice for a family vacation spot had exactly &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with my identity, and &lt;strong&gt;I was really just letting some dude in a Mickey Mouse costume ruin family time simply by standing nearby.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of power to give a stranger wearing a giant rubber head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-cages-we-build-for-ourselves:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;The Cages We Build for Ourselves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brick by brick, I&amp;rsquo;d built a wall between what was and was not acceptable for Someone Like Me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me listens to death metal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me would &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; shop at Walmart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me loves &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_the_Homicidal_Maniac&#34;&gt;Jhonen Vasquez&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone Like Me doesn&amp;rsquo;t love Jhonen Vasquez anymore because Hot Topic started carrying his comics.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was proud of the wall at first, because it created a clear separation between &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo; (me) and &amp;ldquo;them&amp;rdquo; (the sheeple).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building the wall was my tiny way of asserting a tiny bit of dominance over the tiny shadow I&amp;rsquo;d cast on the Earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/nate-green-jason-lengstorf_high-school-attitude.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Nate Green and Jason Lengstorf high school bad attitude&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt; and me showing the world just how cool we were.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: a wall is a wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, I was trapped by the imaginary Malevolent Universe that ensured my life happened &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now, I was trapped by the imaginary Someone Like Me who ensured only a tiny subset of all available choices were ever seriously considered.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-identity-snowball:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;The Identity Snowball&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was born, I was a tiny spark of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no memories. I knew nothing. All I cared about was whether I was hungry or sleepy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When something happened, I had no frame of reference. I could only observe, consider it as an isolated event, and make a decision about what that meant to me in that moment.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-childhood.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf childhood photo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  No agenda, no prejudices — just a sweet bear sweater.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no subtext or personal politics. &lt;strong&gt;Things were what they appeared to be. How could a thing be more than it is?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew, I learned language and fear and prejudice and opinion from my environment. Cat peed on me when I was four? Now I hate cats. Dog bit me? I&amp;rsquo;m scared of Dalmatians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends teased me about my Looney Tunes t-shirts, so that stuff was for babies. My mom knew the words to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2H5uWRjFsGc&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tubthumping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so it was clearly too mainstream for me to listen to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slow accumulation of experiential biases continued until &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d become so mired in my identity that I could no longer see an event as A Thing That Happened&lt;/strong&gt;; now it was inextricably linked to things I&amp;rsquo;d seen or heard before, opinions I&amp;rsquo;d adopted or developed, and my own historical stance on events of this type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My tiny spark of consciousness had grown into a hulking snowball of opinions and filters and fears and prejudices, and it was growing larger every day. There was no such thing as an isolated incident anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t asking myself what I should do in response to an event; I was asking myself what Someone Like Me would do in response to that event.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet again, I was out of the director&amp;rsquo;s chair and letting something else make my decisions for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-melt-the-snowball:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;How to Melt the Snowball&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 28, I was invited to try wake surfing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d always hated water: I nearly drowned on multiple occasions&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; when I was really young; I had a chip on my shoulder about being too cool for sports (especially water sports); but mostly I was chubby, pasty, and generally uncomfortable in anything but long sleeves and pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I made the decision to hate water before I can remember.&lt;/strong&gt; As a result, I&amp;rsquo;d spent nearly twenty years flatly refusing any activity involving water because — through the filter of my projected identity: Someone Like Me — water activities were stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my knee-jerk reaction was to refuse. Someone Like Me wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do it, so of course I won&amp;rsquo;t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then — at the insistence of my then-girlfriend — I started examining that refusal. Did I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; dislike water sports, or was it just something I&amp;rsquo;d told myself years ago and never since questioned? &lt;strong&gt;Was I cutting myself off from activities I might really enjoy because of something my idiot teenaged self had decided due to body issues and anti-conformity complexes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to test it: I&amp;rsquo;d go wake surfing, and if I hated it, my dislike for water sports was justified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I liked it, &lt;strong&gt;I needed to reevaluate my opinions about the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;taking-back-control-from-my-past-selves:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;Taking Back Control from My Past Selves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wake surfing was a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;fb-video aligncenter&#34;
  data-href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/jlengstorf/videos/vb.107496345986942/519589568110949/&#34;
  data-width=&#34;730&#34;
  data-allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;
  data-autoplay=&#34;false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve since learned how to surf, snorkel, and kayak.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Each time, I was participating in water-based activities — the ones I&amp;rsquo;d always told myself I hated — and each time, I had a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many other decisions was I letting my pre-teen self make? My teenage self? My twenty-two-year-old post-rockstar-aspirational self?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been cheating myself out of dozens — if not &lt;em&gt;hundreds&lt;/em&gt; — of experiences because I&amp;rsquo;d let my unexamined emotional detritus hobble me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was I really in control of my life if a fifteen-year-old grudge against water was holding me back from things I truly enjoyed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-what-i-am:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a&#34;&gt;I Am What I Am&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the wake surfing incident, I&amp;rsquo;ve started running all my decisions through a do-I-really-feel-that-way-or-am-I-listening-to-my-idiot-teenaged-self-again filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/popeye-i-yam-what-i-yam.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Popeye I Yam What I Yam&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://popeye.com/&#34;&gt;Popeye the Sailor Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt I catch all of them. Good ideas still snag on my emotional barnacles more often than I&amp;rsquo;d prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m trying to keep my identity lean and adaptable. I&amp;rsquo;ve got new &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Popeye&#34;&gt;Popeye-esque mantra&lt;/a&gt;, even:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am who I am — not who I was — and I&amp;rsquo;m working to become who I want to be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, at least, I feel happier than I&amp;rsquo;ve ever felt — and significantly more in-control of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/marisa-morby-nate-green-jason-lengstorf-pot-luck-of-meaning.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Marisa Morby, Nate Green, Jason Lengstorf at a Precision Nutrition charity pot luck.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://marisamorby.com/&#34;&gt;Marisa&lt;/a&gt;, Nate, and me at a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.precisionnutrition.com/&#34;&gt;Precision Nutrition&lt;/a&gt; charity potluck. Big smiles brought to you by a low emotional bullshit quotient.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m free to become the hero of my story.&lt;/strong&gt; To take control of my part in its outcome. To try anything that might make me a better person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, I&amp;rsquo;m free to let my past experiences make me lighter — they&amp;rsquo;re there to show me what I &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; need to carry, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An abridged list of injustices endured by fourteen-year-old Jason Lengstorf:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mother who forced the removal of a tongue ring, despite the fact that it cost a week&amp;rsquo;s pay and several hours of subterfuge in order to get someone to do the piercing in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Girls who were mysteriously repelled by the black hair, zipper-and-safety-pin-laden clothing, death metal t-shirts, and generally shitty attitude of a &lt;em&gt;really nice guy&lt;/em&gt; (which they&amp;rsquo;d know, if they would stop being jerks and overlook all that so they could get to know him).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet commenters who couldn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp that the Insane Clown Posse is just &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt;, despite mountains of empirical evidence. Also, why were those idiot juggalos on the Eminem fan forum, anyways? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OvmvxAcT_Yc&#34;&gt;Fucking magnets&lt;/a&gt;, right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:injustices&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve read Ayn Rand. Yes, the books made me think and influenced me in certain ways. No, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to hang out, Glenn Beck.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:aynrand&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;There were also non-critical insights: I realized that I was smarter than everyone else on the planet; I solved all the world&amp;rsquo;s problems (short version: &amp;ldquo;Everyone should just think and act &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; like me.&amp;ldquo;); I discovered rhetoric&amp;rsquo;s more sinister uses and brutally terrorized my less-eloquent teachers.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:non-critical&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;The six people I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure think about me regularly: me, Marisa, Nate, my parents, and Nadia (whose job involves making sure I&amp;rsquo;m still alive and accomplishing things).
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:peoplewhocare&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leeloo Dallas &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119116/quotes?item=qt0464059&#34;&gt;mul-ti-pass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:fifthelement&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;No matter how I try to say this, it feels cheesy. I feel like some doofy motivational speaker trying to pump up an audience whenever I share this idea. But shifting that power dynamic changed everything in my life, so fuck it: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/kevinkruse/2012/11/28/zig-ziglar-10-quotes-that-can-change-your-life/&#34;&gt;call me Zig&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:cheesy&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;I was probably doing something &lt;em&gt;totally unique&lt;/em&gt;, like writing emo lyrics or reading Chuck Palahniuk.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:sulking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;When I got a JtHM tattoo at seventeen, I never imagined the sort of people who would — in their thirties — recognize and start a conversation with me because of said tattoo. I imagine it feels the same for people who got Disturbed tattoos.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Or maybe not. Maybe they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;stoked&lt;/em&gt; about the folks still down with the sickness twenty years later.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:jthm&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;My go-to responses were &amp;ldquo;crying&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;not crying&amp;rdquo;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:infantdecisions&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;Turns out it&amp;rsquo;s bad news to be both A) recklessly inclined to jump into large bodies of water and B) the opposite of buoyant.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:drowning&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;I say &amp;ldquo;learned&amp;rdquo; loosely. I stood up on a surfboard a couple times, figured out that a snorkel is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a giant straw for drinking ocean water quickly, and dumped a kayak in the shallows while an older couple looked on and laughed.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f2b86522572db70769126b5b2cb8ff8a:kinda&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Completely Alone at a Table of Friends</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/fomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 10:07:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/fomo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So these three statisticians go duck hunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;ve got the shotguns and the duck calls and the waders and the decoys, and they head out into a marsh and wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After a little while, they see some ducks, and the first statistician stands up to take a shot. He shoots — &lt;em&gt;BLAM&lt;/em&gt; — but the duck keeps flying; he&amp;rsquo;s missed high by about a foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The second statistician is ready, and he takes a second shot — &lt;em&gt;BLAM&lt;/em&gt; — but the duck&amp;rsquo;s still flying; the shot missed low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The third statistician jumps up and&amp;hellip; he, uhhh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking at my phone now. My friend&amp;rsquo;s mother just liked one of my photos on Facebook. How anticlimactic. She likes &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; photo I post, so it&amp;rsquo;s kind of like getting a participation trophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I look up, the table is staring at me expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; I ask.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phones-and-toddlers-are-dicks:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;Phones (and Toddlers) Are Dicks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/kids-are-assholes.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Kid being an asshole&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  &#34;Oh, you still needed this? ...yeah, I&#39;m not sorry.&#34;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/gallery/sO1Ok&#34;&gt;chaselye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends are getting to the age where some of them are married and have kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the kids are old enough to talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they do. Frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND:&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at remodeling the basement, but we think we&amp;rsquo;re going to—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY VOICE:&lt;/strong&gt; MOM MOM MOM THERE&amp;rsquo;S A DOG MOM DID YOU MOM DID YOU SEE THE DOG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND:&lt;/strong&gt; Just a minute, honey. We&amp;rsquo;re going to hold off until next—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY VOICE:&lt;/strong&gt; I WANT TO PET THE DOG MOM MOM CAN I PET THE DOG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND:&lt;/strong&gt; Sweetie, I need you to be quiet for a minute. We&amp;rsquo;re holding off until next Spring so we don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with the—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY VOICE:&lt;/strong&gt; MOM MOM CAN I HAVE MY JUICE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[FRIEND digs in cooler for a juicebox. 30 minutes pass. Interruptions continue. TINY VOICE becomes so insistent that FRIEND exits the table briefly. It becomes clear, finally, that FRIEND wants to remodel the basement, but will wait until Spring to avoid extra heating costs since they&amp;rsquo;re planning to replace the insulation. No further discussion is possible because TINY VOICE needs to be put down for a nap. FRIEND goes home.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barbecues aren&amp;rsquo;t that much fun anymore, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these days, neither is the bar. Or dinner. Or other kid-free events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jokes and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/funny-stuff/the-fine-art-of-bullshit-c09f7bbb391e&#34;&gt;silly arguments&lt;/a&gt; and general banter is all different now. Staccato bursts of conversation are all interrupted by flashing lights and three-second bursts of muzak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Two-thirds of a thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY ROBOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND 2:&lt;/strong&gt; New thought started in awkward silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIEND 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Interruption to finish original thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TINY ROBOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see a group of friends in a bar isn&amp;rsquo;t much like watching humans who care about each other interact. It&amp;rsquo;s like watching four people sit alone at a communal table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alone-at-a-table-full-of-friends:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;Alone at a Table Full of Friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ignoring-friends-on-phones.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Ignoring friends at dinner on cell phones.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Dinner was great; I finally caught up on my Twitter feed!

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://grooverpr.wordpress.com/2014/03/29/topic-of-the-week-cell-phones-conversations/&#34;&gt;grooverpr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a true story: I was in Chiang Mai a few months back, and Marisa and I made a game of timing how long it took for various tables of 3+ college students to actually speak to each other. The game was boring; they almost never spoke to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one table — two guys and two girls — who never spoke at all. One of the girls didn&amp;rsquo;t even look at her friends; she spent the whole meal taking selfies at severe downward angles. The other girl photojournaled the entire meal and presumably starved to death because she never got around to eating anything. The guys buried their heads in an iPad game and Snapchat.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-let-em-get-the-hooks-in:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;We Let &amp;lsquo;Em Get the Hooks In&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change was slow for most of us. Almost imperceptible. Sometime in 2009 we became abruptly aware of a dozen unread notifications in our pockets and our stomachs went through the taffy puller because &lt;em&gt;things were happening&lt;/em&gt; and we were missing them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way someone&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; came up with the term FoMO and it started getting tossed around as a psychological disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And — like magic — being a total dick to your friends became a psychological disorder, in the same way that bringing a rooster&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; onto a plane somehow became medically valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;This is things that have gone to far: A rooster on a plane, in a pink tutu, as an &amp;ldquo;emotional support&amp;rdquo; animal. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/PLpuf4EH5Z&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/PLpuf4EH5Z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sue Strachan (@SueStrachan504) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SueStrachan504/status/511540289769844737&#34;&gt;September 15, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-want-to-be-everywhere:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;We Want to Be Everywhere&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren&amp;rsquo;t more things happening in the world now than there were thirty years ago. We&amp;rsquo;re just able to see more of it happening in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a practical demonstration of &amp;ldquo;ignorance is bliss&amp;rdquo;, our parents and grandparents never tasted the bitter anguish of realizing that nerds from the U.S. just &lt;a href=&#34;http://twistedsifter.com/videos/usa-challenges-japan-to-giant-robot-duel/&#34;&gt;challenged Japan to a mech-suit battle&lt;/a&gt; last week &lt;em&gt;and you didn&amp;rsquo;t hear about it until today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we unfortunate residents of The Future™ weren&amp;rsquo;t so lucky. Fate, with a mirthless grin and malevolently glittering eyes, thrust us into a world where Periscope and Facebook and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theonion.com/article/media-landscape-redefined-by-24-second-news-cycle-2213&#34;&gt;24-second news cycle&lt;/a&gt; exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our only weapon in this struggle against cultural irrelevance is a constant IV-drip of information, fed through our eyeballs and fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armed with the latest smart_______, we doggedly pursue Total Awareness. Legends are told of an elite few who know all things &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; they start trending on Facebook. These multi-screen samurai pursue 100% coverage of global occurrences with Neeson-esque determination.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-where-are-we-exactly:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;So Where Are We, Exactly?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the corners of our vision, just beyond the edge of what we can identify without turning our heads, another world is dimly lit with blue light, collecting dust and falling into disrepair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that world doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter now. We &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that world; it&amp;rsquo;s the other things that we need to keep tabs on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; our friends, and their stories.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We already &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; all our family&amp;rsquo;s dirty secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s exciting about the things we already know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing. &lt;em&gt;Nothing&lt;/em&gt; is exciting about the things we know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; exciting? Kid Rock acting like an ignorant hillbilly. &lt;em&gt;What drama and intrigue!&lt;/em&gt; And you know what else? Donald Trump on an escalator. If that&amp;rsquo;s not a memory that will bring you some small comfort in the final hours of your life, you&amp;rsquo;re probably dead inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Grandma can just hold her damn horses if she wants to spend the day with us; we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with matters of critical import, here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/fomo.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;FoMO: Fear of Missing Out&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  #thestruggleisreal

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-things-that-matter:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f&#34;&gt;The Things That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work endlessly — thanklessly — to keep drinking from the information firehose spraying from this pitiless world we live in. No one will sing songs of our dedication and perseverance. The history books won&amp;rsquo;t mention our names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;rsquo;ll know what we&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our old age, we want to look fondly back on a lifetime of accomplishment and contentment. Happy memories of happy days, where we did things that truly mattered to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom&amp;rsquo;s kinda-dry turkey dinner just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make that cut. Sorry, Mom, but there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;real struggle&lt;/em&gt; happening here. You&amp;rsquo;re just too old to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that we don&amp;rsquo;t love our friends and family — we do. Dearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just that we aren&amp;rsquo;t 100% sure there&amp;rsquo;s not something out there that we might love &lt;em&gt;more.&lt;/em&gt; So we have to keep our options open&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and stay diligent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise we&amp;rsquo;re just cheating ourselves, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may not be able to communicate our feelings without emoticons. We may not have spoken to our parents in weeks. Our friends may only know us as That Guy Who Plays on His Phone Through Lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we saw &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tvsV6nlLe1g&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; the day it came out. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VLEfrulUEcs&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, our sacrifice was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;The third statistician jumps up and starts fist-pumping and yelling, &amp;ldquo;Yeah! We got him, boys! We got him!&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:punchline&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;He was looking at snaps of beautiful women doing nothing: talking to the camera, pointing their cameras at what they were eating, waving and laughing. The two girls he was with were incredibly good-looking. They had food they could show him. They had (perhaps most importantly) agreed to hang out with him in person. I wanted to shake him: &amp;ldquo;Son, do you even understand what you&amp;rsquo;re doing wrong, here?&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:snapchat&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bostonmagazine.com/news/article/2014/07/29/fomo-history/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boston Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, credit for FoMO (&amp;ldquo;Fear of Missing Out&amp;rdquo;) goes to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danherman.com/The-Fear-of-Missing-Out-(FOMO)-by-Dan-Herman.html&#34;&gt;Dan Herman&lt;/a&gt;, though it was really popularized by Patrick McGinnis in a 2004 op-ed on the subject. This will be on the quiz.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:fomo&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;Or pig, or mini-horse, or peacock. It&amp;rsquo;s so absurd that you have to wonder if it&amp;rsquo;s an attempt at satirizing rich white women with tiny dogs to help with their depression, or this subversion of cloying airline policy is being carried out by a subset of hipsters who decided mustaches weren&amp;rsquo;t ironic enough.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:supportanimal&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;Of course, no one can prove that the fabled Ultrainformed exist. They&amp;rsquo;ve never been spotted in the wild, and only surface for mere moments at a time under the guise of various throwaway Reddit accounts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The hopeful among Millennials (a.k.a. the Informationally Forsaken) speak of the Ultrainformed as possible saviors from our ignorance; the cynical write them off as the Illuminati; my grandpa says we should just close the fucking computer and go outside already.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:samurai&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;For the last time, Dave: we&amp;rsquo;ve all heard your goddamn Mariah-Carey-in-the-elevator story.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Nobody cares.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:stories&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, yeah, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hang out, but I can&amp;rsquo;t actually commit to anything. There&amp;rsquo;s a possibility that something better than your shitty party will come up, and I want to keep my options open. I&amp;rsquo;ll show up if I show up.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:b103230cb9e761db3dbcf88261a0087f:options&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizards and Assholes</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/wizards-and-assholes</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 09:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/wizards-and-assholes</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One of my early jobs was at a local publishing house, where I did typesetting and rudimentary layout work for field guides. There was a guy there — we&amp;rsquo;ll call him Carl — who handled the still-new digital aspect of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had built a website or two at this point. My work was total amateur hour, but I could tell that this kind of work was something I enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl was the first person I&amp;rsquo;d met who worked on websites for a living.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; At the time, he represented all of the things I wanted in my career. So I looked up to him as a mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, Carl, can I ask you a question? How can I get to where you are? What should I do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl looked at me, sizing me up. He had a smirk on his face. His condescending gaze was amused, like, &amp;ldquo;Who the fuck does this kid think he is?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/ron-swanson-condescending.gif&#34;
       alt=&#34;Ron Swanson condescending&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  I want to make sure you feel like a complete idiot.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1266020/&#34;&gt;Parks and Recreation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt ashamed. I wanted to take my question back. I wanted to hide under the desk until Carl left for the day so I could slink home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked at me for a long time. I shriveled under his stare, questioning everything about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can you tell me the difference between cell padding and cell spacing?&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty sure I knew the answer. I thought maybe it was a trick question. I second-guessed myself. I hesitated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He chuckled and shook his head, disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re not ready to handle the kinds of work I do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-was-an-asshole:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;Carl Was an Asshole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl was forty-something years old, working a job that — in retrospect — was entry-level at best. His skill level was nothing to brag about; he could get the job done, but no one was going to knock any doors down to hire him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Carl was a big fish in a small pond. There was no competition for his job, because no one in Montana at the time was taking digital media very seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/the-wizard.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;The Wizard of Oz&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Pay no attention to the dickhead lording his junior-level skill set over your head.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1JF0EdZ&#34;&gt;The Wizard of Oz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made Carl a lot like the Wizard of Oz: he was mysterious and powerful, dealing in forces that few people really understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I was Dorothy, lost on this brand new career path, looking for someone to guide me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was an eager student. Carl was in a position to help me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, he chose to be an elitist asshole and made me feel stupid for not knowing the things I&amp;rsquo;d just asked him for help with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-of-becoming-irrelevant:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;Fear of Becoming Irrelevant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to think that Carl just didn&amp;rsquo;t like me. He thought I was some dumb kid who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t amount to much and who was probably just on his hobby of the week. Why waste time on the likes of me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think something else may have been at play: Carl might have seen me as a threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not directly. Carl wasn&amp;rsquo;t thinking, &amp;ldquo;Oh no! This kid&amp;rsquo;s about to take my job!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On some level, though, I think Carl may have seen my questions as a threat to his job security. After all, if enough people learned this stuff, it&amp;rsquo;d be a lot more difficult for him to remain the big fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl wanted to be indispensable. He wanted to be the lynchpin in the organization, without which everything would go off the rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That meant treating his knowledge like a trade secret, and boxing out anyone who might weaken his grip on this job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it didn&amp;rsquo;t excuse humiliating a teenager for showing interest in his field of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-be-like-carl:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Be Like Carl&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I was in Boston speaking at an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one of the evenings there was a cocktail mixer at a bar called Lucky&amp;rsquo;s, a basement bar in South Boston. It was the sort of dimly lit, brick-walled dive where you imagine finding disreputable people discussing unsavory acts, but actually find disinterested twenty-somethings discussing undiscovered bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jake-pruitt.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jake Pruitt&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the night wound down, the group I was standing with was approached by this kid, &lt;a href=&#34;http://javascriptjake.com/&#34;&gt;Jake&lt;/a&gt;, who looked like he was about 12 years old. He was 20, in college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment, I was dismissive. &lt;em&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s probably out of his depth,&lt;/em&gt; I thought. &lt;em&gt;I hope he doesn&amp;rsquo;t start asking a bunch of dumb questions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I was angry with myself for letting thoughts like that into my head. I remembered how it felt when I asked Carl for advice, and how humiliated I was when he talked down to me and made me feel like I was too dumb to play on his level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be like Carl,&lt;/em&gt; I reminded myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake was outgoing, curious, personable. He asked a ton of questions, and the whole group joined in to answer them as best we could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point I started giving him shit because he kept pulling his phone out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m taking notes on what you&amp;rsquo;re saying,&amp;rdquo; he told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was both flattering and terrifying. &lt;em&gt;This kid is listening to me? Is that&amp;hellip; Should he be doing that?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it felt good. Here was this kid: excited to learn, passionate about building a career, and looking to me for a little guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake was an eager student. I was in a position to help him out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have been an elitist asshole. I could have done my best to assert my superiority and make him feel dumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it felt way better to help him out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Jake felt good about things, too; later that evening, I got a note from him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Really great chatting with you, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jlengstorf&#34;&gt;@jlengstorf&lt;/a&gt;. Super great life tips, I hope to be like you when I grow up!
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Jake Pruitt (@thejakepruitt)&lt;/small&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thejakepruitt/status/527644976113803265&#34;&gt;October 30, 2014&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;there-s-room-for-all-of-us:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s Room for All of Us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake will end up being pretty successful. He&amp;rsquo;s smart, ambitious, and he&amp;rsquo;s got a head start on his career. He&amp;rsquo;s years ahead of where I was at his age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So should I worry about Jake replacing me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe. But at least now I can remind him that I was a helping hand on his way up, and hope that he&amp;rsquo;ll give me a job when he does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;During the early 2000s in Montana, there were approximately seven people who knew what the internet was.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:montana&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;For the non-nerds in the room, let me try to put this question into perspective. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re curious to know more about engines, and you ask a mechanic how what you should do to learn more about cars. In response, he says to you, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between using a horse to pull your carriage, or using a donkey?&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:e883b21e0e1b626efec1407fdd3ddf25:perspective&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Growing Up? Or Just Growing Older?</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/growing-up-vs-growing-older</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 16:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/growing-up-vs-growing-older</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time in the last few months thinking about adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not the idea of growing older — the actual act of growing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does a boy know he&amp;rsquo;s become a man?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;growing-up-the-old-fashioned-way:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;Growing Up the Old Fashioned Way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some other cultures around the world and throughout history, &lt;strong&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s a rite of passage from childhood into adulthood.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of them seem silly and cruel&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:circumcision&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:circumcision&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but others pose some very real questions about growing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/becoming-an-adult.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;becoming an adult, rites of passage&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;into-the-wilderness:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;Into the Wilderness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, many Native American tribes would send teenage boys on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vision_quest&#34;&gt;vision quest&lt;/a&gt;. Aborigine tribes have a similar ritual, called a walkabout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both cases, the idea is that &lt;strong&gt;the child spends time alone in the wilderness, learns to get by unassisted, gets in tune with life&amp;rsquo;s purpose, and comes back a full-fledged adult.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;growing-up-today-or-the-lack-thereof:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;Growing Up Today (or the Lack Thereof)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my family, growing up wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a thing we cared about. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s all that uncommon an experience in the United States, or really in most of the Western world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As far as I can tell, there is no rite of passage for children in modern culture.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became an adult when I turned 18. At least that&amp;rsquo;s what the legal system and the military said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was headed off to college, which meant leaving home, but otherwise I did the same shit on day 1 of year 18 that I did on day 365 of year 17. Except now I could legally buy cigarettes and play Keno in the gas station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;failure-to-launch:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;Failure to Launch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of any clear distinction between being a teenager in high school and an &amp;ldquo;adult&amp;rdquo; out of high school leaves a lot of us — myself included — feeling like we&amp;rsquo;re still not in control of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an authority figure somewhere with a plan: your parents, your boss, your teachers, anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t you that has more experience and a real plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look to our parents and friends to make our decisions for us. &lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re not ready to be the one holding the bag just yet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grow older, but we remain children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-makes-a-man:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;What Makes a Man?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a scene in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1qUidwZ&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fight Club&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that has always stuck with me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/fight-club.png&#34;
       alt=&#34;Fight Club&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0137523/&#34;&gt;Fight Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tyler Durden:&lt;/strong&gt; My dad never went to college, so it was real important that I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narrator:&lt;/strong&gt; Sounds familiar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tyler Durden:&lt;/strong&gt; So I graduate, I call him up long distance, I say &amp;ldquo;Dad, now what?&amp;rdquo; He says, &amp;ldquo;Get a job.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narrator:&lt;/strong&gt; Same here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tyler Durden:&lt;/strong&gt; Now I&amp;rsquo;m 25, make my yearly call again. I say Dad, &amp;ldquo;Now what?&amp;rdquo; He says, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know, get married.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narrator:&lt;/strong&gt; I can&amp;rsquo;t get married, I&amp;rsquo;m a 30 year old &lt;em&gt;boy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a man with all the right boxes checked for adulthood: college, condo, career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet he&amp;rsquo;s still looking to external sources for guidance. Still wondering what he should be when he grows up. &lt;strong&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s rudderless.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fifty-year-old-children:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;Fifty-Year-Old Children&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother has just recently — in her fifties — started looking at what her life means to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s always had external meaning: her parents; her teachers in high school and college; my dad&amp;rsquo;s career and the need to relocate to support it; raising her children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s all done. My dad&amp;rsquo;s career is established, her kids are grown, and she&amp;rsquo;s feeling a little lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no one left to tell her what to do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So she&amp;rsquo;s starting to answer big questions for herself. What makes &lt;em&gt;her&lt;/em&gt; happy? What does she &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want to do with her time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a lot of ways, &lt;em&gt;she&amp;rsquo;s still a kid.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And she&amp;rsquo;s just one of many people I know who are in similar situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-inward:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;Looking Inward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t claim to know the proper way to bring a child into adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me say that again, so we&amp;rsquo;re clear: &lt;strong&gt;I do not have the answers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I have some ideas.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:outline&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:outline&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the most basic level, &lt;em&gt;adulthood is not reaching a certain age,&lt;/em&gt; ticking off boxes on a checklist, or even things that seem quintessentially adult like having children or getting colonoscopies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adulthood is confidently approaching unfamiliar situations, not because you have a solution, but because you trust that you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to fumble your way to a satisfactory outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adulthood is the understanding that there are no authority figures. There is no one who has this all figured out. We&amp;rsquo;re all just making best guesses and doing what we think is right, based on the limited information and experience we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adulthood is the knowledge that — no matter what you&amp;rsquo;re facing — you can handle it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-vision-quest:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;My Vision Quest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my parents sent me off to college in Denver, I&amp;rsquo;m sure they had high hopes that I&amp;rsquo;d grow up, stop wearing my all-black band t-shirts, get a degree, and embark on some storybook American Dream™ career path with a wife and kids and pets and a house and whatever else it is that signifies a successful life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I dropped out after a few months, moved back into their basement, joined back up with my band, and embarked on what ended up being my vision quest: I jumped in a van with four other dudes and drove around the country playing music for two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/minusmythoughts.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Don&amp;#39;t we look ready to face grown-up issues?&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Don&#39;t we look ready to face grown-up issues?

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tysonvick.com&#34;&gt;Tyson Vick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;into-the-wilderness-or-van-in-my-case:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;Into the Wilderness (or Van, in My Case)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The band barely made enough money to pay for gas. We made our way by asking concertgoers to let us crash on their floors, or by sleeping in our van in the Walmart parking lot.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:protip&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:protip&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was faced with a wide variety of unfamiliar circumstances. My parents — though they weren&amp;rsquo;t going to let me die on the streets of Tucson if the van broke down — weren&amp;rsquo;t wholly supportive of my rockstar lifestyle.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:parents&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:parents&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; My bandmates were no more capable of solving problems than I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was on my own for the first time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-is-within-your-reach:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;This Is Within Your Reach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The band needed shows booked, merchandise designed and ordered, guarantees negotiated and collected, promotion, website design, and a whole bunch of other things ranging from the minutia to long-term strategy that were critical if we wanted to keep touring.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:safety-net&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:safety-net&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I realized that no one was going to do any of this for me, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/set-yourself-on-fire/&#34;&gt;set myself on fire&lt;/a&gt; and figured it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short-term gain of all this was that our tour was a relative success. The long-term benefits, though, I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize for years: &lt;strong&gt;I had learned to trust myself in unfamiliar, uncertain scenarios.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My minor successes as a member of an anonymous, marginally successful band planted the seeds of confidence that would grow to power nearly all of my adult accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;should-we-send-teenagers-into-the-woods:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034&#34;&gt;Should We Send Teenagers into the Woods?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, my situation was pretty unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I think every kid should join a band and make slow laps around the western United States for two years while sleeping in a van?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Well, maybe. But it&amp;rsquo;s not practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do we do? It&amp;rsquo;s not really feasible to send teenagers into the woods. We certainly can&amp;rsquo;t adopt older rites of passage like circumcising high school sophomores or sending girls into seclusion when they start menstruating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s something missing in the way children enter adulthood now. &lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re letting children drift into their twenties and even thirties without any sense of independence or self-reliance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we nudge children into adulthood?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Should&lt;/em&gt; we nudge children into adulthood? Or does the act of pushing them negate the benefits?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do you stand on children becoming adults? Modern rites of passage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we need them? Do we already have them and I&amp;rsquo;m just not paying attention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was your journey into the wilderness?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:circumcision&#34;&gt;The Mardudjara Aborigines circumcise boys at 15 or 16 years old, then make the boys eat the foreskin.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:circumcision&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:outline&#34;&gt;Maybe just the general outline of a few ideas. Based on conjecture and anecdotal evidence. That probably only work for me. (And they only work for me &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; of the time.)
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:outline&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:protip&#34;&gt;Transient #ProTip: Walmart has a policy that allows travelers to park overnight in their lot without being harassed. They also usually have a security guard in a golf cart doing slow laps. When all else fails, it&amp;rsquo;s a place to crash without getting harassed.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:protip&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:parents&#34;&gt;My dad liked that I was in a band. I think he was watching me with the same kind of amusement with which he might watch a puppy trying to climb the stairs for the first time. My mom just thought I was going through a phase and hoped that not too many of her friends saw my eyeliner.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:parents&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:safety-net&#34;&gt;I should mention that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only member of the band who did this stuff. Everyone pitched in. But what I said I would do, I was on the hook for. There was no safety net or backup plan.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:06d12643c1d3ebcd836ae3d290d9d034:safety-net&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away Its Power</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/name-your-fear</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 10:58:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/name-your-fear</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At a sleepover in second grade, my friends put on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0094761/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Blob&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — a horror film about space jelly that kills anyone it touches. I was so scared I started crying and my mom had to pick me up to take me home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another night I snuck out of my bedroom while my parents watched TV, and I saw the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OPdDdC4go6c&#34;&gt;sewer scene from &lt;em&gt;It&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. My dad had to remove everything that even &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt; resembled a clown from the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-wasn-t-scared-of-the-story:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;I Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Scared of the Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both cases, I actually barely saw any of the movie that frightened me. I saw that the movie was a scary movie, I knew that scary movies terrified me, and I knew that watching a scary movie would scare me too badly to be able to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize, however, was my fear of horror films — and the fear I felt when I imagined what terrors those films might contain — was all it took to ruin my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was scared of the movies themselves.&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of the movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was so bad that I only had to see the cover of &lt;em&gt;Child&amp;rsquo;s Play&lt;/em&gt; in a video store to end up petrified and sleepless for a few nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-out-how-it-ends:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Find Out How It Ends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an adult, I still don&amp;rsquo;t care for horror films. But if I start watching one, I now force myself to finish the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I see a scene from a horror film — just like I did when I was a kid — I build a vague, terrifying beast out of my fear of the movie, and this unknowable shape is more monstrous than anything I&amp;rsquo;ll see in a movie. I don&amp;rsquo;t care how good the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer-generated_imagery&#34;&gt;CGI&lt;/a&gt; is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to see the end. I need to know what happens. What &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; goes on in this movie?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no way the actual outcome will be scarier than what I can dream up in my ignorance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By seeing the full movie, I learn the reality of the story, and that takes away the paralyzing power of my ignorance and fear.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-away-its-power:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Take Away Its Power&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our fears are imaginary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t know what comes next, so we make projections about the future. And in our imaginations, the potential for catastrophe is alarmingly high.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;rsquo;re not actually scared of the experience. We&amp;rsquo;re scared of the unknown: the vague, monster-shaped outline in our imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By facing that fear, we replace the monster with a memory. And even if the memory is uncomfortable or humiliating, it&amp;rsquo;s very unlikely that it will be as horrifying as the make-believe nightmare scenario we dreamed up before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shining-a-light-into-monster-shaped-shadows:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Shining a Light into Monster-Shaped Shadows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To take power away from your fear, give it a name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an effort to limit the number of monsters occupying my headspace, I try to push my fears into reality and name them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I feeling anxious about a client who seems unhappy with my work? Call them and clear the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there an unresolved tension between me and a family member? Let&amp;rsquo;s sit down and get to the bottom of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is my laundry room haunted? Let&amp;rsquo;s go stand in there and find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I notice a situation that scares me, I try to jump in earlier rather than later, because the end result is always the same: I face the fear and realize the difference between what I &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; was wrong, and what was &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; wrong is staggering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I thought may have been a relationship-ending issue with the client turned out to be a few small adjustments and ten minutes of screensharing to show them how to use a tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a beer with the family member, we realized we were both working toward the same goal even though our methods were clashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My laundry room is creepy as shit. But it&amp;rsquo;s not haunted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a fear is dragged into reality and exposed to a little daylight, the giant monster-shaped shadow in my imagination shrivels to a small, silly bit of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;name-your-fears:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a&#34;&gt;Name Your Fears&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What monsters are lurking in your imagination right now? How many of them can you drag into reality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/uaeincredible/217849066/&#34;&gt;Capture Queen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;Sure, &lt;em&gt;The Ring&lt;/em&gt; still scared the shit out of me, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t lose any sleep afterward. I can guarantee the things my brain will dream up out of a storyline involving a dead girl who haunts your TV are &lt;em&gt;far worse&lt;/em&gt; than what happens in the movie.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:the-ring&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;For an easy example, imagine asking someone out on a date that you think is &amp;ldquo;out of your league.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I get anxious imagining it: I see her across the room, obviously more successful, socially adept, and better-looking than me. She&amp;rsquo;s smiling, sharply dressed, surrounded by people who are laughing at the devilishly clever observation she just made about current events of which I&amp;rsquo;m appallingly ignorant.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And here I come — trying to look confident but probably smiling like a crazy person, food caught in my beard, smudges on my glasses — to interrupt her conversation. I tell a joke that doesn&amp;rsquo;t land, laugh loudly at my own joke out of discomfort, turn tomato-red in self-conscious embarrassment, and stammer my way through awkward compliments that are just making her more uncomfortable.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I never even get to the part about asking her out.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;She laughs in my face. The people around her laugh in my face. Everyone in the room perks up, and she grabs the microphone from the party&amp;rsquo;s emcee.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ladies and gentlemen, a special announcement: Jason Lengstorf is a useless idiot who lacks the charm of a papercut and smells like he&amp;rsquo;s been eating nothing but cheese for the last eight weeks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The story makes the news later that night, and I&amp;rsquo;m forced to flee the country in shame. I live out the rest of my days in Bulgaria harvesting sugar beets in exile.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The reality, however, is that — while &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d probably still blow it&lt;/a&gt; — the actual situation would be far less ridiculous. I&amp;rsquo;d say hello, she&amp;rsquo;d say hello, I&amp;rsquo;d try to make conversation, and when we didn&amp;rsquo;t hit it off I&amp;rsquo;d make an exit. This isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a storybook ending, but it&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near the worst-case scenario my imagination cooks up.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:71461a143c15f7631f6fc455b3a9044a:out-of-my-league&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Taste Doesn&#39;t Matter</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/taste-doesnt-matter</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 17:59:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/taste-doesnt-matter</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me knows that I love a good cup of coffee, and that my first order of business upon arriving in a new city is to locate the best barista in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good coffee is important to me.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:marco-arment&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:marco-arment&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/coffee-jason-lengstorf.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;coffee, by Jason Lengstorf&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wallywhitefish.com/&#34;&gt;My dad&lt;/a&gt;, however, doesn&amp;rsquo;t give a shit about coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He loves a good cup every now and then, but most of the time he drinks &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.keurig.com/shop/k-cups/all-k-cups&#34;&gt;K-cup coffee&lt;/a&gt; or — gasp! — instant Folgers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This used to bother me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fighting-the-urge-to-fix-my-dad-s-taste-in-coffee:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540&#34;&gt;Fighting the Urge to &amp;ldquo;Fix&amp;rdquo; My Dad&amp;rsquo;s Taste in Coffee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: my preference in coffee only matters to me. His preference in coffee only matters to him. And the little bit of overlap when he drinks &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.heartroasters.com/&#34;&gt;my kind of coffee&lt;/a&gt;, or when I drink his, just isn&amp;rsquo;t worth the emotional effort of caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I call my dad&amp;rsquo;s preferences into question, it puts strain on both of us. He&amp;rsquo;s defensive because I&amp;rsquo;m attacking something he&amp;rsquo;s doing; I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated because he can&amp;rsquo;t see how unbelievably, unflinchingly &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; I am; both of us start thinking of excuses to leave the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-could-you-possibly-like-that:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540&#34;&gt;How Could You &lt;em&gt;Possibly&lt;/em&gt; Like That?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to lose sight of what&amp;rsquo;s really important in relationships. We all have a tendency to get caught up in a little cloud of &amp;ldquo;my way&amp;rdquo; that makes opposing viewpoints seem scary, stupid, irresponsible, ignorant, or any combination thereof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the majority of the decisions I make have zero impact on the people closest to me. If I&amp;rsquo;m not into &lt;em&gt;Parks &amp;amp; Recreation&lt;/em&gt;, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any difference&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:mustache&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:mustache&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for my friends who love that show; if I don&amp;rsquo;t see the appeal of running a marathon, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean anything at all for the people who embrace the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, the opposite is true: my friends&amp;rsquo; decisions don&amp;rsquo;t actually impact me. Yes, I would love it if all of my friends loved whisky and talking about business development. That some of them don&amp;rsquo;t means nothing within the scope of my experience; I can still enjoy whisky, even if Chelle prefers tequila.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting worked up because things that don&amp;rsquo;t affect me aren&amp;rsquo;t done my way is a shortcut to an extremely frustrating and deeply dissatisfying existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-want-to-know-how-to-solve-all-your-problems-just-be-a-little-less-like-you-and-a-lot-more-like-me-attribution:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You want to know how to solve all your problems? Just be a little less like you, and a lot more like me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:attribution&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:attribution&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to start a lot of monologues with the phrase, &amp;ldquo;You know what you should do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d listen — for a few seconds, at least — to someone&amp;rsquo;s experience, apply my own tastes to it, then harangue them about all the ways they were doing it wrong. In effect, all I was saying was, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you even &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; how much easier your life would be if you were just *more like me?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I always hated in other people: they&amp;rsquo;d just start telling me how to solve problems that didn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was ignoring, though, is that I&amp;rsquo;m just as annoying when I force my taste onto others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My taste doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. At least not to anyone but me. (And neither does yours.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-shut-up-and-drink-the-shitty-coffee:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540&#34;&gt;Just Shut Up and Drink the Shitty Coffee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could get offended by my dad&amp;rsquo;s ambivalence toward a subject I&amp;rsquo;m so passionate about. I could try to convince him that he&amp;rsquo;s wrong, and that his decision to drink awful coffee is somehow linked to his happiness and overall wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I visit my parents and my dad serves me K-cup coffee, I could throw a fit and refuse to drink it. Or I could bring coffee with me and supplant his morning coffee ritual with my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I drink coffee with my dad. Because as long as I&amp;rsquo;m spending time with people I love, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the coffee is terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:marco-arment&#34;&gt;I spun off on a tangent and wrote this article after reading Marco Arment&amp;rsquo;s article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marco.org/2014/03/31/throwing-k-cups-in-glass-houses&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Throwing K-Cups In Glass Houses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:marco-arment&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:mustache&#34;&gt;Except that I don&amp;rsquo;t understand half the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bwGat4i8pJI&#34;&gt;Ron Swanson&lt;/a&gt; jokes they make about my mustache.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:mustache&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:attribution&#34;&gt;I wish I could take credit for this little gem, but it comes from a friend of mine. I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to get attributed to him as something said seriously, so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to include his name here.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:d2da049ed3145702cc6f7c305092b540:attribution&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Drinking for Adults</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-drink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 12:31:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/how-to-drink/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In my younger days, I had mixed feelings about going out for drinks. Lately, though, I love bellying up to the bar. Just not the way &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-hit-the-bars:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s hit the bars.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My younger, single self did bars differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start at the trendy bar: watching hot girls in too-short dresses; Jameson and PBR to build the courage to approach.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:rejection&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:rejection&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, the hope of a sexy jacuzzi party fades. We move to the &amp;ldquo;cool bar&amp;rdquo; and start buying each other shots nobody wants. The smoke is thick. We choose songs on the jukebox ironically; Lionel Richie asks the room if he&amp;rsquo;s the one we&amp;rsquo;re looking for. He&amp;rsquo;s not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At closing time, we&amp;rsquo;re at a bar we swore we&amp;rsquo;d never drink in again. Hammered sorority girls wobble like baby gazelle in their six-inch heels. The guys all circle around like hyenas, ready to pick off the ones who get separated from the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we come to surrounded by fast food wrappers, nursing seventh-level hangovers, promising ourselves we&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; do this again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-not-drinking-alone:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Not Drinking Alone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, I love drinking. But I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call what I do &lt;em&gt;drinking&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to meet friends at bars and have a couple drinks. I do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; like &amp;ldquo;going drinking&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is a running joke between my friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenategreenexperience.com/&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:similar&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:similar&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and his girlfriend Chelle after he once argued, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Look, I&amp;rsquo;m not drinking alone — &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m having a cocktail by myself!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while I may be heading to a bar with the intention of having a cocktail, I&amp;rsquo;m never going with the sole purpose of getting drunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important we establish this early on, or I&amp;rsquo;ll sound like an alcoholic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-not-drinking-it-s-research:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Not Drinking, It&amp;rsquo;s Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not drinking alone; I&amp;rsquo;m having a cocktail by myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate Green&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like learning about the things I&amp;rsquo;m into. &lt;em&gt;Experiences mean more when we fully grasp the complexity of what&amp;rsquo;s happening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cocktails caught my attention because they&amp;rsquo;re a lost art&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:art&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:art&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s been rediscovered in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half the fun for me is learning how the Old Fashioned morphed over time to include club soda and muddled fruit&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:prohibition&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:prohibition&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or that the daiquiri wasn&amp;rsquo;t always a fruity Spring Break booze smoothie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could certainly learn most of this by doing online research, but half the fun in cocktails is learning about them from smart people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-drink:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;How to Drink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I go to a bar, I sit &lt;em&gt;at the bar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to see the drinks being made, and ask questions. I want to get the bartender talking so I can hear about the history of the cocktail I&amp;rsquo;m about to drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I drink now, I go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clydecommon.com/&#34;&gt;Clyde Common&lt;/a&gt; at 5pm on a Monday and ask Junior endless questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t go during happy hour or on Friday night when the bar is packed and the bartenders too busy to talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best experience at a bar was in &lt;a href=&#34;http://rumclubpdx.com/&#34;&gt;Rum Club&lt;/a&gt; after I was stood up for a 5:30 meeting. Bartenders from &lt;a href=&#34;http://expatriatepdx.com/&#34;&gt;Expatriate&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.broderpdx.com/&#34;&gt;Broder Nord&lt;/a&gt; were there; otherwise, the bar was nearly empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat with a few of Portland&amp;rsquo;s biggest cocktail nerds for an hour, learned about Aquavit and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angostura_bitters&#34;&gt;Angostura bitters&lt;/a&gt;, and even did a shotski&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:shotski&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:shotski&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/shotski.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;The Shotski&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Shotski.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://hillarymaybery.com/2010-09-kelly-creighton-wedding/&#34;&gt;Hillary Maybery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t just have a great cocktail or two; I had an awesome time learning something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-all-have-a-drink:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s All Have a Drink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part about learning all this is testing my knowledge by trying to make drinks at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I really learned (from Daniel at &lt;a href=&#34;http://teardroplounge.com/&#34;&gt;Teardrop&lt;/a&gt;) was the proper way to make an Old Fashioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Old Fashioned is a simple drink that dates back to before Prohibition. It follows a simple formula: spirit, sugar, water, and bitters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should find a great bartender near you and learn about this drink. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have access to a great bartender, here&amp;rsquo;s a video of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jeffreymorgenthaler.com/&#34;&gt;Jeffrey Morgenthaler&lt;/a&gt; showing you how it&amp;rsquo;s done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LufrnOktZiA?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a variation I&amp;rsquo;ve been making at home recently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.beamglobal.com/brands/old-overholt&#34;&gt;Old Overholt Rye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; oz honey simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 dashes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feebrothers.com/products/bitters/black_walnut_bitters.php&#34;&gt;Fee Brothers black walnut bitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orange twist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is basically an Old Fashioned, but each varied ingredient makes the drink just a little different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make it with rum instead of whisky. Maple syrup instead of honey simple. Orange bitters instead of walnut bitters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these are all variations on just one style of cocktail. The depth of information here is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-need-a-drink:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32&#34;&gt;I Need a Drink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinking is something I regularly look forward to now. Just not the way I did when I was a teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone are the days of pounding Irish whiskey and ogling cute college girls. I&amp;rsquo;m too old now, anyways; it&amp;rsquo;d be creepy&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:creepier&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:creepier&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking at cocktails the same way I look at code, business, art, and philosophy: it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating world to study, with a rich history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s delicious. Also, making a good cocktail makes me feel like Don Draper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight, I&amp;rsquo;ll be making a drink. But remember: I&amp;rsquo;m not drinking alone; I&amp;rsquo;m having a cocktail by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:rejection&#34;&gt;We never actually approach. Rejection wasn&amp;rsquo;t something our whisky-fueled egos could actually bear.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:rejection&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:similar&#34;&gt;Nate recently wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thenategreenexperience.com/the-best-time-to-go-to-a-bar/&#34;&gt;a post similar to this one&lt;/a&gt;. We had the idea over drinks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://expatriatepdx.com/&#34;&gt;Expatriate&lt;/a&gt;, and apparently he&amp;rsquo;s more motivated.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:similar&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:art&#34;&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that long ago that bartenders enjoyed a similar level of respect as doctors and lawyers. Like any trade, a bartender who takes it seriously is on the level of an artist or chef.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:art&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:prohibition&#34;&gt;During the Prohibition they were introduced to cover the flavor of low-quality alcohol.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:prohibition&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:shotski&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Didn&amp;rsquo;t you just spend 200 words talking about how drinking for the sake of drinking is bad?&amp;rdquo; Hey. Shut up. We were bonding.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:shotski&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:creepier&#34;&gt;What I should &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; say here is, &amp;ldquo;Even creepier than it used to be.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:50dc723431069b5f30c1a77a33a0ff32:creepier&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Not a Phony</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/not-a-phony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 15:24:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/not-a-phony/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Confidence is kind of a dirty word these days. Talking about our strengths and abilities makes us feel like impostors. We&amp;rsquo;re all insecure, and &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sick of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I read an old post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/ImAPhonyAreYou.aspx&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; about feeling like a phony. It reminded me of another post by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scrawnytobrawny.com/my-success-is-a-lie&#34;&gt;Nate Green&lt;/a&gt; on the same subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sentiment behind both of these articles is summed up pretty well in this quote from Nate (for context, he&amp;rsquo;s talking about how he got &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1m1oy3S&#34;&gt;a book deal&lt;/a&gt; at 23 with no formal education):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who the hell did I think I was?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only a matter of time, I thought. Only a matter of time before everyone realizes I have no business doing any of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any moment, I would be exposed as a fraud. On a large scale. And it scared the shit out of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-get-trained-to-feel-like-phonies:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;We Get Trained to Feel Like Phonies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty widespread sentiment among the people I know who are successful. Far too many things are working against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the slow build, which pretty much guarantees that you never really notice your success.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Lots of things have improved for me since I was a broke freelancer working 16-hour days in an apartment that I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure had black mold — but I don&amp;rsquo;t really &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; different than that younger, less experienced version of myself.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the realization that knowing almost everything about Thing A only leads to the further realization that — in order to &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; understand the &amp;ldquo;big picture&amp;rdquo; — a complete knowledge of Things B, C, and D is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, most importantly, we get told that feeling competent and self-assured is socially unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;apologize-for-your-progress:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;Apologize for Your Progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the lines, it became unacceptable to feel proud of our success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying out loud that you&amp;rsquo;re skilled is met with derision. &amp;ldquo;You sound arrogant.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re acting like you&amp;rsquo;re better than everyone else.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s be clear: I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about &lt;em&gt;bragging&lt;/em&gt;, here. There&amp;rsquo;s a world of difference between, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m making a lot of progress at work right now; all that hard work is finally paying off,&amp;rdquo; and, &amp;ldquo;I am &lt;em&gt;killing it&lt;/em&gt; right now — who wants to touch me?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels, though, that the pursuit of political correctness has made it a &lt;em&gt;faux pas&lt;/em&gt; to talk about what you&amp;rsquo;re capable of in most situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I find myself actively try to steer conversations away from what I&amp;rsquo;m doing because I&amp;rsquo;m worried that I&amp;rsquo;ll come off like an asshole if I talk about the things I&amp;rsquo;m working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-am-not-a-phony:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;I Am NOT a Phony&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not the smartest guy in the world. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the most things about anything. There are much smarter people, much more experienced people, much better-looking people, much funnier people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet I still represent myself as an expert on certain topics, and I still think I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just because someone else is better doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m not good.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, on top of that, I have a very unique blend of strengths that make me extremely valuable in certain situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people ask for my services, I don&amp;rsquo;t look around like &lt;em&gt;who, me?&lt;/em&gt; — I take the compliment and get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-okay-to-be-confident:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Okay to Be Confident&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate that when I compliment someone, the expected response is, &amp;ldquo;Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m not any good. I just got lucky.&amp;rdquo; Or, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by a great team.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We deflect the praise because it just feels too &lt;em&gt;icky&lt;/em&gt; to admit we&amp;rsquo;re good at things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear myself say shit like this all the time. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be branded a cocky prick, so I give all the credit to other people, or hide behind some self-deprecating wisecrack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of this is humility, which is a good thing. But it&amp;rsquo;s been taken to the extreme where accepting &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; praise is somehow uncouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: I have been fortunate, and I do have an incredible team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;but I&amp;rsquo;m also really fucking good at what I do.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve put in tens of thousands of hours learning this craft, and every year I put in thousands more continuing my education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a phony. I belong here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-guy-s-a-dick:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;This Guy&amp;rsquo;s a Dick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post sounds like bragging. Like I&amp;rsquo;m trying to tell everyone how great I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say here is that &lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s okay to be proud of your accomplishments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re being honest with yourself, talking about your accomplishments is perfectly acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;m not advocating constant self-adulation. It requires a little tact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-own-your-success-without-being-a-dick:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;How to Own Your Success Without Being a Dick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know my friends, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I still struggle with &amp;ldquo;the line&amp;rdquo; sometimes. But I&amp;rsquo;m working on a system of rules to keep myself from being a dick in conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never bring up your own success.&lt;/strong&gt; You can&amp;rsquo;t avoid sounding self-serving if you insert praise for yourself into a conversation; let someone else ask first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t exaggerate.&lt;/strong&gt; Hyperbole is great for a cute anecdote, but if it turns out you&amp;rsquo;re telling a success story that&amp;rsquo;s been embellished, you&amp;rsquo;ll look like a liar. If anything, play &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt; the details a bit.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop at one.&lt;/strong&gt; If you end up telling a success story, don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself get sucked into telling another one. This is hard, because once you start talking about yourself it&amp;rsquo;s hard to stop. But, seriously. Stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spend more time asking questions and listening than talking.&lt;/strong&gt; This is huge. Unless you&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to speak, spend more time seeing what you can learn from everyone else at the table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a complete list, but it (usually) keeps me from coming off like a douchebag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-not-a-phony-either:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re Not a Phony, Either&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we make a deal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, let&amp;rsquo;s try to own our successes. We&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s recognize that we&amp;rsquo;re not the best or the smartest, but we&amp;rsquo;re pretty damn good, and we&amp;rsquo;re pretty damn smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are NOT impostors. We are NOT frauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are fucking awesome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;This is called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normalcy&#34;&gt;creeping normalcy&lt;/a&gt;, which is the idea that we don&amp;rsquo;t notice changes if they happen in small increments over a long period of time. Usually this is used to describe negative changes, but the same effects seem to be present with the positive as well.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:creeping-normalcy&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;Except for the whole &amp;ldquo;not dying of black mold-related illness&amp;rdquo; thing.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:black-mold&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;I am. I&amp;rsquo;m awesome.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:bragging&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;For example, if you launched a successful company, don&amp;rsquo;t talk about the press or awards you&amp;rsquo;re getting. Instead, talk about what you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt;, and let someone else talk about how much everyone else likes you.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:9bc9b7677143253ec1a130a34d27bcc4:modesty&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All Jazz</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/jazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:37:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/jazz/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have a mantra. It&amp;rsquo;s the metronome that keeps me from going into a tailspin when things go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s my reminder to keep perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all jazz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s simple. Almost silly. And it probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense unless you&amp;rsquo;re me.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-wait-jazz:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;So, Wait. Jazz?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you listen to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jazz_improvisation&#34;&gt;jazz improv&lt;/a&gt;, the musicians are all working within the general framework of the song, but they each take turns making shit up as they play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good jazz musician will play something he&amp;rsquo;s never played before — &lt;em&gt;something he&amp;rsquo;s literally making up on as he goes&lt;/em&gt; — with the kind of skill and ease that makes everyone watching feel as though it&amp;rsquo;s a standard that&amp;rsquo;s been thoroughly rehearsed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ta_UByyi4Z0?rel=0&amp;start=179&amp;end=278&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while it&amp;rsquo;s incredible to watch, this kind of improvisation also has huge implications outside of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans-and-how-they-never-work-out:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Plans, and How They Never Work Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I make a plan, it&amp;rsquo;s virtually guaranteed that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; will go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This used to drive me &lt;strong&gt;crazy.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d develop a vision of the way things ought to go, and when they failed to go &lt;em&gt;exactly right&lt;/em&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d be angry, disappointed, and resentful of the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-mad-bro:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;U Mad Bro?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It bothered me that I let myself get beat by a changed plan, so I started thinking about what it was that bothered me so much when a plan went off-track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, my plans went well. The outcome was really close to what I wanted. So what was the big deal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had set my expectations in such a way that only perfection would be considered a success.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anger, fear, and disappointment happen when our expectations are violated.﻿﻿&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This meant that even when things went my way, I&amp;rsquo;d still be upset because they &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t go exactly the way I&amp;rsquo;d imagined.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-improvisation:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;The Art of Improvisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing this, I had two choices: I could A) accept that I&amp;rsquo;d never be happy and resign myself to a life full of disappointing, mostly-successful plans, or B) figure out a better way to plan that allowed for some wiggle room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the two, the latter seemed more palatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jazz-musicians.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jazz musicians&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Making it up as they go.

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://noblacktie.com.my/2011/04/28/photos-jazz-electronica-17-april-2011/&#34;&gt;No Black Tie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a large amount of trial and error, I finally came up with the jazz analogy, and built a new planning approach on two tenets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip the Details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expect Everything to Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;skip-the-details:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Skip the Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every plan is an effort to obtain a desirable outcome (e.g. &amp;ldquo;improve my client&amp;rsquo;s online marketing,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;have a nice dinner with my friends&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans, however, didn&amp;rsquo;t stop at the outcome; I&amp;rsquo;d work out which sides I would make to pair with the entrée, what games we&amp;rsquo;d play after dinner, and what cocktail I&amp;rsquo;d make to complement the meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inevitably, one or two details would change — no one would want to play a game, or I&amp;rsquo;d forget to grab an ingredient for the cocktails — and I&amp;rsquo;d be upset that it didn&amp;rsquo;t go according to plan, even though the dinner was a success overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By not worrying about the details, I&amp;rsquo;m free to focus on the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something will go wrong. So what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it does, I &lt;strong&gt;adjust within the framework of the plan and make something up.&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ll still get where we need to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forget about managing the details. Just focus on getting the desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;expect-everything-to-change:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Expect Everything to Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another case of framing, which I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/&#34;&gt;touched on before&lt;/a&gt;. If I enter a situation expecting only one outcome, I&amp;rsquo;m doomed to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I expect that things will change and trust myself to adjust accordingly, my expectations are very hard to violate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get sucked into believing that if anything goes wrong, all is lost. But in most cases, the only person who knows anything is amiss is the person who made the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where plans &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; get ruined is when the planner sinks into a funk and everyone else gets uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the musician misses a note, but powers through and just keeps playing, almost no one will notice. But if he stops mid-song to apologize about the mistake, it becomes a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-keep-playing:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a&#34;&gt;Just Keep Playing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing I do ever turns out exactly the way I expect. But it usually goes pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I can do is keep playing, and, with enough practice, maybe everyone will believe that — for me at least — it&amp;rsquo;s all going according to plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;Or one of the people close enough to me that you&amp;rsquo;ve heard the lecture.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:lecture&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so much to be said about this — it really does explain almost every negative human interaction. Think about it next time you get mad: &amp;ldquo;What was I expecting here, and how does the reality differ from my expectations?&amp;rdquo; You&amp;rsquo;re in for a serious moment of zen, &lt;em&gt;mon frere&lt;/em&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3d1dee40223e8f29a940d54d43469c6a:expectations&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See the Tree Coming</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/see-tree-coming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When I fail, I&amp;rsquo;m presented with a choice: do I learn nothing, learn one thing, or learn a life lesson?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that sounds ridiculous. Of &lt;em&gt;course&lt;/em&gt; I should learn a life lesson, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for me, at least, learning something valuable from failure hasn&amp;rsquo;t always been easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-treadmill-treadmill:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The Treadmill Treadmill&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me try to explain with a story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled for years to stay consistent with my trips to the gym. I would get inspired, find a workout program, pick a diet plan, write a detailed daily fitness agenda, and start planning how I&amp;rsquo;d handle the dozens of beautiful women who would undoubtedly be throwing themselves at me in the coming weeks.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, despite my initial optimism, I&amp;rsquo;d find myself feeling discouraged, making excuses, and eventually abandoning the whole idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was failing. And I was being presented with a choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-five-times-i-failed-in-exactly-the-same-way:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The First Five Times I Failed In Exactly the Same Way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I made the choice to learn nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made excuses. I blamed external circumstances. I tried to convince myself that I was just better off ignoring my health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d brush it off, the memory would fade, and eventually I&amp;rsquo;d start the cycle over again &amp;ndash; only to fail in exactly the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was learning nothing, and it showed in my embarrassing lack of progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-next-five-times-i-failed-creatively:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The Next Five Times I Failed Creatively&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I recognized that I was stuck in a loop, I started choosing to learn one thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I learned that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good at working out first thing in the morning. Then I learned I couldn&amp;rsquo;t always make the afternoons work. After that I discovered that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sustain a chicken-and-steamed-broccoli diet like my bodybuilder friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time I failed again, I was learning one thing &amp;ndash; one precise set of circumstances &amp;ndash; that led to my failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-last-time-i-failed-i-learned:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;The Last Time I Failed, I Learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After repeating this cycle maybe a dozen times, I finally took a step back and thought about my situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I was, trying to stay consistent with a plan to make myself healthier &amp;ndash; what better motivation is there? &amp;ndash; and somehow &lt;em&gt;I was failing every time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d learned lots of &amp;ldquo;one thing&amp;rdquo; lessons, but I&amp;rsquo;d never taken the time to examine the root of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was treating the symptoms instead of the disease.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I analyzed, and I ultimately came to the conclusion that the common thread in all my failures was that I gave up after I started to fail: if I missed a workout or had some ice cream, I felt like I&amp;rsquo;d ruined everything and just gave up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an &amp;ldquo;all or nothing&amp;rdquo; type. So when I made a plan, I had to execute it flawlessly or I was wasting my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I learned a life lesson: &lt;strong&gt;I need to set my bar low enough that I can always hit my goal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans started out as, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to do this huge workout and eat exactly these things.&amp;rdquo; The simple lowering of that bar to, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to do something active every day and make sure I eat vegetables with every meal,&amp;rdquo; has made it possible for me to always hit my goal, and as a result I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed consistent for nearly a year now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To clarify, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that I set low expectations that allow me to skate by. I&amp;rsquo;m just adjusting the definition of &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; so that I can sustainably hit my goals. If my goal is &amp;ldquo;just get to the gym, even if you show up, turn around, and go back home,&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve set the bar really low. However, while I&amp;rsquo;ve been to the gym and done a less-than-stellar workout, I&amp;rsquo;ve never showed up to the gym and done &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no picture of perfect human health or anything, but I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; climb stairs without wheezing and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any aches or pains &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s all I really need to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m taking care of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/jason-lengstorf-working-out.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Jason Lengstorf working out&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One of my &amp;ldquo;get moving&amp;rdquo; activities: conditioning class at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elementalfitnesslab.com/&#34;&gt;Elemental Fitness Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-the-source:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;Finding the Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the obvious benefit to my physical well-being, dealing with my failures taught me one of the most useful life skills I&amp;rsquo;ve come across yet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you fail, try to understand &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you failed instead of just learning how to avoid repeating this one mistake.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I run into a tree, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t just glare at the tree and then go about my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t just make a note of where the tree is so I can avoid it next time I pass this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I should try to understand why I didn&amp;rsquo;t see the tree coming in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-practice:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944&#34;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond my fitness goals, this approach to failure has helped me in every area of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s helped me understand that when I lose clients, it&amp;rsquo;s not because that client is beyond help or because I worded something incorrectly; it&amp;rsquo;s because I violated their expectations, which put them on edge and started a downward spiral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s helped me understand that when I end up fighting with my girlfriend, it&amp;rsquo;s not because she&amp;rsquo;s irrational or because I&amp;rsquo;m too detached; it&amp;rsquo;s because I made her feel attacked, or unimportant, or a similarly unsavory emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This applies to dozens of other examples that I could have brushed past as one-off incidents (or worse, forgotten entirely). Each failure gives me a little window into how I&amp;rsquo;m perceived by others, or how I&amp;rsquo;m wired, and it allows me to &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; my personality &amp;ndash; I can see certain trees coming and avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll hit hundreds more trees &amp;ndash; thousands even &amp;ndash; as I continue to grow and learn and fail, but if I&amp;rsquo;m doing this right, they won&amp;rsquo;t be the same trees all that often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/27139502@N00/460096222/&#34;&gt;Andy Cox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;I had this all worked out: there would be a reality show where these women would showcase their intelligence, strength, and wit through a Billy Madison-esque decathlon featuring such events as &amp;ldquo;Carry Me Up the Stairs as if I&amp;rsquo;ve Been Injured&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Write Me a Haiku About Bears&amp;rdquo;. There would be laughter, tears, strategy, and a Final Challenge that probably involved the Nerf guns from &lt;em&gt;American Gladiators&lt;/em&gt;. The series would be met with lackluster reviews, but a strong cult following.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:new-life&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;The big difference here is &lt;em&gt;framing&lt;/em&gt;. Before, when I was failing, doing a quick workout because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling 100% would constitute a failure; now, I look at &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; workout being better than no workout. Get it?
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:651429ecea821716f8554d03d68d6944:starting&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Alone with My Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/time-alone-with-my-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 22:23:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/time-alone-with-my-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Or, the measures I’m taking to avoid sinking into the trap of dying frustrated and ignorant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest things about writing is just sitting down to write. I&amp;rsquo;ve been telling myself that I&amp;rsquo;d get around to blogging again for&amp;hellip;three years, now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like writing. I think thoughts that I find helpful. I believe that some of those thoughts &amp;ndash; in theory, at least &amp;ndash; are valuable when applied by humans other than myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the silence, then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a lack of desire, certainly. At least once a day it occurs to me that something I&amp;rsquo;ve said or done or learned or screwed up could be worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not fear. I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly long to spill my guts publicly, but I&amp;rsquo;m far from shy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My literary cease-fire, then, boils down to either inertia or screwy priorities. Probably, if I&amp;rsquo;m being completely honest, a fair amount of both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That, or just my own unwillingness to spend an extended amount of time alone with my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a trend right now in the circles I run in: more and more people around me are meditating or keeping gratitude journals or something similarly, inwardly peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not me, though. I can&amp;rsquo;t do it; meditation feels forced and awkward, and a gratitude journal is just homework from a lifestyle blogger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even though my knee-jerk reaction is to write it all off as new agey, touchy-feeley, hippie dippy bullshit, I see the value in it. We need to be alone with our thoughts; to spend some time sifting through all the noise in our minds; to think a little bit about the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; of what we&amp;rsquo;re feeling instead of just the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s next&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s some pretty important, grownup-level business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That leaves me with a bit of a conundrum: I feel like an asshole counting my breaths or keeping a diary of warm fuzzies, but I see a valid and pressing need to stay mindful of where I am, what I&amp;rsquo;m feeling, and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m here to learn. If I&amp;rsquo;m not learning from the things I feel, I&amp;rsquo;m just barreling toward death as a ball of unexamined loneliness, momentary joy, and mystery boners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes sense to me is to just take half an hour each day and write. No set subject matter, no agenda, no business model &amp;ndash; just a (completely public) space to spend a little alone time with the chaos in my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And really, this may just prove to be my way of both meditating &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; keeping a gratitude journal, tweaked just enough that I can convince myself it&amp;rsquo;s neither.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>