<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Firstworldproblems on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/firstworldproblems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Firstworldproblems on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 15:28:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/firstworldproblems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bright Side</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/bright-side</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 15:28:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/bright-side</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Every time you talk to another person, you&amp;rsquo;re affecting the way they feel. Try not to make them feel like shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re meeting two people for dinner. One sits down with a smile, making eye contact, sitting up straight, looking pretty happy; the other is despondent, flopped in his chair like a sack of laundry, and studying the palms of his hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now ask about their days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paulie-poopypants:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Paulie Poopypants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The schmoopy one says, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough day. I was late getting to work, and as soon as I showed up my boss dropped this giant project in my lap. And then — as if my day wasn&amp;rsquo;t already bad enough — it was raining after work so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t go to the park like I wanted to.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bobbi-brightside:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Bobbi Brightside&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smiley one says, &amp;ldquo;Today was pretty good! I took an extra-long shower, which was great even though I had to rush to work afterward. I just got a new project at work that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a great challenge — I think if I do well, I might get a promotion. And since it was rainy after work I got a chance to write a letter to a friend I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to send.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;they-re-describing-exactly-the-same-day:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re Describing Exactly the Same Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever someone tells a story, they spin it. Their feelings and motives color the narrative, and we feel — to a certain extent, at least — what they feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that. Because it&amp;rsquo;s huge: &lt;strong&gt;you have the ability to control the moods of the people around you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-fun-to-be-around:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Are You Fun to Be Around?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone wants to feel happy. It&amp;rsquo;s why we seek out things like music and love and beauty; it&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href=&#34;http://illegal-art.net/girltalk/&#34;&gt;Girl Talk&lt;/a&gt; causes spontaneous dance parties; it&amp;rsquo;s why I prefer to hear &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/&#34;&gt;stories with happy endings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have the ability to make me feel happy when I ask about your day. What were the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jlengstorf/stop-glossing-over-the-good-stuff-b89e25f7c714&#34;&gt;good things that happened to you&lt;/a&gt;? What&amp;rsquo;s the bright side? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the best thing about today?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you focus on the negative, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to feel great. And I&amp;rsquo;m going to associate that feeling with you. And if it happens frequently, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start avoiding you, because you&amp;rsquo;re a downer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-to-paulie-and-bobbi:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Back to Paulie and Bobbi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s assume you have the option to hang out with either Paulie Poopypants or Bobbi Brightside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a lot more fun hanging out with Bobbi; positivity is contagious, and optimism cures a lot of ills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of all the people you look forward to spending time with. Are any of those people constantly bringing you down with stories about how hard, unfair, or hopeless things are?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-your-silver-lining:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e&#34;&gt;Find Your Silver Lining&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything has a bright side.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s up to you to let the bright side give you hope instead of letting the challenge bring you down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/eeyore.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Eeyore&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself become an emotional black hole.&lt;/p&gt;

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you see your glass as half-empty or half-full, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s still your glass.&lt;/strong&gt; And you have to deal with that regardless of your attitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; control is how you frame your circumstances in conversation. Bringing a little sunshine to someone else&amp;rsquo;s day means they&amp;rsquo;ll look forward to your company. And you might even find that projecting positivity outward makes you more inwardly positive as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ask yourself: Are you a source of positivity and happiness for other people? Or are you the Eeyore that shits on everyone else&amp;rsquo;s good time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;Okay, okay, not everything. Some things are irredeemable. But if you have time to read a blog like mine, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to bet that you and I are talking better than 95% First World Problems, here. #realtalk
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:91b9b7bceeb3bc6558778cae2e5e2a1e:realtalk&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing the Weekend</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/losing-the-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 17:04:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/losing-the-weekend/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When I started Copter Labs, it started a new phase of &amp;ldquo;working from anywhere&amp;rdquo; in my life. It really changed my perception of time, though, and I no longer have a concept of &amp;ldquo;the weekend&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me qualify this statement by saying this is &lt;em&gt;not a complaint&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s just something I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed as the years have gone on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tgim:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;TGIM?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I don&amp;rsquo;t know what day of the week it is. Sometimes I feel like this is a good thing, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been liberated from the shackles of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other times I feel like Norm Macdonald in &lt;em&gt;Billy Madison&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/norm-macdonald.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;What day is it? October?&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What day is it? October?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;small&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112508/&#34;&gt;Billy Madison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I get cues about the day of the week from conversations with other people; they say things like, &amp;ldquo;TGIF,&amp;rdquo; and, &amp;ldquo;Must be Monday.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;losing-the-weekend:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;Losing the Weekend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really have a weekend to speak of. Today is Saturday, and I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of migrating a dozen sites to &lt;a href=&#34;http://cptr.me/HP5GYs&#34;&gt;WPEngine&lt;/a&gt; and doing logo concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be fixing a site that got hacked and making improvements to a couple other client sites&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes this bothers me, and I get grumpy and think, &amp;ldquo;Man, I wish I could just take two days a week off.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, actually, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like having weekends back &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekends-imply-weekdays:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Weekends&amp;rdquo; Imply &amp;ldquo;Weekdays&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of having two days a week completely to myself sometimes sneaks into my brain and tricks me into thinking I&amp;rsquo;m missing out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the whole idea that those two days are mine and mine alone &lt;strong&gt;implies that the other five days are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, I have to remind myself occasionally, is the &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; reason that I chose the career path I&amp;rsquo;m currently on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-hard-work-but-it-s-my-work:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Hard Work, but It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;My Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I average a ten-hour workday. I work seven days a week. My clients call and email me at all hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll get asked how that kind of schedule is better than working 40 hours and having the rest of my time to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair question. And, honestly, sometimes I wonder the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where I always land on this issue is that, yes, what I do is &lt;em&gt;really hard work&lt;/em&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s what I love to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day I solve hard problems: I come up with a design that will support a marketing strategy that I need to define, or build a piece of software that solves a complex problem in a way that&amp;rsquo;s simple for my clients to use, or I coordinate the team at Copter Labs to tackle an impossibly large project on an impossibly short timeline to get it launched on time.[footnote]Or, more realistically, get it launched &lt;em&gt;less late&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;more late&lt;/em&gt;.[/footnote]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t think of anything I&amp;rsquo;d rather do with my time. And my track record shows it: when I was working full time at a Kinko&amp;rsquo;s, I would get off work and go home to work on a code project or design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This was my hobby before it was ever a source of income.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I didn&amp;rsquo;t love code and marketing and design as much as I do, my life would probably be a lot different than it is now, and the idea of a 70+ hour workweek would probably make me gag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do, it isn&amp;rsquo;t, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;redistributed-weekends:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;Redistributed Weekends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s also not fair to say that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a weekend at all, though. I do have time off. It&amp;rsquo;s just spread out throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can take a long lunch, or schedule an appointment at 10am. I can shut down at 3:30pm if I know I can stay up a bit later or put in a couple extra hours tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nothing-s-lost-after-all:04a823fa0333ac9a30065f1038eb0f58&#34;&gt;Nothing&amp;rsquo;s Lost After All&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of all this, I guess, is that I should probably just shut up whenever I start to think I&amp;rsquo;m missing out. I need to keep perspective, and realize that my life is exactly the way I want it to be right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things like weekends were never important to me, or I would have made that a part of the structure of Copter Labs. And if, in the future, a weekend becomes something I actually want, I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll figure out how to have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have any &amp;ldquo;grass is greener&amp;rdquo; thoughts bringing you down? Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it: jump to the Facebook discussion and let&amp;rsquo;s air all our First World Problems publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>