<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stories on Jason Lengstorf</title>
    <link>http://lengstorf.com/tag/stories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stories on Jason Lengstorf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 08:00:06 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lengstorf.com/tag/stories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Tourist Trap</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/navigating-the-tourist-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 08:00:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/navigating-the-tourist-trap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In my worst nightmare it goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m standing somewhere significant. Maybe historical, or cultural, or just &lt;em&gt;totally fucking majestic.&lt;/em&gt; The sort of place your well-traveled friends tell you no but seriously you &lt;em&gt;have to see it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of moment camera companies have trademarked. Before now the thing I&amp;rsquo;m looking at was only an &lt;em&gt;understanding&lt;/em&gt; of a place in my head, but now it&amp;rsquo;s becoming an experience; a memory: the image from Wikipedia grows a Z axis and I can touch it and there&amp;rsquo;s a smell and now I can give you directions to here complete with landmarks and everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I inhale deeply through my nose. &lt;em&gt;This is exactly the kind of shit that makes travel worth—&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reverie is shattered by a tiny old woman in a sleeveless floral blouse and a white visor who elbows past me to take a photo of the &amp;ldquo;Sortie / Exit, Toilettes / Washroom&amp;rdquo; sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A British tour group forces me forward, each of them labeled with a neon Post-It™ note signifying which bus brought them here. A middle-aged woman is digging in her purse in the middle of the path, preventing anyone from going around her, which has infuriated her husband up ahead to the point he&amp;rsquo;s now standing in the middle of the path with his hands cupped around his mouth screaming &lt;em&gt;get out of the damn path, Emily, no one can get around you&lt;/em&gt; as a queue builds on either side of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Japanese kid is switching out absurdly expensive optics on his DSLR and taking macro shots of a fencepost, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me except that I know his photos of nothing are better than any photo I will take in my lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind me, a meaty shoulder or belly or breast presses into the back of my arm, and in front of me a child who is far too young to have any hope of remembering this family outing is &lt;em&gt;melting the fuck down&lt;/em&gt; because he&amp;rsquo;s the only one of us sane enough to realize that being here, on this path, in this place, is the worst kind of hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gorgeous outdoor space starts to feel small, and the press of tourists is taking all of my oxygen. I suppress the urge to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5Iv9q9QI1g&#34;&gt;Barry Sanders&lt;/a&gt; my way to the nearest exit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/tourists-in-monets-garden.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Tourists at Monet&amp;#39;s Garden in Giverny, France.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Monet&#39;s water garden — home to the famous water lilies.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-and-self-loathing-in-claude-monet-s-garden:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;Fear and Self-Loathing in Claude Monet&amp;rsquo;s Garden&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday I lived my nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early afternoon, I climb out the back of a van and into an enormous parking lot&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:village&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:village&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to join a queue of art- and/or flower-enthused travelers who&amp;rsquo;ve made the trip to get a glimpse of Monet&amp;rsquo;s botanical muses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enter through a small gate at the southwestern corner of the property. Inside the gate, there&amp;rsquo;s a ticket booth and high hedges all around — no peeking, I guess. Marisa&amp;rsquo;s mom bought some package online that lets us skip the line and duck through the hedge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As weather for standing in a garden goes, this afternoon in Giverny is just about perfect. It&amp;rsquo;s about 20°C under a bright blue sky with what Bob Ross would certainly describe as &amp;ldquo;happy little clouds&amp;rdquo; hovering over the Seine in the western sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/blue-sky-over-the-seine-river.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Blue skies over Giverny, France.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The view from a hill just outside Giverny, France.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The garden is huge. Maybe a little bigger than a football field&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:pitch&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:pitch&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and crosshatched with paths that lead through intensely colorful landscaping that overflows with flowers I can&amp;rsquo;t identify&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:flowers&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:flowers&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in colors I didn&amp;rsquo;t know flowers could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden is a special place. And not just because it was the inspiration for a large number of his paintings — this is a place where it just feels good to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-the-locusts-descend:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;And the Locusts Descend&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, for all the beauty that the garden has to offer, there will be no peace or reflection here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By my estimation, roughly 30% of the global population is stuffed inside the walls of Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden, all jockeying for selfie-space along the garden paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dozens of old women&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:oldwomen&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:oldwomen&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from every corner of the globe totter along the path, asking each other how their cameras work and (loudly) discussing the scene:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aren&amp;rsquo;t these gorgeous?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The flowers!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The flowers?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What about the flowers?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aren&amp;rsquo;t they gorgeous?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s gorgeous?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teenage girls who&amp;rsquo;ve slipped away from their parents make doe-eyes and duck-faces for strangers on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young couple detains me and holds up foot traffic so I can take their picture in front of the main path. Four times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sayeth-the-locust:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;Sayeth the Locust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I fucking hate tourists,&lt;/em&gt; I think to myself as I crouch down in front of a flower that sort of looks like a popcorn ball to take a close-up with a shallow depth of field. Those tend to get more likes, I&amp;rsquo;ve found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/p/4AUts8zK9K/&#34; style=&#34; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;Claude Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;
A photo posted by Jason Lengstorf (@jlengstorf) on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2015-06-16T21:26:06+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 16, 2015 at 11:26pm CEST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smile apologetically at the people waiting behind me as I usher Marisa and Jil into position for a mother-daughter photo. Marisa keeps talking, so I have to try three or four times before she&amp;rsquo;s not pulling a goofy face in the photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a baby bird I think is a black swan starts jumping from lily pad to lily pad, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/video.php?v=839353302801239&#34;&gt;take a video&lt;/a&gt; and point it out to Jil and we discuss what type of bird it is. The ladies next to us start trying to take a video — &lt;em&gt;what button do I push again?&lt;/em&gt; — and point it out to each other and start calling it a baby duck, which I decide is wrong and hold against them as ignorant Americans.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:bird&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:bird&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marisa and I decide to skip Monet&amp;rsquo;s house&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:house&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:house&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and duck outside the walls to buy ice cream. We find a spot in the shade to sit down and I silently judge all the other fatties on tour buses eating ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-trouble-with-tourist-traps:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;The Trouble with Tourist Traps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cringe at the thought of waiting three hours to ride &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.londoneye.com/&#34;&gt;the London Eye&lt;/a&gt;. At &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sacre-coeur-montmartre.com/english/&#34;&gt;Sacre-Cœur&lt;/a&gt;, I came as close as I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been in adult life to starting a physical altercation with some overly-touchy peddler.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:touching&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:touching&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, I recoil from anything that would be called an &amp;ldquo;attraction&amp;rdquo; when I visit a new city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, these are the places that — once, long ago — had significance, but have now been roped off and sanitized and crammed full of souvenir shops to the point that, really, they&amp;rsquo;re not anything like what they were when they became significant.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:edinburgh&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:edinburgh&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything with any value to a city&amp;rsquo;s tourism board quickly becomes the Attraction &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ship_of_Theseus&#34;&gt;of Theseus&lt;/a&gt;: if an historically significant site, incrementally, has all its parts replaced by informational plaques and concession stands, is it still the same historically significant site?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/see-the-world-without-being-a-tourist.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;How can you see the world without being a tourist?&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-yet:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;And Yet&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the issues with tourist traps, there&amp;rsquo;s no denying that some of this stuff really does have historical significance. And really — significance aside — some of it is just &lt;em&gt;really fucking cool&lt;/em&gt; to see up close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Eiffel Tower is probably one of the top 5 most recognizable structures in the world. Almost everyone can sketch a rough approximation of what it looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, goddammit, standing on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Passerelle_Debilly&#34;&gt;Passerelle Debilly&lt;/a&gt; facing SSE at 23:00 is still breathtaking, no matter how many times I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the photos online before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for all the venom and vitriol I spit at tourist attractions, I&amp;rsquo;m still susceptible to the sense of wonder and awe that made these places attractions in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-a-better-mouse-trap:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;Building a Better Mouse Trap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, back in Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden, I started solving problems in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These paths should be made one-way to avoid this clusterfuck.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why are half the paths closed?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They should let us pay more for a ticket where only 25 people get to go in at a time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My claustrophobia and impatience grew in intensity, and my solutions became more extreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You should have to pass a basic camera competence exam to get into this place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everyone should be allowed three photos before moving further down the path.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end I was more or less a Marvel supervillain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Humanity has failed to make tourism work. To fix tourism, we must kill all tourists.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:exceptions&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:exceptions&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This is the only way.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/claude-monet-real-life-waterlilies.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Waterlilies in Claude Monet&amp;amp;#039;s garden, Giverny, France.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  The waterlilies Claude Monet painted.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coming-to-terms-with-tourism:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;Coming to Terms with Tourism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m here, standing on a bridge over the world&amp;rsquo;s most famous waterlilies, fuming over the crowds and the chaos and the commercialization of history. I feel cheated because I can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; enjoy this experience with all these other jerks pushing their way past me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hypocrisy of it all sneaks up on me. I feel a little sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m one of them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came here to look at this place. To take iPhone photos and tell my Facebook friends I&amp;rsquo;m here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m probably less qualified than many of these people: they might be able to name a few Monet paintings — maybe they know more about this painter and his garden than his first name. Really I just came because Jil wanted to go and I wanted to make an effort and keep an open mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But really, at the core, I&amp;rsquo;m only one Tommy Bahama button-down removed from the guy next to me. We&amp;rsquo;re both foreigners. We both speak no French and have bad American habits and probably offend&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:offense&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:offense&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; nearly half the locals we meet. We wanted to see the best things the world has to offer, and this particular piece of the globe has been deemed noteworthy — so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-re-not-so-different-you-and-i:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re Not So Different, You and I&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My self-consciousness about being an outsider makes me quick to put some distance between myself and tourists. I don&amp;rsquo;t want French people to look at me and immediately peg me as an American&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:american&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:american&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and assume I&amp;rsquo;m just some tourist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; just some tourist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, sure, maybe the people in this garden with me will spend their vacations eating burgers because &lt;em&gt;coq au vin&lt;/em&gt; sounds too exotic, and maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll never leave Champs-Élysées unless it&amp;rsquo;s in the back of a tour van. Maybe they won&amp;rsquo;t even bother trying to speak French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of that makes me better than they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I sit next to an American couple and pretend not to speak English so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to talk to them, that&amp;rsquo;s not making me &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; worldly; it&amp;rsquo;s further isolating me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/make-money-like-claude-monet.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;I make Monet like Claude Money.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Get the Monet. Dolla dolla bills, y&#39;all.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-search-of-authenticity:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;In Search of Authenticity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to &amp;ldquo;live like a local&amp;rdquo; — it&amp;rsquo;s been this &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-travel/&#34;&gt;location independence experiment&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;raison d&amp;rsquo;être&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:french&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:french&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from the start — but my eagerness to have an &amp;ldquo;authentic&amp;rdquo; experience built a wall between me and other travelers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to be seen as The Right Kind of Traveler™: when I meet someone from another country, I want to become the example they offer up as an exception to the rule during a discussion of how awful American tourists are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I let my desire to live as locally as someone can for a month become a default avoidance of anything that could be called &amp;ldquo;tourist activities&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on a huge percentage of the world&amp;rsquo;s beauty and history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because it&amp;rsquo;s popular doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s not worth doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;authentic-tourism:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b&#34;&gt;Authentic Tourism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside Monet&amp;rsquo;s garden, Jil asks me, &amp;ldquo;Did you have a good time?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ride home is pulling into the parking lot, near the bench where we were all told to meet at 14:30. We hurry to polish off our ice cream cones and buy a bottled water for the drive. The older couple we rode up with looks exhausted — &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;can&amp;rsquo;t wait to get to Provence so we can finally slow down and relax,&amp;rdquo; the man is saying to his wife, who is flipping through the photos she&amp;rsquo;s taken today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/marisa-and-jil-in-monets-garden.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;Marisa and Jil in Claude Monet&amp;amp;#039;s Garden, Giverny, France.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    
  Marisa and Jil in Monet&#39;s Garden.

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jil lives for this stuff: tomorrow she&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting outside a comfortable hotel in the shadow of the Eiffel Tower at 05:30 for a bus tour to Normandie in the morning, back in the late afternoon to haul ass to Musée d&amp;rsquo;Orsay before closing, off to the Eiffel Tower to see it sparkle at 23:00 on the dot, and in bed right away so she can get up at 04:00 to do it all again the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get exhausted just &lt;em&gt;reading&lt;/em&gt; her itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I can see on her face that this — standing on the bridge Claude Monet painted in 1899 — this is a &lt;em&gt;moment&lt;/em&gt; for her. Walking through Monet&amp;rsquo;s house, she could feel Monet in those rooms; she was sharing space with one of her favorite artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meaning — the emotion — that this trip held for her was beyond anything I could ever hope to feel about a house or a garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t hold that against her. I can&amp;rsquo;t hold that against any one of these people here to see something significant from human history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This was great, Jil.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She smiles and thanks me for putting up with the crowds. Then she asks if I want to go to Normandy tomorrow at 05:30. (I don&amp;rsquo;t.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ll go to Versailles&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:versailles&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:versailles&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; the day after. And then we&amp;rsquo;ll go to a local bar I like where we&amp;rsquo;re the only people who don&amp;rsquo;t speak French. Because I don&amp;rsquo;t have to choose: I can be a tourist sometimes without ruining my chances at experiencing local hangouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, quick: take my picture in front of this moment. I want all my friends to know I had a like &lt;em&gt;life-changing epiphany&lt;/em&gt; in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That shit gets retweeted like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:village&#34;&gt;Under which I assume used to stand a very charming village.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:village&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:pitch&#34;&gt;And just a tad smaller than a football pitch.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:pitch&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:flowers&#34;&gt;Though — let&amp;rsquo;s be honest — I can only identify maybe a half-dozen flowers without help from Google.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:flowers&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:oldwomen&#34;&gt;The relationship between septua- and octogenarian human females and botany has a distinctly moth:flame character to it. This was something I had always considered a kind of good-natured stereotype. At least until I entered the garden to find a field of blue and silver hair, about 1.5m tall, swaying slightly in the breeze.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:oldwomen&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:bird&#34;&gt;It was actually a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=baby+rail+bird&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=ZyeEVaDlO4HaUdKos4gM&amp;amp;ved=0CAcQ_AUoAQ&amp;amp;biw=1440&amp;amp;bih=801&amp;amp;dpr=2&#34;&gt;baby rail&lt;/a&gt; (I think). Which I didn&amp;rsquo;t know was a type of bird.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:bird&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:house&#34;&gt;Presumably, it was filled with doors, tables, chairs, and a fucking gift shop.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:house&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:touching&#34;&gt;Can we all agree that you just &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t touch strangers?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reactiongifs.us/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/no_touching_arrested_development.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NO TOUCHING!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:touching&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:edinburgh&#34;&gt;The castle in the center of Edinburgh, Scotland is a great (?) example of this. All the cannons are covered in high-gloss paint. The dungeons are gift shops now. There&amp;rsquo;s a concession stand. It feels about as authentic as an Olive Garden.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:edinburgh&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:exceptions&#34;&gt;Except me, of course.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:exceptions&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:offense&#34;&gt;Mostly because we&amp;rsquo;re ignorant and — despite our best efforts — just clueless about the proper approach to certain situations. Sometimes because we&amp;rsquo;re painfully, obviously American and bulling through the world&amp;rsquo;s china shop. And every once in a while because I can just be a dick when I&amp;rsquo;m hungry.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:offense&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:american&#34;&gt;They do. Every time. Usually before I even open my mouth. Serious question: do I look &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; American?
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:american&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:french&#34;&gt;Something I hadn&amp;rsquo;t realized when I first arrived in Paris was the astonishing number of French words and phrases that have been &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_French_expressions_in_English&#34;&gt;ported directly to English&lt;/a&gt;. I knew &lt;em&gt;raison d&amp;rsquo;être&lt;/em&gt; was French; I &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; know that (just in the As and Bs of the American lexicon) we&amp;rsquo;d borrowed &amp;ldquo;aperitif&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;armoire&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;belle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;boulevard&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;bourgeois&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;bouquet&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;brunette&amp;rdquo;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:french&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:versailles&#34;&gt;The grounds at Versailles were incredible, but the palace itself was awful because &lt;em&gt;holy shit&lt;/em&gt; the crowds. If there was anything worth seeing there, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it out over the sea of phone screens and miscellaneous objects waved by tour guides to keep their groups from disappearing into the mêlée. 0/10 would not return.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:929df55f9a9feba66dd2b2aa3d52f22b:versailles&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stories We Tell Ourselves</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/stories</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 10:03:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/stories</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t regret anything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done that I saw through to the end. I only regret things I left unfinished, or never started at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-journey-is-the-story:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;The Journey Is the Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I tell you that a guy named Billy Ray Valentine was a successful investor and made a killing in the commodities market, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t bat an eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever, right? Lots of people are good at their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if I tell you that Mr. Valentine came from the gutter and &lt;em&gt;got his job on a bet&lt;/em&gt;, things get a little more interesting.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/images/stories1.jpg&#34;
       alt=&#34;stories&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;
    

    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-good-story-isn-t-about-the-ending:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;A Good Story Isn&amp;rsquo;t About the Ending&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all love a good story. &lt;em&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s too easy to mistake the ending for the whole story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The journey is what makes a story good.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s the details. The twists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, stories don&amp;rsquo;t have to end well. Heroes can lose. Main characters can die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll allow any ending, as long as the story is good.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-lives-are-a-collection-of-short-stories:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;Our Lives Are a Collection of Short Stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we don&amp;rsquo;t sit around at dinner telling tales, &lt;strong&gt;our lives exist as a series of stories.&lt;/strong&gt; We tell these stories to ourselves, to our friends, to potential employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/bright-side/&#34;&gt;spin our stories&lt;/a&gt; and use them to create little vignettes of who we are and what we value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strangers use them to make us real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our stories become the only part of us that anyone else really touches.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-good-story-has-a-follow-through:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;Every Good Story Has a Follow-Through&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, even though the guts of a story lie in the journey, every story still needs to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it needs to &lt;em&gt;really end.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the plot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/WTy0QP&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cool Runnings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was the story of that time Derice Bannock was accidentally tripped by an opponent in the 1988 Summer Olympics qualifier before giving up on his Olympic dreams, the story would have felt incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Derice took his failure and pushed onward — and ultimately &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=31M_MdSVxV8&#34;&gt;failed again, sort of&lt;/a&gt; — and it makes for a great story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-up-to-us-to-make-our-stories-good:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Up to Us to Make Our Stories Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a choice with every story we begin: &amp;ldquo;Am I going to see this through to the end, or am I going to give up and leave the story unfinished?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When things get difficult, we can always bail and walk away. And sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s how a story needs to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for every story we leave unfinished, we&amp;rsquo;re building a narrative around ourselves. Are we leaving more stories unfinished than we&amp;rsquo;re seeing through to the end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-your-stories-say-about-you:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407&#34;&gt;What Do Your Stories Say About You?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you play back your stories in your head, do you feel good about them?&lt;/strong&gt; Or do they feel like a collection of half-finished anecdotes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that — regardless of how your stories read so far — you&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of a few stories right now. And you&amp;rsquo;ll start new stories in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to make them good ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the idea of traveling permanently while making a living probably seems like a dream — but you don&amp;rsquo;t think you can pull it off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I felt that way right up until I actually boarded a flight to leave the United States. And now I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t start living this life sooner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;I want to help you avoid my mistake: you can start living the life of your dreams right now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;free step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to show you how.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lengstorf.com/remote-work-course/&#34;&gt;Click here to get the free guide.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;If you want to know Billy Ray&amp;rsquo;s full story, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/X7sjiL&#34;&gt;watch the documentary&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:8146d69623c598bd1f00796c6e9ef407:trading-places&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Montana</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 17:46:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/miss-montana</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Years back, before I moved to Portland, I used to haunt a bar called Al&amp;rsquo;s and Vic&amp;rsquo;s in Missoula, Montana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of those dives where it was too loud to hear yourself think and the floor was &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; sticky, but they sold a bucket of PBR for four dollars, and a Montana Happy Meal&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a night where I&amp;rsquo;d been called in as wingman for Scott, we met with his date and — for the span of a beer — I did my best not to make him sound like a degenerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His date, whose name I don&amp;rsquo;t remember but whose face looked like a Bernadette, told us her friends were arriving and would we mind standing at the bar with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette introduced us to her friends, Mandy and Kate. Mandy, it turns out, was a friend of Scott&amp;rsquo;s, and the two of them pulled Bernadette into conversation, leaving Kate and I to fend for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate was beautiful. Like, &lt;em&gt;holy shit&lt;/em&gt; good-looking — the kind of attractive that usually requires about a grand&amp;rsquo;s worth of Photoshop cleanup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, on the other hand, was wearing a cowboy shirt with pearl snaps, sporting an extra twenty pounds or so, and unshaven in the not-sexy way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, despite my homeless desperado ensemble, we hit it off immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was funny, sharp-witted. I was scrambling to keep up, but she was laughing. The hoarse mating calls of a hundred college kids were muffled under the sound of her voice, like bourbon over fine-grit sandpaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The faces around us blurred and faded; it was just me and Kate and my beer and her whisky diet and this moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain was leaking that special cocktail of chemicals that only happens the first time you make a connection with someone. In that moment I understood how people can meet and fall in love and end up making long-term promises to each other in front of an Elvis impersonator — all in the span of one intense night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spark between us had magnetized the air; my heart was trying to pull out of my chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernadette reappeared over Kate&amp;rsquo;s shoulder, and the room snapped back into focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandy was with her, and Scott returned a moment later with a fresh bucket of beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott gave me a &lt;em&gt;how&amp;rsquo;d it go for you&lt;/em&gt; look. I tried not to look upset about the interruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls did their secret eye contact telepathy thing, and Bernadette started preparing her exit. Mandy and Kate took her cue and started gathering their purses and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate caught my eye as she swung her coat around her shoulders, and my heart went all squishy and weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I formed the words in my brain — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number&lt;/em&gt; — opened my mouth to speak — &lt;em&gt;ask for her number, you idiot!&lt;/em&gt; — and I said, &amp;ldquo;It was really nice meeting you. Have a great night.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She might have hesitated. I was too disgusted with myself to notice. The next thing I knew I was watching her hair bounce in the red bar-glow as she walked away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of running after her, telling her I couldn&amp;rsquo;t let her get away without knowing I could see her again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s romantic? Probably creepy. Better not.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of asking Scott for Bernadette&amp;rsquo;s number so I could call her and ask for Kate&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s even worse. Stop it. All of your ideas are bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did nothing. I watched the door close behind her. My mouth was probably hanging open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Scotty — never one to pass up a kidney punch — said, &amp;ldquo;Blew that one, huh?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the beer he offered and did a poor job of acting nonchalant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You know who she is, right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shook my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a special kind of schadenfreude that only men experience. It occurs when we watch a friend — hitting it off with a woman who is clearly out of his league — suddenly and spectacularly self-destruct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a teeball benchwarmer. Kate was one good season away from the big show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scotty was so darkly gleeful he should have been stroking a Persian cat as he said, &amp;ldquo;She was Miss Montana last year.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goddammit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot with Miss Montana, and I let her walk out of the bar. After fifteen minutes of great conversation and good chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replayed the moments before she left in my head. I met her eyes. &lt;em&gt;She was waiting for you to ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a shot. I did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-wasted-second-chance:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;The (Wasted) Second Chance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks later, I was out with Scotty again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was late, and we had slunk into the bar everyone despised. The sign on the door said &amp;ldquo;Bodega&amp;rdquo;, but it may has well have been called You&amp;rsquo;re Hammered Again &amp;amp; None of the Girls Will Talk to You, Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out front, I bummed a cigarette off a stranger and wobbled gently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jason?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wheeled and found myself facing Kate. I immediately stamped out my cigarette. I could feel the air starting to magnetize again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate smiled. And then she hugged me. Her hair smelled like vanilla-scented heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smelled like an ashtray full of whiskey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So how are you?&amp;rdquo; I managed to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Great! Oh, by the way, these are my brothers, Jeff and Mark,&amp;rdquo; she said, motioning to the two frighteningly large men who flanked her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded. They nodded back, then pretended not to pay attention while this drunken asshole in front of The Saddest Bar in Missoula tried to flirt with their sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow we just fell back into it. She teased me about my smoking, I poked fun at the shoes she was carrying, and we both laughed. My heart did the squishy-weird thing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it was time to make the move. Her brothers weren&amp;rsquo;t going to stand there all night, and I needed to head back inside before Scott ordered me any more drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried scraping every last bit of courage off the walls of my rib cage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just ask. Ask for her number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to think of a line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a line, dickhead: &amp;ldquo;Can I get your number and call you sometime?&amp;rdquo; Just. Ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I caught eyes with the larger of her two brothers. And then I wondered if I&amp;rsquo;d misread the whole situation and she was just being nice to me. And then I froze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, hey, it was great seeing you again. I should probably get back inside.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Idiot. Idiot. Idiot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flushed. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even make eye contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As suddenly as she&amp;rsquo;d appeared, Kate — Miss Montana — the gorgeous, funny girl I love-at-first-sighted (twice) was gone into the night. For good this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lost-in-the-woulds:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf&#34;&gt;Lost in the Woulds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would have been a great couple. She would have had a secret family recipe for waffles and a mean Scrabble game. Maybe her disturbingly attractive genes would compensate for my hairiness and we&amp;rsquo;d make the world&amp;rsquo;s hottest babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She would have shot me down. We&amp;rsquo;d have only had another thirty seconds of good conversation left in us. She would have had a boyfriend. I would have hated her guts after two weeks of hanging out. Or, more likely, she&amp;rsquo;d have hated mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand wonderful memories, starting with the one where I asked if I could call and she said yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have made a thousand mistakes and alienated myself from the Montana Beautiful Women&amp;rsquo;s Club&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any of those outcomes would have been fine. Even bad experiences are still &lt;em&gt;experiences&lt;/em&gt;, you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;em&gt;wondering!&lt;/em&gt; The wondering is murder. There&amp;rsquo;s no lesson to learn in &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s just the nagging of an unanswered question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, I&amp;rsquo;m not the guy who took a long shot with a beauty queen and succeeded against the odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also not the guy who took a shot and missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just a guy who had a shot and stood there looking foolish while the clock ran out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;A shot of Jameson with a PBR back.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:happymeal&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;Totally a thing.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:a9230ef37d6ab8576e9d5a8c6b83f1bf:mtbwc&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fear</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/fear</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 15:17:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/fear</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to back down from a challenge, or to hedge our bets to leave ourselves an out. Sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s wise. Most times we&amp;rsquo;re just scared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a terrifying thing, The Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear tells us that our ideas are too risky, or uninteresting, or just plain &lt;em&gt;bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear tells us we&amp;rsquo;ll be rejected if we try to say hello. That we&amp;rsquo;ll be ridiculed and laughed at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we stand on the starting line of a new adventure — moving to a new city, leaving an unfulfilling job — The Fear tells us we&amp;rsquo;ll never make it; could never make it; should just give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying is scary. Trying is difficult. Most of all, trying makes us vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;schrödinger-s-kiss:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738&#34;&gt;Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s Kiss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was twelve, my parents used to play cards with Cindy&amp;rsquo;s parents. She was the first girl I&amp;rsquo;d spent time alone with, and I was &lt;em&gt;in love&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I wanted to do was kiss Cindy. And I was pretty sure Cindy wanted to kiss me, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But The Fear was certain a kiss spelled disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;ll say no. She&amp;rsquo;ll tell her parents. She&amp;rsquo;ll be so disgusted she&amp;rsquo;ll throw up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I didn&amp;rsquo;t try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wondering was torture. Would she kiss me? What would kissing be like? Did she like me, or did she &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; like me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visualized every step of the kiss: Cindy and I would be playing &lt;em&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/em&gt;, and she&amp;rsquo;d be on a roll&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;d watch intently as she squared off with Dr. Robotnik.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the split second after defeating the boss, while her heart was soaring with the joy of having saved the world from the clutches of evil, I&amp;rsquo;d wrap my arms around her and we&amp;rsquo;d kiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;d be surprised, and thrilled, and we&amp;rsquo;d kiss like on those soap operas my mom watched where our heads rotate side to side for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could almost feel our lips touching, I wanted it so bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But still The Fear said it would never work, and that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t even bother trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me weeks to defeat The Fear. During a game of Truth or Dare, I finally worked up the courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I dare you to kiss me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heart was in my throat. I was tensed up, ready to sprint for the door if she said no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But she didn&amp;rsquo;t say no.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Cindy led me downstairs, where we snuck past our dads out into the garage and sat on the bumper of her mom&amp;rsquo;s minivan.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Even as she held my hand, I heard The Fear telling me it was all about to go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it didn&amp;rsquo;t go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy leaned in, and I had my very first kiss: a tight-lipped peck followed by a panicked sprint back up to her room before our parents could notice we&amp;rsquo;d left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been kissed. I was a man now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fear-as-a-friend:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738&#34;&gt;The Fear as a Friend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I overcame The Fear and got my first kiss, I had an advantage: I knew The Fear could be beaten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear told me I&amp;rsquo;d blow it on my first oral presentation in junior high. I pushed through and got a B+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear was certain I&amp;rsquo;d never win in the student elections, but I ran anyways. I was elected Junior Class Vice President.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fear screamed that my band would make me the butt of a lot of jokes. But I got on stage, and discovered my first real passion in music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It never went away, The Fear, but every time I push past it, it gets a little easier the next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started to look forward to The Fear now; when it rears its head, I know I&amp;rsquo;m pushing myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m doing something that scares me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m growing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still don&amp;rsquo;t like The Fear. It makes me feel awful, paralyzed, a little nauseous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every new adventure, I&amp;rsquo;ll be that twelve-year-old boy: terrified, and desperately trying to scrape together enough courage to go in for my first kiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I welcome it now. The Fear is the starting line of a new challenge. A sign that I&amp;rsquo;m becoming more than I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth-or-dare:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738&#34;&gt;Truth or Dare?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s play a game of Truth or Dare.&lt;/strong&gt; Think of something you&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to try, but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now tell the truth: &lt;strong&gt;is there anything &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; stopping you?&lt;/strong&gt; Or is it just The Fear making excuses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, of course, the dare: I dare you — I &lt;em&gt;double dare&lt;/em&gt; you — to &lt;strong&gt;do that thing you&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do *today&lt;/strong&gt;*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s too big to do in a day, then take one step toward that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; to move past The Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it can be shared publicly, post your thing on the discussion for this post, and tell me what the one step you&amp;rsquo;re taking today will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Push through The Fear. The kiss is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brennaphotos/3499551628/&#34;&gt;Brenna Lyn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;Get it? Because&amp;hellip; because it&amp;rsquo;s Sonic. And he rolls. &lt;em&gt;Amirite?&lt;/em&gt; Ah, never mind.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:dadpun&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;Because — of course — sneaking clumsily through the house was &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; less conspicuous than staying in her room like we always did.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:sneaking&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;I was impeached about a month later. Long story. Ask me over drinks.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dc3ae6538dde502be0d652ef2521d738:impeached&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enough with the Sad Stories</title>
      <link>http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 13:34:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lengstorf.com/enough-sad-stories/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I watched Robert Redford die &amp;ndash; slowly and tortuously &amp;ndash; for two hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was watching his new movie, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2017038/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;All Is Lost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is &lt;strong&gt;killing it&lt;/strong&gt; on Rotten Tomatoes (currently rocking a 94% rating). I left the theater feeling heavy, sad, despondent. It was rough. I didn&amp;rsquo;t much care for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-container aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/75824994?color=e26700&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;422&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say &lt;em&gt;All Is Lost&lt;/em&gt; is a bad movie. It&amp;rsquo;s well-made, and Robert Redford is a solid actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Jesus! what a draining way to spend an afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-nineteen-year-old-self-is-so-ashamed-right-now:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;My Nineteen-Year-Old Self Is So Ashamed Right Now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;rsquo;m saying all this as Present Tense Jason, who is very different from Jason of Yore; in fact, the latter would spit right in my face for what I&amp;rsquo;m about to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten (somewhat) older and seen (a bit) more of the world, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost interest in the movies that used to top my list. Gone are the days of repeated viewings of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1g5XH57&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Clockwork Orange&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; no longer do I want to sit down and really &lt;strong&gt;experience&lt;/strong&gt; a film like &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzt.to/1crskxC&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Requiem for a Dream&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still think they&amp;rsquo;re good movies &amp;ndash; great ones, even &amp;ndash; but god&lt;em&gt;damn&lt;/em&gt; are they depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid it was important to me that my movie choices felt authentic, and didn&amp;rsquo;t cloud the story with fluffy Hollywood nonsense. I wanted heroes who could die, and stories that twisted and turned and gave you hope before killing the main character &amp;ndash; y&amp;rsquo;know, because life is like that sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;art-imitating-life:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;Art Imitating Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year I read about some movie that raises the bar for authenticity. Some &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1hlY1Rb&#34;&gt;movie about Osama Bin Laden&lt;/a&gt; put all the actors through real military training, or some French filmmaker had his actors &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1dgPXu0&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; have sex during the love scenes&lt;/a&gt;. Even the superhero movies are coming up with as-plausible-as-you-can-make-a-superhero-backstory origin stories &amp;ndash; apparently so we can all avoid the burden of suspending our disbelief for 105 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all pushing toward a true-to-life experience. And a good portion of it is terribly hard to watch because it&amp;rsquo;s so depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-em-laugh:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;Make &amp;lsquo;Em Laugh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take away my cinephile card if you want, but these days, I just want to be entertained, not bashed in the skull repeatedly with an emotional sledgehammer. I&amp;rsquo;m sick of feeling bad when the credits start rolling, or after finishing a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to hear a great story about characters that make me want to be better, filled with heroes who win by being smarter and more determined than the villains; about couples who believe so deeply in true love that even insurmountable obstacles can be surmounted; about wizened old mentors who teach just the right lesson at just the right moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I want things to work out in the end.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know life is hard, and that not everything ends well. There are little reminders of life&amp;rsquo;s hardships and inconveniences all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, then, would I want additional reminders while I&amp;rsquo;m trying to relax and take my mind &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; the world&amp;rsquo;s ills?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-be-awesome:f59d606ff7376956e4b10b1180650b12&#34;&gt;Just Be Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I want nothing but romantic comedies. I just want more stories involving people being awesome, and that leave me feeling better than when I started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t show me &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1crujSA&#34;&gt;Paul Giamatti slowly self-destructing&lt;/a&gt; in a moody downward spiral. Instead, show me Cary Elwes &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1a6pCBD&#34;&gt;outsmarting Sicilians and besting giants&lt;/a&gt; to rescue his true love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your favorite feel-good movies and books?&lt;/strong&gt; Let me know in the Facebook discussion!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>